I've never seen a single paper that
我从未见过任何一篇论文……
shows you can't lose weight you can't
这表明你无法减肥，你不能
get stronger all of it can be done but
变得更强壮，这一切都能做到，但是
you paying attention to things that just
你注意到那些事情
do not matter Dr Andy gpin one of the
安迪·格平博士（Dr Andy gpin）并不重要。
most highly respected exercise
最受推崇的运动
physiologists in the field today he is
他是当今该领域的生理学家之一。
the director of the center for sports
体育中心主任
performance and he's a coach to many
他表现出色，而且还是许多人的教练。
professional athletes I'm going to talk
我要谈的是职业运动员。
about how do I lose weight and how do I
关于如何减肥以及如何
improve my performance mood sleep but if
改善我的表现、情绪和睡眠，但是如果
you want to live as well as possible for
你想尽可能好好地生活下去
a long time it comes down to a couple of
很长一段时间以来，最终都归结为几个问题。
things number one you can't not pay
第一件事，你不能不付钱。
attention to grip strike and in fact we
注意握拳，事实上我们
can actually PR dicts Alzheimer's and
实际上，公关可以决定阿尔茨海默病和
Dementia risk via grip strength testing
通过握力测试评估痴呆风险
and then leg strength and do2 Max those
然后是腿部力量和 Do2 Max
things will out predict how long you're
事情会比你预想的更糟，你会持续多久？
going to live more than almost any
将会比几乎任何人活得更久
metric and I'm saying leg strength
我用的是公制单位，我说的是腿部力量。
because one of the most significant
因为其中最重要的一点是
issues that we face during aging it's
我们在衰老过程中面临的问题是……
our Falls if you look at the risk of
如果我们考虑风险，就会发现我们的瀑布
dying after a hip break and those are
髋部骨折后死亡，这些都是
over 60 years old there is a 70% chance
60岁以上的人有70%的概率
of death of the next 15 years wow what
接下来15年死亡人数，哇，什么？
is V2 Max your maximum ability to bring
V2 Max 是你所能达到的最大能力吗？
in and utilize oxygen there was actually
实际上，那里存在并利用氧气。
a study with 750,000 people and found
一项涉及75万人的研究发现
smoking and diabetes at a 40% increase
吸烟和糖尿病病例增加40%。
risk of dying and V toax is 300% oh
死亡风险和 V 类药物摄入量是 300%，哦，天哪
what do I need to be doing comes down to
我需要做什么归根结底是……
a couple of things if you can do this
如果你能做到这一点，有几件事可以做。
stuff consistently you're going to be
你会一直做些事情
just fine first of all but why' you care
首先，一切都很好，但你为什么要在意呢？
most people will go through challenges
大多数人都会经历挑战
at some point in their life this is
在他们人生的某个阶段，这是
going to give you the ability
将会赋予你这种能力
to not be in those situations
避免陷入那种境地
anymore sorry I need to collect myself a
抱歉，我需要冷静一下。
little bit here just just a lot of part
这里只有一点点，还有很多部分。
of my story that the world doesn't know
世人不知我的故事
um it's absolutely crazy to me that so
嗯，这对我来说简直太疯狂了。
many of you have decided to watch our
你们中的许多人决定观看我们的节目。
show um and so many of you have decided
给他们看看，你们很多人都决定这么做了。
to subscribe to our show we now have
现在您可以通过以下方式订阅我们的节目：
five million subscribers on YouTube
YouTube 拥有五百万订阅者
which is a number that I just can't
这是一个我根本无法回答的数字
comprehend and it's a dream that I
理解，这是我的梦想。
absolutely never could have had we
我们绝对不可能拥有
started the dire of a CO just over 3
一氧化碳中毒事件的严重性始于3年多一点。
years ago now and in my wildest
几年前，在我最疯狂的时候
expectations we might have had a 100,000
我们原本预期会有 10 万人
subscribers by now so you can imagine
现在订阅用户已经很多了，你可以想象一下。
how shocked I am that so many of you
令我震惊的是，你们当中竟然有这么多人……
have chosen to tune into these
已选择收听这些节目
conversations every week um and spend
每周的对话，嗯，还有花费
some time with us so thank you and I
感谢您和我们共度的时光。
made a deal with you I made a deal that
我和你达成了协议，我达成了一项协议。
if you subscribe to this show that we
如果您订阅了本节目，我们
would continue to raise the bar and in
将继续提高标准，并且在
2024 we're going to raise the bar like
2024年，我们将提高标准，就像……
never before I've been working for the
我以前从未为……工作过
last nine months on a surprise for all
过去九个月对所有人来说都是一个惊喜
of you that have subscribed to the show
你们当中已经订阅了该节目的观众
and I'm very excited to deliver that for
我非常兴奋能够实现这一点。
you the production's going to change
制作过程将会改变
we're going to go even further with our
我们将更进一步，继续我们的
guests and we're going to tell even more
来宾们，我们还会透露更多。
Global stories so as always if you
全球新闻，一如既往，如果您
appreciate what we're doing here the
珍惜我们在这里所做的一切
simple free favor I'll ask from you is
我能请你帮个简单的忙是
to hit the Subscribe button let's get on
点击订阅按钮，我们开始吧！
with the
和
[Music]
[音乐]
episode Dr Andy Galpin if someone's just
安迪·加尔平医生那一集，如果有人只是
clicked on this podcast right now and if
我刚刚点击了这个播客，如果
you were to speak freely about the
你应该畅所欲言地谈论……
things that you care about the most what
你最在乎的事情是什么？
exactly is it that they would walk walk
他们究竟是会走路还是走路呢？
away from this
远离这里
conversation with in terms of value that
与人交谈时，要注重价值。
would positively impact their
这将对他们产生积极影响
life I've done hundreds of podcasts and
在我的人生中，我制作了数百期播客节目，
I have never had that
我从来没有过那种经历。
question and I've certainly never had it
这个问题我当然从来没有过。
coming right at the gates so I love
正好到大门那里，所以我很喜欢
it the way I would capture it would be I
我捕捉它的方式是……
want to enhance Human
想要增强人类
Performance and when I say that I want
表现，以及我所说的我想要
to make sure that you're not hearing
为了确保你没有听到
sport performance that means sport to
运动表现，意味着运动
you fine that's great but I really break
你没事那就太好了，但我真的崩溃了
that down into three categories people
这可以归纳为三类人
want to look a certain way whatever that
无论如何，都想看起来像某种样子。
means to you I don't care people want to
对你来说，这意味着我不在乎别人想怎样
feel a certain way and people want to
人们会感到某种情绪，并且想要……
perform a certain way you set the ground
按照你设定的某种方式进行操作
rules you want to look this way when you
当你希望规则以这种方式呈现时
say perform and you think perform that
你说要表演，你认为表演就是
means X to you when you say you want to
当你说你想……的时候，它对你来说意味着X。
feel that means why to you great let's
感觉这意味着什么？对你来说很棒，让我们……
establish all that and then my goal is
把所有这些都确定下来之后，我的目标是……
simply to help you achieve all of those
仅仅是为了帮助你实现所有这些目标
goals so you want to be bigger and
你的目标是变得更强大，而且
stronger and have more energy throughout
更强壮，精力更充沛
the day great you want to think more
今天很棒，你想多思考一下。
clearly you want to be a better leader
显然你想成为一名更优秀的领导者。
athlete spouse parent that's great you
运动员配偶/父母，太棒了！
want to be out of pain you want to have
你想摆脱痛苦，你想拥有
a certain functionality in a certain all
某种功能在所有
those things are on the table so when I
这些事情都摆在桌面上，所以当我
say perform I mean cognitively
我说的是认知能力方面的表现。
physically in whatever area of
在任何领域
Department that matters for you all
对您所有人来说都很重要的部门
those are on the table we we analyze all
这些都是摆在桌面上的，我们会全部分析。
that we break it down and we say okay
我们把它分解开来，然后说好的
this is the targets we're going after
这就是我们追击的目标。
and then my mission is just to help
然后我的任务就是帮助别人。
anyone I'm working with but really
任何与我共事的人，但真的
broadly the world get better at that I
总的来说，世界在这方面做得越来越好了。
don't think I've ever seen any paper
我好像从来没见过任何纸张。
that has shown any genetic combination
已显示任何基因组合
that shows you can't grow muscle I've
这说明你长不出肌肉。
never seen a single paper that shows you
从未见过任何一篇论文能证明这一点
can't lose weight never seen a single
减不了肥，从来没见过一个
indication of any physiological marker
任何生理指标的迹象
that says you can't get stronger
那意味着你不可能变得更强。
whatever you're interested in nothing
无论你对什么感兴趣
should stop you from making some
应该阻止你做一些事情
progress in some area of your physical
身体某些方面取得进步
health and if you do that you got a
健康，如果你那样做，你就会得到……
chance why do you care why' you care
你为什么在乎？你为什么在乎？
about human performance and exercise and
关于人体机能和运动
cognitive performance where did that
认知能力在哪里？
come from what was the like first Domino
源自最早的多米诺骨牌。
that fell in your
掉进你的
life sorry I need to collect myself a
生活啊，抱歉，我需要冷静一下。
little bit here
这里一点点
um
嗯
I've been on a lot of podcasts and
我参加过很多播客节目，
there's just I've been in the media a
我只是最近一直在媒体上露面而已。
lot and there's just a lot of part of my
很多，而且这其中有很多是我的一部分。
story that the world doesn't know
世人不知的故事
um the shortest answer to that question
嗯，这个问题的最简短回答是……
was I grew up with sports being
我从小就接触体育运动。
everywhere right and and I played Sports
到处都对，而且我参加过体育运动
growing up everyone I knew played Sports
我从小认识的每个人都热爱运动。
growing up and I personally was an
成长过程中，我个人就是
adequate athlete which
合格的运动员
means I was good but not exceptional but
这意味着我表现不错，但并不出类拔萃。
I wasn't terrible
我表现还不错。
either I was told uh as a teenager and
要么是我十几岁的时候被告知的，要么就是……
by the people around me and my parents
来自我身边的人和我的父母
and my
以及我的
grandparents that you you know you
你认识的祖父母
deserve nothing not in the negative way
不值得以任何负面方式获得
but in terms of like no one owes you
但就“没有人欠你”这种说法而言
anything in this world if you want to
世界上任何东西，只要你想得到。
get better at sports you better train
想在运动方面取得进步，你最好多加训练。
you better work harder and in in the
你最好更加努力，争取成功。
most positive loving like way possible
以最积极、最充满爱的方式尽可能地
Right my I was very fortunate my parents
没错，我非常幸运，我的父母
were incredibly positive and supportive
他们非常积极热情，给予了极大的支持。
and there's no negativity there and so
那里没有任何负面情绪，所以
it was just as simple as a matter of
事情就这么简单……
fact of hey you say you want to win then
事实是，你说你想赢，然后
why aren't you working hard than
你为什么不努力工作呢？
everybody else just the way that my
其他人都和我一样。
parents raised us and the way that my
父母养育我们的方式，以及我
grandparents and my siblings um there
祖父母和我的兄弟姐妹们，嗯……
was just a sense of
只是一种感觉
like
喜欢
my sorry I'm trying to it's okay give it
对不起，我正在努力，没关系，给你。
more genuine answer but um there's only
更真诚的回答，但是，嗯，只有
so most people will go through
所以大多数人都会经历
challenges at some point in their life
他们一生中都会面临挑战
and
和
uh I'm no
呃，我不是
different
不同的
I was just very fortunate to where my
我很幸运，我的
parents were in a position that my dad
父母当时的处境是这样的：我爸爸
was a construction worker my
我曾是一名建筑工人
grandparents were construction workers
祖父母是建筑工人。
we grew up in the country my mom did
我妈妈在乡下长大。
whatever she could to you know keep our
她尽一切可能让你知道，我们
house and things like
房子和类似的东西
that and they raised us in a very
他们把我们抚养成人，而且他们非常……
positive way they always said you're
他们总是用积极的方式说你是
going to go to college I don't care what
我要去上大学，我不在乎什么
you do what you spend your career on
你职业生涯所投入的一切，最终都会体现在你的工作中。
whatever but you're just not doing what
随便吧，反正你没做什么。
we did just because they wanted us to
我们这么做只是因为他们想让我们这么做。
have an easier and better life
拥有更轻松、更美好的生活
um so so for me Human Performance was
嗯，对我来说，《人类绩效》这部剧是这样的。
that hey here's your chance like here's
嘿，机会来了，就像……
your chance to get out and do something
这是你走出去做点什么的机会
um this is going to give you the ability
嗯，这将赋予你这种能力
to not be in those situations
避免陷入那种境地
anymore and I get to do that by being
不再如此，而我可以通过以下方式做到这一点：
around Sports all the time which is is
一直围绕着体育运动，那就是
pretty great so why I
非常棒，所以我为什么……
care
关心
what is the emotion
情绪是什么？
Andy sorry I've never been on this road
安迪，抱歉，我从来没走过这条路。
in real public before
在真正的公共场合
um there's a lot of things that people
嗯，有很多事情是人们
will go through in life that are out of
人生中会经历许多意想不到的事情。
their
他们的
control to me this represents stuff that
对我而言，控制代表着某些东西
will be within your
将在你之内
control and so I give you the chance to
控制权，所以我给你这个机会
make changes that you can control your
做出你能控制的改变
strength and your health at least you
至少你的体力和健康会让你感到强壮。
got
得到
that you tell me where the parameters
请告诉我参数在哪里
are here because I want to make sure
我来这里是因为我想确保
that you're comfortable but from that I
你感到舒适，但从那以后我
understand that in your childhood there
要明白，在你的童年时期
were things that you you couldn't
是你做不到的事
control and in in what I heard there was
控制，而且据我所知，还有
that this was something that you could
这是你可以做的事情
give you that
给你那个
control I don't want to overplay my own
控制，我不想过度发挥自己的优势
situation
情况
I had a tremendous childhood had a
我拥有一个非常棒的童年。
tremendous
巨大的
life again especially never being around
再次经历生活，尤其是从未在身边。
alcohol or violence and things like that
酒精或暴力等等
like I had a lot of great breaks and
感觉我有很多很棒的机会，
still had loving parents support
仍然有慈爱的父母支持
positivity there were a number of years
积极情绪持续了好几年
you know as a child that were really
你知道，小时候我们真的
difficult and just being like man my
很难，简直就像……我的天哪
parents never did anything like again
父母再也没有做过类似的事情了。
never violence never alcohol never
绝不暴力，绝不饮酒，绝不
negative never hate just okay fine that
负面情绪从不讨厌，好吧，没关系。
was really horrible really bad break
真是太糟糕了，真是个糟糕的假期
what are we going to do we're going to
我们接下来要做什么？我们要……
work harder financially difficult yeah
是的，工作更辛苦，经济更困难。
for sure
一定
um in other
嗯，在其他方面
ways but the the thing I appreciate is
方式有很多，但我最欣赏的是……
like many of the things the biggest one
就像很多事情一样，最大的一件事
is just like it doesn't matter we're
就好像我们是谁都无关紧要一样
moving forward like not in terms of like
向前迈进，不像是像那样
ignoring it we're letting it go but like
我们选择忽略它，放任不管，但就像
okay great bad deal here got real bad
好吧，这笔交易糟透了，情况变得非常糟糕。
luck but we're we're we're pressing on
运气不错，但我们仍在努力。
we are going to overcome this
我们将克服这一切
stuff when we start talking about
当我们开始谈论某些事情时
exercise and health and performance and
运动、健康和表现
all these
所有这些
things what have what's been your
你的那些事，你拥有过什么，你经历过什么
academic and life experience that has
学术和生活经验
built the foundation of everything that
奠定了一切的基础
you know can you give me a little bit of
你知道，你能给我一点……
a
一个
walkr yeah so I have an undergraduate
沃克，是的，我有一个本科学位
degree in what's called exercise science
运动科学学位
can you iology it's same thing I got a
你能学学吗？这跟我得到的东西是一样的。
master's in human movement sciences and
人体运动科学硕士学位
then my PhD is in what's called human
我的博士学位研究方向是人类学。
bioenergetics and what happened
生物能量学及其发展
professionally once you graduated from
毕业后，你的职业生涯将从……开始
there so as soon as I finished my PhD I
所以，我一完成博士学位，就立刻……
started my lab at Cal State Fullerton um
我在加州州立大学富勒顿分校建立了我的实验室
so I work and I'm now one of the
所以我工作，现在我是其中一员。
directors of What's called the center
所谓“中心”的负责人
for sport performance there so within
为了运动表现，所以在此范围内
that we've got multiple
我们有多个
Laboratories biome mechanics strength
实验室生物群落力学强度
conditioning um motor control motor
调节电机 控制电机
learning Etc and they all study the the
学习等等，他们都在学习
mission of that Center actually is to
该中心的使命实际上是
study and disseminate research that
研究并传播以下研究成果：
enhances Human Performance what is the
提升人类表现是什么？
range of people that you work with that
你与之共事的人员范围
come to you and say Dr Andy Galpin I
来找你，说我是安迪·加尔平博士。
need help with this oh oh my gosh so we
需要帮忙啊，我的天哪，所以我们
have traditionally spent most of my
我传统上把大部分时间都花在了……
career working with our pro athletes um
与我们的职业运动员一起工作的职业生涯
I've been fortunate to work with Olympic
我很幸运能与奥林匹克队合作。
gold and silver medalists world
世界金牌和银牌获得者
champions the highest contract in Major
赢得Major赛事最高级别的合同
League Baseball and golf All Pro that
职业棒球和高尔夫全明星
every position in the NFL etc etc but by
NFL 的每个职位等等，但是通过
far in terms of numbers wise we've
就数量而言，我们已经……
worked with more executive clients and
与更多高管客户合作
than professional athletes so our
比职业运动员还多，所以我们
coaching program rapid health and
教练计划快速健康
performance is like what if we took what
表现就像如果我们采取什么
we've been doing for a decade in only
我们十年来一直在这样做，而且只用了十年时间。
these Elite athletes and put a system
这些精英运动员并建立了一套体系
together for non-athletes and that's
为非运动员群体而设，就是这样。
exactly what we've done with that
我们正是这么做的。
company and it's gone exceptionally well
公司合作进展非常顺利。
people that tend to come in for that uh
那些经常来这里的人……
kind of fall into a couple of buckets a
大致可以归入以下几个类别：
lot of times it's kind of like your your
很多时候，这有点像你的你的
adult athletes if you will so I want to
成年运动员，如果你愿意这么称呼的话，所以我想
run a marathon I want to do something
我想跑马拉松，我想做点什么。
like that but the overwhelming majority
就像那样，但绝大多数
of people are just going hey I want to
很多人就说，嘿，我想……
just feel better I want to look better
只想感觉好些，也想看起来更好些。
and I want to perform better and I want
我想表现得更好，我想要
to minimize my likelihood of missing
为了尽量减少我错过的可能性
what I mean by that is you can try a
我的意思是，你可以尝试一下
diet you can try a thing and like see
你可以尝试一些饮食方法，看看效果如何。
what happens for six weeks and that's
接下来的六周会发生什么，那就是……
very effective but some people have more
非常有效，但有些人效果更佳。
money than they have time and some some
他们有的钱比他们的时间多，还有一些
people have been through the ringer I've
人们都经历过磨难，我
been trying for a year two years five
尝试了一年、两年、五年
years I haven't slept in a decade what's
我已经十年没睡过一个安稳觉了，这是怎么回事？
it going to take I don't want to miss
这需要时间，我不想错过
anything and so we do extremely
任何事，所以我们都做得非常出色。
comprehensive testing uh it takes a very
全面的测试需要非常
long time to finish all of our testing
完成所有测试花了很长时间。
we can get a volumetric measurement of
我们可以得到体积测量值
each muscle on your body so I can look
你身体的每一块肌肉，这样我才能看到。
at the size of each ind1 we can look at
我们可以观察每个 ind1 的大小
your V2 Max we can look at cognitive
我们可以看看你的 V2 Max 的认知能力。
performance we're running very in-depth
我们正在进行非常深入的性能测试。
sleep assessments we're looking at
我们正在研究的睡眠评估
environmental factors in your house like
家中环境因素，例如
we're running everything possible that
我们正在尽一切可能实现这一点。
we go through with our highle athletes
我们和我们的优秀运动员一起经历
and by doing that we're able to see and
通过这样做，我们就能够看到和
find what we call Performance anchors so
找到我们所说的绩效锚点
these are things that are putting the
这些都是造成这种情况的原因。
most constrain on your
对你而言最大的限制
physiology and so the analogy I'll say
生理学，所以我要打个比方：
is imagine you want to drive a car
想象一下你想开车
faster people's initial inclination is
人们最初的倾向是速度较快的
to hit the gas pedal that's great my
踩下油门，那太好了，我的
inclination is to look at your left foot
下意识地会看向你的左脚
which is I want to make sure your foot
也就是说，我想确保你的脚
isn't on a break
不在休息
somewhere so before I you the gas pedal
在某个地方，所以在我踩下油门之前
let's make sure our left foot's off the
让我们确保左脚离开……
brick and in this case that is a
砖，在这种情况下，它是一块
constraint what are you doing to hold
限制 你正在做什么来保持
back your own biology and so we can able
支持你自身的生物学，这样我们才能能够
to find those things and then because of
为了找到那些东西，然后因为
that we can give them extremely specific
我们可以给他们非常具体的信息
Solutions and our program tends to be so
解决方案和我们的项目往往如此
effective because we can go through all
有效，因为我们可以完成所有步骤
this
这
analysis that allows us to
分析使我们能够
then give them very simple and hypers
然后给他们非常简单和超级的
specific plans when you talk about that
谈到具体计划时，你指的是什么？
left foot on the break analogy which I
左脚踩刹车的比喻，我
thought was a really nice sort of
觉得这是一种非常好的感觉
crystallizing
结晶
analogy what are the most common um
类比中最常见的是什么？
things that we have our left foot on the
我们左脚踩在……的事情
break with in terms of are there
就是否存在而言，打破常规
fundamental things that you see most
你最常看到的基本事物
most often that are kind of getting in
大多数情况下，那些进入的人都属于这种情况。
the way of us reaching our Optimal
我们达到最佳状态的方式
Performance yeah you want to think about
表现方面，你需要考虑一下。
these in a couple of buckets we call
这些装在几个桶里，我们称之为
these stressors yeah so the way that
是的，这些压力源，所以就是这样。
your body works at all times in fact I
事实上，你的身体无时无刻不在运转。
think this is one of the traits that
我认为这是其中一个特点
separates human physiology from any
将人类生理学与其他任何生理学区分开来
other
其他
animal we have a better ability to adapt
动物界对我们人类来说，适应能力更强
and respond to our environment that's
并对我们的环境做出反应
the single thing your body is trying to
你的身体正在努力做的一件事
do at all times right put pushing and
始终做正确的事，推和
pulling it's always reading and sensing
它一直在读取和感知
trying to get to a certain place
试图到达某个地方
stressor comes in and it adjusts okay
压力源出现后，系统能够调整过来。
great that's a good thing we categorize
太好了，这很好，我们可以进行分类。
those stressors into two major areas
这些压力源可归纳为两大领域。
what we call Visible stressors and then
我们称之为可见压力源，然后
hidden stressors visible stressors are
隐性压力源和显性压力源
things you're doing that you are visible
你做的那些引人注目的事情
and aware of so you went and worked out
所以你意识到了这一点，然后就去努力了。
you felt that great that's a stressor
你感觉那么好，那反而会成为一种压力源。
you drank alcohol you felt that you
你喝了酒，你感觉你
didn't sleep tonight you feel these
今晚没睡，你感觉到了吗？
things right you can see them you smoke
事情进展顺利，你可以看到它们，你抽烟
cigarettes like you have all these
像你这样的香烟，全都这样。
things you your diet your nutrition so
你的饮食和营养状况
all those are analyzed from a
所有这些都是从A的角度进行分析的。
perspective of there one of the most
从某种角度来看，这是最……
common ones well the obvious ones youve
常见的那些，嗯，就是那些显而易见的。
probably covered countless times right
可能已经被无数次提及了，对吧？
don't drink alcohol in excess and don't
不要过量饮酒，也不要
drink um try to have quality water and
喝水，尽量喝优质水。
sunlight and honestly like
阳光，老实说，我喜欢
the the you know
你知道的
15-year-old Health like could probably
15岁的健康可能
tell you like what are the five pillars
告诉我，这五大支柱是什么？
in of health and like that would you
身体健康，你会喜欢那样吗？
would line those things up pretty well
这样安排得相当不错。
now where things get more interesting in
现在事情变得更有趣了。
our stuff is the hidden stressors so
我们的物品才是隐藏的压力源。
these are things that are putting equal
这些都是等同的事情。
or greater stress on your system but you
或者说，你的系统承受了更大的压力，但你
can't see or feel them so this could be
既看不见也摸不着，所以这可能是
things like a vitamin or mineral
比如维生素或矿物质
insufficiency you no one wakes up and
不足之处，无人醒来，
goes ah man like my vitamin D is low
感觉就像我的维生素D不足一样
today you know you don't see that you
今天你知道你看不到你
don't feel that right where you know
感觉不对劲，你知道的。
like man I ate all you could eat pizza
我简直吃光了自助披萨！
last night like I know why I feel this
昨晚，我好像知道我为什么会有这种感觉了
way because of that thing I did last
都是因为我上次做的那件事。
night um if there is a pathogen if there
晚上，嗯，如果有病原体的话……
is an something suppressing your immune
是不是有什么东西在抑制你的免疫力？
system If U endocrine system is not
如果 U 内分泌系统不存在
happy with something going on oxidative
很高兴看到氧化作用正在发生。
stress something like that could be
像这样的压力可能会
happening um a lot of times these can be
很多时候都会发生这种情况。
falling into sleep as well we've seen a
我们也看到了入睡的情况
number of times where people have a um a
人们有“嗯……”这种情况的次数
self-
自己-
perceived I sleep okay I sleep pretty
我感觉自己睡得还不错，睡得很好。
decent and then we can actually run real
不错，然后我们就可以真正开始运行了。
true in depth analysis and we can see hu
真正的深入分析，我们可以看到……
in fact we've had multiple times where
事实上，我们已经多次遇到这种情况：
we've like very likely saved somebody's
我们很可能救了某人的命。
life because there's self-perceived
生活，因为存在自我感知
sleep was pretty good and we were able
睡眠质量很好，我们能够
to actually see like your your steps
真正看到你的步骤
away from a heart attack um and
远离心脏病发作
effectively put them basically in a
实际上，基本上是将它们置于一个
hospital within a few weeks and and
几周内就住院了。
we're told many times like you basically
我们经常被告知，基本上就是这样。
saved this guy's life that's happened
这件事救了这个人的命。
countless times so there are things that
无数次，所以有些事情
are going on that are beyond your
正在发生的事情超出了你的理解范围。
perception that we can see um whether
我们能否感知到……
it's through some of our molecular
这是通过我们的一些分子实现的
biomarkers whether it's again our brain
生物标志物是否又与我们的大脑有关？
analysis like a lot of the stuff that we
分析就像我们分析的很多东西一样
can see um other ones that are common
可以看到其他一些常见的
are things like muscle strength muscle
肌肉力量之类的东西是肌肉
performance people don't realize how
绩效人员没有意识到这一点
telling those can be over your overall
告诉那些可能会影响你整体表现的人
physiological Health but you don't
生理健康，但你没有
necessarily see them a really easy
不一定认为他们很容易
example is most people um are somewhat
例如，大多数人嗯，都有些
aware that grip strength yeah is a
我知道握力确实很重要。
incredibly important predictor of in
极其重要的预测因素
fact there's a really cool paper it's
事实上，有一篇非常棒的论文，它是
titled something like grip strength is
标题类似“握力”之类的
an indispensable marker of Aging
衰老不可或缺的标志
something like that right which is
差不多就是这样，对吧？
basically saying like you can't not pay
基本上就是说你不能不付钱。
attention to grip strike and we've
注意握拳姿势，我们已经
actually published a paper last year
实际上去年就发表过一篇论文。
Tommy wood um from the University of
来自大学的汤米·伍德
Washington neuroscientists LED this
华盛顿的神经科学家领导了这项研究
project and we've got a couple of them
项目，我们已经有几个了。
going but one of the things things we
去吧，但其中一件事是我们
found there is is we can actually
我们发现那里确实存在我们可以实际做到的事情
predict um Alzheimer's and Dementia risk
预测阿尔茨海默病和痴呆症风险
via grip strength
通过握力
testing and strongly we actually have a
测试结果非常可靠，我们实际上已经……
project right now that we validated in
我们目前正在验证的项目
the UK biobank which is 500,000 people
英国生物银行，包含50万人。
or so we validated it in the American
或者说，我们在美国证实了这一点。
equivalent which is called n Hanes um we
等价物，称为 n Hanes um 我们
can actually predict muscle quality from
实际上可以通过以下方式预测肌肉质量
four blood markers and we can also
四种血液标志物，我们还可以
predict the risk of dementia as well
也能预测患痴呆症的风险。
from those four basic biomarkers and
从这四种基本生物标志物中
those are also directly tied to grip
这些也与握把直接相关。
right and so looking at things like that
对，所以要考虑诸如此类的事情。
is saying okay you have some potential
意思是说，好吧，你有一些潜力
signs of of either short-term or
短期或长期迹象
long-term physiological stress that's
长期生理压力是指
happening and you don't necessarily feel
事情正在发生，但你未必有这种感觉。
it yet because you're 35 or 45 and you
因为你已经35岁或45岁了，所以你还没做。
don't feel super weak but we're seeing
虽然感觉不是很虚弱，但我们看到
these early signs one other example of
这些早期迹象是另一个例子
that and I and I'll caution to say that
而且，我还要谨慎地说：
there's only been one paper on this so
目前只有一篇关于这方面的论文。
in science that's a way of
在科学中，这是一种……
saying we'll see like okay but just as
说我们会看看情况，好吧，但就像
one example this paper came out last
一个例子是，这篇论文最后才发表。
year and it showed that the asymmetry in
一年，结果表明，不对称性
your grip strength so the difference in
你的握力，所以这方面的差异
strength between your right and left
你左右两侧的力量
hand is actually an early predictor of
手实际上是早期预测指标
neurological
神经系统
Decline and the reason is think about
下降的原因在于思考
this in order for your muscles to
这样做是为了让你的肌肉……
contract they have to be sent a signal
合同中必须向他们发送信号
from your central nervous system your
来自你的中枢神经系统
brain and brain stem and if you're
大脑和脑干，以及如果你是
having significant asymmetries from one
存在显著的不对称性
side to the other and by this they meant
左右两边，他们的意思就是
over 10% so if you have a grip strength
超过 10%，所以如果你有握力的话
of 40 kilos on the right hand 10% of
右手负重40公斤，占总重量的10%。
that would be 4 kilos so if your left
那将是4公斤，所以如果你左边
hand is 30 kilos that's way more than
手重30公斤，远远超过
10% difference that may be an early sign
10%的差异可能是早期征兆
of of early denervation of that left
左侧早期去神经支配
side and so neurologically I'm
侧面，所以从神经学角度来说，我是
potentially losing ground there so just
可能会在那里失去阵地，所以……
things like that are are things were
诸如此类的事情都是过去的事情。
able to detect this is hey we're seeing
能够检测到这一点，嘿，我们看到了
things that are putting stress on your
给你带来压力的事情
system whether you realize that or not
无论你是否意识到，这都是一个系统。
so they can be these molecular
所以它们可以是这些分子。
biomarkers but they can also be other
生物标志物，但它们也可以是其他东西。
things that people just either don't
人们要么根本不会做的事
have a technology or they don't know how
他们要么掌握了这项技术，要么就不知道该怎么做。
to or or they're not aware that that can
他们可能没有意识到这一点。
give you tremendous insights into the
让你对……有深刻的了解
overall stress as scientifically we call
总体压力，我们科学上称之为
this allostatic load or
这种异质性负荷或
allostasis but that's the marker where
异质稳态，但那是标志物
after ultimately and in the case of grip
最终，在握力的情况下
strength I find that so fascinating
我觉得力量这一点非常迷人。
because I was reading about that in your
因为我在你的文章里读到过这件事。
work um a while ago that it could also
之前的工作也可能导致这种情况。
be the case that I've just trained one
假设我刚刚训练了一个
side to totally it could so it's if
从侧面看，它完全有可能，所以如果
you've trained one side then you're yeah
你训练了一边，那么你就是……
then if you've only gone after one side
如果你只针对了其中一方的话。
you've done either a sport
你要么参加过体育运动，要么参加过其他体育运动。
or you have a lifestyle or an occupation
或者你有一种生活方式或职业
that is really one side dependent it
这完全取决于单方面因素。
could be as simple as but for the
可能很简单，但是对于
typical person we tend to yeah be fairly
我们这类人通常都比较……嗯，相当……
even and asymmetrical sorry symmetrical
均匀且不对称，抱歉，对称
with our grip strength yeah remember
凭借我们的握力，是的，记得吗？
these are population averages sure right
这些是人口平均值，没错吧？
this is one study it's you know the
这是一项研究，你知道的
individual person always uh means less
个人总是意味着更少
to the individual person than it does to
对个人而言，这比对……
the population when we were talking
我们谈话时的人口数量
about some of these invisible stresses
关于其中一些隐形压力
um my partner came back to the house two
嗯，我的伴侣回到了家。
days ago and said babe I've just found
几天前，我说宝贝，我刚刚发现
out from the doctor because she did a
因为医生做了什么，所以她离开了医生。
bunch of tests and she hadn't been
她做了好几项测试，但都没通过。
feeling so great but one of the things
感觉非常好，但其中一件事
we found out was that she was very
我们发现她非常
deficient in vitamin D and it made me
维生素D缺乏，这让我
wonder how many people are walking
想知道有多少人在步行
around and you must have seen this in
周围，​​你肯定见过这种情况。
some of the the lab work you've done
你做过的一些实验室工作
with a deficiency in things like vitamin
缺乏维生素等物质
D and what is what is then the symptom
D，那么症状是什么呢？
of that
那
deficiency so vitamin D is one of the
缺乏症，例如维生素D缺乏症，是导致维生素D缺乏的原因之一。
more common deficiencies you will
更常见的缺陷是您将
see you will not see or feel that oh
你不会看到也不会感觉到这一点。哦
this is another example of potentially
这是另一个潜在的例子。
hidden stressor right what could you be
隐藏的压力源是什么？你可能是什么？
experiencing vitamin D is associated
维生素D缺乏与
with low bone mineral density low muscle
骨密度低，肌肉量少
size low muscle strength cognitive
体型小、肌肉力量弱、认知能力低
function uh immune
功能呃免疫
function mental health so you could be
心理健康功能，所以你可能会……
experiencing any number of things and
经历各种各样的事情
vitamin D being low could be
维生素D水平低可能是
contributing to that it's very likely to
导致这种情况发生的可能性很大
be the sole explainer of any individual
成为任何个人的唯一解释者
thing but it could be playing a larg
但这事儿可能起着重要作用
impact vitamin D is also one of the
维生素D的影响也是其中之一。
higher safety profiles and so typically
更高的安全性能，因此通常
what I tell people is I don't like when
我告诉别人，我不喜欢……
people go after supplements specifically
人们专门购买营养补充剂。
vitamins and minerals you can get away
你可以摄取的维生素和矿物质
with vitamins a little bit more minerals
添加维生素和少量矿物质
be really careful of but vitamin D
一定要小心维生素D
honestly you can go pretty wild with it
说实话，你可以尽情发挥创意。
and the chances of you being deficient
以及你缺乏这种能力的可能性
or even just subclinically low as we'll
或者甚至只是亚临床水平低，就像我们所说的那样。
call that chances are pretty high and
可以认为这种可能性相当高。
the chances of you running into issues
你遇到问题的几率
with the vitamin D are also very low so
维生素D水平也很低，所以
it's one of those ones that mask like
它属于那种会伪装自己的类型。
pretty good chance to be effective
很有可能有效
pretty low risk I'm okay with people
风险很低，我和人相处没问题。
really pushing vitamin D obviously
显然，维生素D的摄入量确实很高。
supplements the better answer is the
补充说明中，更好的答案是……
sunlight right yeah but if if you want
阳光对吧，但是如果你想
to take a supplement and you don't have
想服用补充剂，但你没有
the don't have money for or availability
他们没钱或没货。
to get blood testing done and you're not
去做血液检查，但你没有
sure going after a little bit of vitamin
当然要补充一点维生素
D is there are worse things you could do
D 表示还有更糟糕的事情可以做。
we'll put it that way so I'm okay with
我们就这么说吧，这样我没意见。
that one are there other deficiencies
除此之外，还有其他不足之处吗？
that you're more concerned about in
你更关心的是
terms of um vitamins yeah well well I
就维生素而言，嗯，嗯，我
you should be concerned about vitamin D
你应该关注维生素D。
being low because it is so effective in
价格低廉是因为它非常有效
so many areas that's generally how
很多领域通常都是这样。
vitamins and minerals work it's also
维生素和矿物质确实有效。
very very very common I maybe I I sort
非常非常非常常见，我可能我排序
of inadvertently blew past that so much
无意间错过了那么多。
because there there are things that we
因为有些事情我们
are going after much more that people
他们追求的远不止人们所追求的。
are unaware of um when you see vitamin D
当你看到维生素D时，你可能并不了解它。
on a blood panel and if it is low you
在血液检查中，如果这项指标偏低……
can take vitamin D that said you do want
你可以服用维生素D，也就是说，你确实想要
to be really careful if you get blood
如果出血一定要非常小心
work done of trying to just move those
尝试移动这些工作已经完成了。
numbers up and down and I'm going to say
数字上下波动，我要说
this for a couple of reasons vitamin D
这主要有两个原因：维生素D
is one of those ones that's okay if it's
如果符合以下条件，那就没问题：
low take vitamin D directly move it up
维生素D摄入量低，直接向上移动。
no problems there that said when you go
也就是说，去的时候没问题。
to interpret blood work you have to
要解读血液检测结果，你必须……
realize most of those values when you're
当你……时，你会意识到这些价值观中的大多数。
being told that number is high or that
被告知这个数字很高或者
number is
数字是
low I won't say they're irrelevant but
低，我不会说它们无关紧要，但是
they're misleading at the least and that
它们至少具有误导性，而且
to
到
say you've got some blood work done
假设你做了血液检查
right
正确的
and it gives you a whole bunch of things
它给了你很多东西
back let's say you did a basic thing
假设你做了一件基本的事情
like what we'll call a CBC and CMP so a
就像我们所说的CBC和CMP一样
complete blood count and a cardom
全血细胞计数和卡多姆
metabolic panel those are like the most
代谢指标，就像大多数
common things you'll get and you'll see
你会得到并看到的常见事物
all kinds of stuff in there white blood
白血里有各种各样的东西
cell counts and vitamins and and
细胞计数、维生素和
hormones and things like that okay great
激素之类的东西，好的，太好了
and then on the as you look over at the
然后当你看向……
paper on the right side it's going to
右边的纸，它要……
tell you a reference range that
告诉你一个参考范围
reference range is going to tell you
参考范围会告诉你
whether you're high or low right and so
无论你情绪高涨还是低落，对吧？
on that test you did right um it
那次考试你考得不错，嗯……
probably said you know your vitamin D
可能说过你知道你的维生素D
level is 20 and it should be between 30
等级是20，应该在30之间。
and 100 something like that great well
还有一百多个类似的，真棒
it's that 30 to 100 part where things
就是那30到100之间的部分，事情就是这样。
get
得到
squarely because did they take into
完全是因为他们是否考虑过
account
帐户
ethnicity okay those numbers differ
种族方面，这些数字有所不同。
based on your ethnic background right
基于你的种族背景
what is normal as we said earlier is
正如我们之前所说，正常情况是
also not the same as what is common okay
也和常见的不一样，好的。
and it's definitely not the same as
这绝对不一样
optimal now remember and I'll try not to
记住，现在是最佳状态，我会尽量避免。
say this too many times I don't deal
这句话说太多遍了，我受不了了。
with disease I disee I deal with like
对于疾病，我看到我处理疾病就像
I'm not not in a disease state but I
我没有生病，但是
want to get better and optimized and why
想要变得更好、更优化，以及为什么
I'm drawing that distinction is because
我之所以做出这种区分，是因为
on a blood test you're looking for do
在血液检查中，你正在寻找什么
you clinically flag for an actual
你临床上标记出一个实际
metabolic disease or otherwise okay most
代谢疾病或其他方面都还好
of those things are set against that and
这些事物都与此相对立，
so their reference ranges are built off
因此，它们的参考范围是建立在……之上的。
of databases like the UK biobank like
类似英国生物银行这样的数据库
and hannes here who are generally not
还有汉内斯，他通常不是
healthy people and the people that are
健康的人和那些
in those data in fact we actually ran
事实上，在这些数据中，我们实际运行了
this and published this last year that
去年出版了这篇文章。
in the and haes database in America at
在美国的和haes数据库中
least the people that had the muscle
至少那些有肌肉的人
mass had no association between their
质量与它们之间没有关联
muscle mass and their exercise
肌肉量及其锻炼
history which means these people did not
历史表明这些人没有
gain muscle by
通过以下方式增肌
exercising now some people exercise in
现在有些人锻炼
these databases but you're talking very
这些数据库，但你谈论的非常
very small numbers in addition when they
此外，还有非常小的数字
build reference ranges so they're
建立参考范围，以便它们是
building it off of populations that are
它是建立在人口基础上的
not the healthiest and as you're aware
这不是最健康的选择，而且你也知道。
our our world is not getting healthier
我们的世界并没有变得更健康。
mhm so those numbers are moving okay now
嗯，所以这些数字现在变化正常。
when they build a reference range they
当他们建立参考范围时
use typically most companies by the way
顺便一提，大多数公司通常都会这样做。
every company that you get your blood
每家给你输血的公司
draw from has a different
从不同的地方汲取灵感
range so they're not all the same okay
范围很广，所以它们并不都一样，好的。
so that it's not like they're not
所以，这并不意味着他们不是
nefarious it's not it's just like they
邪恶的，不是的，就像他们一样
have different databases to pick from
有不同的数据库可供选择
many companies will give you a reference
许多公司都会提供推荐信。
range based on their own database okay
根据他们自己的数据库确定范围，可以。
so all you're seeing is like what's
所以你看到的都是像这样的东西
normal for the people that bought their
对于购买他们的人来说，这很正常。
lab right not population okay and they
实验室权利，人口没问题，他们
use a 95% curve which is to say 95% of
使用95%曲线，也就是说，95%的
people
人们
land within this spell curve and so if
在这个法术曲线范围内落脚，因此如果
you were within that you're normal 2 and
你在里面，你是正常的2，
a half% at the top 2 and a half% low so
最高处占0.5%，最低处占2.5%，所以
what that could mean is you could be in
这意味着你可能处于
like the 94th
就像第94届
percentile and be told you're in the
百分位，并被告知你处于
reference range easy example is
参考范围的简单例子是
something like blood glucose okay now a
比如血糖之类的，好的，现在
normal blood glucose is going to be in
正常血糖水平应该在……
the mid or mid 80s rather 80 85
八十年代中期，而不是八十年代或八十五年代。
something like that okay technically
差不多是这样，技术上来说。
you're not going to flag on most
你大多数情况下都不会出问题。
people's databases until you get past
直到你通过为止，人们的数据库。
like 110 120 130 plus you're actually
比如110、120、130以上，你实际上
diabetes and so you can come and flag
患有糖尿病，所以你可以来登记。
for like
像
108 and technically medically you're not
108岁，严格来说，从医学角度讲，你不是。
diabetic yet you're not pre-diabetic yet
你虽然患有糖尿病，但还不是糖尿病前期患者。
but there's no world on this Earth where
但地球上没有哪个世界是这样的
somebody has a fasting blood glucose of
某人的空腹血糖为
108 and they are healthy or they are
108，他们都很健康，或者他们是
optimally healthy we'll say right that
我们会说，处于最佳健康状态。
is in fact we have strong evidence you
事实上，我们有强有力的证据表明你
get past 95 you're starting to increase
超过95之后，你的速度就开始提升了。
your risk of oxidative stress
你患氧化应激的风险
retinopathy tons of issues happen with a
视网膜病变会引发很多问题
consistent blood fting blood glucose
持续监测血糖
over 95 and so a great example that
超过95岁，这是一个很好的例子。
would be you would be within the
你会在……之内
reference range there you'd be told your
在那里，你会被告知你的参考范围
normal and then I would look at and be
正常情况下，然后我会看着，然后……
like that's absolutely suboptimal is it
这绝对不是最佳方案，对吧？
clinically officially diabetic no but
临床上正式确诊糖尿病，但
I'm telling you right now to have to
我现在就告诉你，你必须
perform at your absolute best that's not
发挥出你的最佳水平，这并非易事。
the range you want to be in I'm going to
你想进入的范围，我将……
make it worse for you so the reference
对你来说这样更糟，所以参考
ranges are one particular concern the
范围是需要特别关注的一个方面。
second one is and the reason I brought
第二个原因是，我带来它的原因
this up with vitamin D vitamin D is okay
补充维生素D没问题，维生素D没问题
it's low you push it up no problem most
它很低，你把它推上去没问题，大多数情况下。
your markers you don't want to do that
你的标记你不想那样做
with though because physiology is
虽然生理学是
responding to physiology which means
对生理反应做出反应，这意味着
something moves something up and then it
某个东西向上移动了某个东西，然后它
moves something else down in the way
把其他东西往下推，挡住了路
it's the push pull thing so if you don't
这是推拉的问题，所以如果你不
know what you're pushing up you might be
知道你正在推的是什么，你可能会……
pulling something else down you're
你把其他东西也拉下来了
pulling something else down it might be
把别的东西拉下来可能是
pushing something else up you don't know
把别的东西往上推，你不知道。
what you're doing there so you don't
你在那里做什么，所以你不会
want to treat those markers as Like A
想把这些标记物当作 A 来处理
and B and C are low I should make them
B和C的值很低，我应该把它们做出来。
all go up you need to understand why
一切都在上涨，你需要明白为什么。
they're doing that low testosterone is
他们这样做是因为睾酮水平低。
an easy example low testosterone is
一个简单的例子是睾酮水平低下。
often times a symptom of something going
这通常是某种现象发生的征兆。
on you need to go backwards and figure
你需要倒回去好好想想。
out why is your testosterone low to
找出睾酮水​​平低的原因
begin with right because if you can do
先从正确的方向开始，因为如果你能做到这一点
that then then you get out of the way
然后你就让开。
testosterone will go up we've done this
睾酮水平会上升，我们已经做到了。
a countless times with people right
无数次与人打交道
we've we've doubled testosterone more
我们已经将睾酮水平提高了一倍。
times than I could even count without
次数多到我都数不清了
using hormones at all again I'm not
我不会再使用激素了
against hormone therapy like at all but
完全反对激素疗法
you don't always necessarily need it if
你不一定总是需要它
you can understand well why is your
你完全可以理解为什么你的
testosterone suppressed as it is if it
睾酮受到抑制，就像它本身一样。
truly is sometimes it's not like we you
确实，有时候我们不像你那样
know there are normal ranges for
要知道，存在一些正常范围。
different people but if we can see
不同的人，但如果我们能看到
something going on where you've got
你那里发生了一些事……
immunosuppress depression or something
免疫抑制抑郁症或其他什么
else happening that's again subclinical
还有其他一些情况，但那也是亚临床的。
so you're not sick all the time you're
所以你不是一直生病，你是
not like in a hospital bed it's like oh
不像躺在医院病床上那样，哦
okay we can see a and C happening those
好的，我们可以看到a和c的情况发生了。
are known to be associated with you know
众所周知，它们与你所知的某些事物有关。
compromising testosterone clear those
损害睾酮清除那些
things up and then back out of the way
把东西收起来，然后再移开。
and watch testosterone just take off
然后眼睁睁看着睾酮水平飙升吧
easy example this one is um my my
简单的例子就是这个，嗯，我的
colleague Dan Garner he did this one
同事丹·加纳做了这个
famously he had an athlete or a client
众所周知，他曾有过一位运动员或客户。
who actually had a a number of markers
实际上，他有很多标记
that are in a blood test so basophil
血液检查中检测出的嗜碱性粒细胞
specifically that are associated with
具体而言，与以下方面相关的
allergic reactions not an allergy test
过敏反应，而非过敏测试
okay but he noticed that this particular
好吧，但他注意到这个特别之处。
individual was doing everything right
这个人做的一切都是正确的
but that number was off the chart found
但这个数字已经超出了图表范围。
that actually was happening is there was
实际上发生的事情是这样的：
a a tree in this gentleman's
这位先生的树
neighborhood that was causing him a
那个让他感到不安的社区
little bit of a response so he had to
他略作回应，所以他不得不……
make sure he stayed away from that tree
务必让他远离那棵树。
his basil fill number went back to
他的罗勒填充数量又回到了
normal and this testosterone rocketed
正常情况下，睾酮水平会飙升。
really
真的
absolutely it gets more complicated okay
当然，情况会变得更复杂。
so take something like albumin albumin's
所以，拿白蛋白之类的东西来说吧。
a protein it's the uh it's actually the
一种蛋白质，呃，它实际上是……
protein on egg whites which is great it
蛋清中的蛋白质很棒。
does a lot of things it's a carrier
它功能很多，它是一种载体。
protein though so it carries um breed
虽然含有蛋白质，但它携带……品种
blood cells it carries cortisol through
它通过血细胞携带皮质醇
your body it's also what's called an
你的身体，它也被称为……
acute phase reactant mean it it will
急性期反应物意味着它会
respond to acute changes in your body
对身体的急性变化做出反应
albumin is is a really good way to
白蛋白是一种非常好的方法
measure hydration most people have no
测量大多数人的水分含量
idea about that right it's because when
关于这一点的想法是对的，因为当
you get dehydrated a little bit albumin
你会有点脱水，白蛋白
is measured based on concentration so
它是根据浓度来衡量的，因此
how much is there relative to how much
相对于多少而言，有多少
blood so if you take the total amount of
所以如果你取血液总量
blood down then the concentration of
血液向下流动，然后浓度
albumin looks like it goes up right you
白蛋白看起来好像会上升。
see what I'm saying so in when you're
你明白我的意思吗？所以当你……
dehydrated albumin levels will go up
脱水白蛋白水平会升高
however when you're
然而，当你
inflamed it goes the opposite
炎症会使情况相反。
direction and so if you look on a blood
方向，所以如果你观察血液
test if you're a little bit dehydrated a
测试一下你是否有点脱水
little bit inflamed what's albumin going
有点发炎，白蛋白去哪儿了？
to look like level dead in the middle
看起来像正中间的水平面
yeah this is exactly what happens when
是的，这正是当……时发生的情况。
people do things like I feel suboptimal
人们会做一些事情，比如我觉得自己状态不佳。
or terrible or just not at my best but
或者说很糟糕，或者只是状态不好，但
my labs look okay nothing's off the
我的化验结果看起来没问题，一切正常。
markers that much like I don't I'm not
像我这样的标记，我不是。
clinically deficient or excessive to
临床上不足或过量
something so everything can be within
某种东西，这样一切都可以包含在内。
the reference ranges but given the
参考范围，但考虑到
reference range problem given the
给定参考范围问题
association problem and giving other
关联问题及其他
things that we uh really happen as that
我们实际发生的事情就是这样。
multifaceted approach we can absolutely
我们完全可以采取多方面的方法
see what's explaining why you're feeling
看看是什么原因导致你感到不舒服。
what you're feeling dead in your blood
你感觉自己死透了
panels without anything ever being off
面板从未关闭过
your reference range in that particular
您在那个特定领域的参考范围
case if your alumin was up or down and
如果你的铝是向上还是向下，情况会怎样？
then you went in and did something
然后你进去做了某件事。
specifically to change your alumen
具体来说，是为了改变你的铝
you've actually now messed with the
你实际上已经把事情搞砸了。
entire system when it had nothing to do
整个系统在与此事无关的情况下运行
with alumen it was just the fact that
用明矾的话，事实就是如此。
you needed to drink some more water and
你需要多喝点水。
lower overall inflammation so I say that
降低整体炎症水平，所以我这么说
to caution folks of saying like be
提醒人们不要说类似这样的话
really careful about especially if
尤其要格外小心。
you're going to go to minerals and then
你要去矿物部门，然后
absolutely with medications please let a
请务必让医生了解药物的使用方法。
qualified physician or somebody that
合格的医生或其他人
understands blood work at this level
具备这种级别的血液检测知识
really make sure that they're helping
务必确保他们确实在提供帮助。
you um One More Time vitamin D is a good
你嗯，再说一遍，维生素D很好
example of something that's okay you
举个例子，说明你做某件事是可以的。
push that one up no problem there for
把那个推上去没问题。
the most part there there are times when
大多数情况下，总会有那么一些时候
it is but the rest of them folks like be
确实如此，但其他人喜欢……
a bit careful there so what are the if I
小心点，如果我……
if I stay away from the temptation of
如果我远离诱惑
the industry that says like drugs and
像毒品这样的行业
minerals and supplements are the answer
矿物质和补充剂是答案
to everything and I come back down to
一切，然后我又回到了原点
the sort of fundamentals of health and
健康的基本要素和
performance sleep is one of the
睡眠质量是提高运动表现的关键因素之一。
fundamentals right oh it pro arguably
基本功对吧，哦，它专业，可以说是
the core yeah so thinking about sleep
核心是的，所以在考虑睡眠
then so many of us are suffering with
那么，我们当中有那么多人正在遭受痛苦。
sleep my sleep for whatever reason is
不知何故，我的睡眠状况是
really really good in terms of duration
持续时间方面真的非常好
I don't know about quality we can you're
我不了解质量，我们可以……
making a face on me I don't know about
对我做鬼脸，我不知道。
quality but the duration is great and I
质量很好，而且时长很长，我
speak to so many people I think
我觉得跟很多人交谈过。
increasing numbers that are struggling
越来越多的人正面临困境。
with sleep for whatever reason if
无论出于何种原因，如果睡眠不足
someone comes to your Labs you know and
有人来你的实验室，你知道的。
you realize that there's an issue with
你意识到存在问题
sleep a how do you realize there's an
睡觉时，你如何意识到有一个
issue and what are the first steps you
问题是什么？您首先应该采取哪些措施？
take to help correct that so that they
采取措施帮助纠正这种情况，以便他们
can get that foundation in place so I
可以先打好基础，这样我
want to know exactly how you're sleeping
想知道你睡眠的具体情况
so I know exactly why you're sleeping
所以我知道你为什么睡着了。
that way so then we know exactly what to
这样我们就能确切地知道该怎么做了。
do about it and this is why frankly our
就此采取行动，坦白说，这就是我们
success rates are so high okay what do
成功率这么高，好吧，该怎么办？
we want to do I want to run the most
我们想做的，我想跑最多
in-depth analysis of your sleep
对您的睡眠进行深入分析
absolutely possible so I have a company
完全有可能，所以我有一家公司
called absolute rest and so what we do
这叫做绝对休息，所以我们要做什么呢？
is we actually build full functional
我们实际上是在构建一个功能齐全的平台。
sleep labs in people's
人们的睡眠实验室
houses and this is all Wireless so we
房子，而且这一切都是无线的，所以我们
can run full full clinical grade FDA
可运行完整的临床级FDA程序
approved sleep studies in your house you
您家已获批准的睡眠研究
don't have to go to a hospital you don't
你不必去医院
have to go to anywhere else right um
必须去其他地方吗？嗯……
we're going to run that we're going to
我们将运行，我们将要
run this all wirelessly and we're going
所有设备都采用无线连接，我们这就出发。
to run uh we're looking at not only
为了运行，我们不仅要考虑
depth of sleep um the the the the gold
睡眠深度，嗯，黄金
standard in science is called
科学中的标准被称为
polysomnography right so it's the like
多导睡眠图，对吧，就是这样。
the wires attached to your brain all
连接到你大脑的所有电线
that stuff actually don't think
那些东西其实并不重要。
polygraphy is the best way there's a
测谎是目前最好的方法
better way to do it called
更好的做法是……
cardiopulmonary coupling where we can
心肺耦合，我们可以
actually look at your autonomic nervous
实际上，你应该看看你的自主神经系统。
system and how that's actually
系统以及它的实际运作方式
responding so I prefer that method we'll
回应方式我更喜欢这种方式，我们会
do both we we actually run full PSG and
两者都做，我们实际上会全力以赴地执行巴黎圣日耳曼的战术。
um cardiopulmonary coupling as well but
嗯，还有心肺耦合，但是
we're looking at that so we can look at
我们正在研究这个问题，以便我们能够进行研究。
are you do you have brexis like are you
你是英国脱欧的支持者吗？你是吗？
are your jaw clenching at night uh we're
你晚上睡觉时会咬紧牙关吗？嗯，我们是
looking at you are your leg moving we're
看着你，你的腿在动吗？
doing that also while we're looking at
同时，我们也在观察……
position so we're having this on your
所以我们现在要讨论的是你的立场。
right side on your left side on your
右侧在你的左侧
back where you at um we can actually do
回到你所在的地方，嗯，我们实际上可以做
a whole bunch of other fancy stuff with
还有很多其他花哨的东西
ocular metrics with eye tracking with
眼动追踪的眼部测量
facial scanning and like all kinds of
面部扫描以及各种其他扫描方式
other stuff but we want to most
其他东西，但我们最想做的是
specifically look at how you're sleeping
具体注意一下你的睡眠情况
we're looking at then why and so in
那么，我们现在要探究的是为什么，以及在
terms of why you're sleeping that's in a
至于你为什么睡觉，那是……
bunch of different buckets one of the
一堆不同的桶，其中一个
buckets is environmental and so we
水桶是环保的，所以我们
actually run full-time environmental
实际上运行全职环境
scanning of your sleep environment we
扫描您的睡眠环境
actually have a little device I take
实际上我有一个小装置。
take it with me like everywhere I go so
我走到哪儿都带着它。
we have our athletes always checking the
我们的运动员总是会检查……
environment when they're in hotels and
他们在酒店时的环境
places like that we can always run
像那样的地方我们总能跑
environmental scans to make sure that um
环境扫描以确保……
it's an optimal thing so we're looking
这是个理想的方案，所以我们正在寻找
for temperature humidity but carbon
温度湿度，但碳
dioxide dander pollen allergens molds
二氧化硫、皮屑、花粉、过敏原、霉菌
things like that we can all measure in
诸如此类的事情，我们都可以衡量。
real time instantaneously on that thing
实时瞬时地在那东西上
so we want to make sure nothing in the
所以我们要确保没有任何东西
environment is causing the sleep if we
环境因素会影响睡眠，如果我们
can check off environment then we're
如果环境符合要求，我们就……
looking at behaviors um you've probably
从行为上看，你可能已经……
heard a lot about sleep hygiene and you
我听说过很多关于睡眠卫生的知识，还有你
know don't watch exciting TV Thrillers
不看刺激的电视惊悚片
before night don't get on your laptop
睡前不要打开笔记本电脑
and work and answer emails and then fall
然后工作、回复邮件，然后就倒下了
asleep try to fall asleep five minutes
睡着了，试着入睡五分钟
later that's all behavioral stuff right
之后那些都属于行为方面的东西，对吧？
and I'm happy to talk about as many of
我很乐意谈论尽可能多的话题。
those as possible um but that that's the
尽可能地，嗯，但那就是……
like stuff people have kind of shared
就像人们分享过的东西
the world a lot right but then those are
世界有很多对的地方，但那些也是
very true and very real outside of
非常真实，而且在外界也非常真实
Behavioral then we're looking at
那么，行为方面，我们正在研究……
physiological so what are your actual
生理方面，你的实际情况如何？
melatonin concentrations how much
褪黑素浓度是多少
serotonin are you making dopamine are
血清素，你体内产生的多巴胺吗？
there what is it in your blood
你血液里到底有什么？
biochemistry uh precursors what is
生物化学前体是什么
actually happening so we're taking
事情正在发生，所以我们正在采取行动
salivary markers and blood markers to
唾液标志物和血液标志物
see what is going on in your physiology
看看你的生理机能发生了什么变化
that is U potentially causing or as a
那可能是你造成的，或者作为一种
result iron concentrations B vitamins
结果显示铁浓度和B族维生素水平。
like a ton of stuff that are that are
就像很多其他东西一样
needed for proper sleep physiology we're
我们需要良好的睡眠生理机能。
measuring all of that we also are
测量所有这些，我们也是
measuring psychology so we have a very
测量心理学，所以我们有一个非常
in-depth um way to to evaluate
深入的评估方法
psychology of sleep so previous trauma
睡眠心理学与既往创伤
and PTSD and associations there's a
以及创伤后应激障碍和相关因素
funny enough there is a ton of actual
有趣的是，确实有很多这样的情况。
Sleep Disorders caused by people's
睡眠障碍是由人们的……引起的
psychological state of their
他们的心理状态
sleep
睡觉
meaning we have had a lot of success you
这意味着我们取得了很大的成功。
know fixing sleep problems because
了解如何解决睡眠问题，因为
people just have such a negative
人们真是太消极了。
association with their sleep because
与他们的睡眠有关，因为
they've s slept so poorly for so many
他们已经很久很久没睡好觉了。
years that they actually start getting
那些年，他们才真正开始获得
anxiety when it starts getting late at
夜深时会感到焦虑
night because they just know they're not
夜晚，因为他们知道自己不是
going to sleep well and so now actually
睡个好觉，所以现在实际上
the the problem is gone but they have
问题解决了，但他们还有
have such a problem they get into this
他们遇到这样的问题，就会陷入这种境地。
is a common one of like I get so tired I
这是一种很常见的情况，比如我太累了，我
get so tired I can't I fall asleep on
累得睡不着了
the couch and then I get in bed I lay
我先在沙发上躺下，然后上床躺下。
there for hours or the the classic one
在那里待上几个小时，或者去体验经典的那种。
we get here is I fall asleep immediately
我们到这儿的时候，我立刻就睡着了。
but then two to three hours in the night
但之后两到三个小时会在夜间到来。
I wake up and then I'm shot awake okay
我醒来，然后就被突然惊醒了，好吧。
great like those are all like pretty
太棒了，就像那些一样漂亮
clear solu or causes a lot of the times
澄清溶液或导致很多时候
so they have very clear Solutions um
所以他们有非常明确的解决方案。
that are not not very often supplements
这些并非经常作为补充剂使用
what do you do in those cases cuz I a
在这种情况下你会怎么做？因为我
lot of people that have messaged me
很多人给我发了消息。
speak to exactly what you've described
正是你所描述的那种情况。
that yeah so we would go back and
是的，所以我们会回去。
actually figure out uh again is this
实际上，再弄清楚一下，这是……
behavioral so are you doing the no
行为方面，你是不是在做“不”？
offense the idiot proof stuff like are
冒犯那些傻瓜式的东西，比如
you drinking are you like doing all
你喝酒吗？你喜欢做所有这些事吗？
those things so a lot of times it is
所以很多时候都是这些事情。
simple as that a lot of the times you
很多时候就这么简单。
don't need to spend a dollar on any
无需在任何方面花费一分钱
assessment it is really truly do the
评估确实非常重要
stuff people have told you 100 times to
人们已经跟你说过一百遍的事
stop doing I mean on the psychological
停止这样做，我的意思是，在心理方面。
Point yeah if it's just an anxiety
如果只是焦虑的话，那确实如此。
reaction well I started there for a
反应嘛，我就是从那里开始的。
reason because that can be causing it
原因可能就在于此。
okay so it is an actual sleep problem
好的，所以这确实是个睡眠问题。
you're happening you're having because
你正在经历你正在拥有的一切，因为
of your behaviors okay now let's say
你的行为，好吧，现在我们来说说
it's not all those things remember
记住，并非所有这些都是事实。
earlier when I said your body's
我之前说过你的身体
superpower is adapting responding right
超级大国正在适应并做出正确的反应
that's exactly what's happening if you
如果你这样做，那就正是这种情况发生的。
get into bed and you learn a pattern of
躺到床上，你就会发现一种模式
continuing to lay there and stay awake
继续躺在那里，保持清醒
or wake up in certain hours that pattern
或者在特定的时间醒来，形成某种模式
will be recognized and that pattern will
将被识别，并且该模式将
be repeated you have to break that
必须重复，你必须打破这个规则。
pattern so how do you do it this is not
模式，那么该怎么做呢？这不是模式。
very common but I'll give you like an
很常见，但我会给你一个
extreme example okay there's a thing
极端例子，好吧，确实有这么回事。
called Sleep restrict rtion training
称为睡眠限制训练
okay it's very effective but it is
好吧，它非常有效，但是……
brutal we don't go to it often one more
太残酷了，我们不常去那里，再一次
time but we have gone to it I have used
时间已经过去了，但我们已经去过那里了，我已经用过了
it it can be successful this is the same
如果它能成功，那就是一样的。
for people who wake up after a few hours
对于那些几个小时后才醒来的人来说
or struggle to fall asleep so what you
或者难以入睡，那又怎样？
do is let's say um you want to get up at
比如说，你想在……起床
we'll make the math easy here 5 o'clock
我们来简化一下计算，五点钟
in the morning okay great and you
早上好，太好了，你
typically get in bed at 10: and you lay
通常晚上10点上床睡觉：然后你躺下
there and you're kind of up all night
在那里，你几乎整夜都睡不着。
and you have all these sleep issues
你还有这么多睡眠问题。
right and then you wake up at 5: you're
对，然后你早上5点醒来：你
exhausted so you have to have Cafe
累了，所以你得去咖啡馆
caffeine all day and then you're up from
一整天都摄入咖啡因，然后你就醒了。
your caffeine so then you have to have
所以你必须摄入咖啡因。
melatonin right I can't tell you how
褪黑素，对吧？我不能告诉你怎么做。
many times we've looked at people's next
我们多次审视过人们的下一步计划。
morning melatonin concentrations and
早晨褪黑激素浓度和
seeing them 20 30 or 40 times higher
看到它们比以前高20倍、30倍甚至40倍
than the upper limit on the reference
高于参考上限
range value so then what happens when
范围值，那么当
you're walking around with extreme
你带着极端的……四处走动
amounts of melatonin the next day like
第二天褪黑素的量就像
you're sedated great so how do you break
你已经镇静剂起效了，很好，那么你如何打破这种状态
this cycle well one of the ones is you
这个周期，其中一个就是你。
stop those Habits Like not that much
戒掉那些习惯，比如不要戒掉太多。
caffeine that late and stop the
这么晚摄入咖啡因，然后停止
Melatonin okay I don't like melatonin
褪黑素？好吧，我不喜欢褪黑素。
like at all very much for almost
几乎完全喜欢
anything but we're going to set the
什么都行，但我们打算设定
clock and you're going to wake up at 5
时钟显示你五点钟要起床。
o'clock in the morning I don't care what
凌晨三点，我不在乎什么
happens you're waking up at 5: in the
碰巧你早上5点就醒了：在
morning period and we're not even going
早上那几天，我们甚至都没去。
to get into bed until
上床睡觉直到
11:59 so you're going to have five hours
11:59，所以你还有五个小时。
of sleep at most and you know what
最多只能睡一会儿，你知道吗？
happens night one you lay there and you
第一晚你躺在那里，然后你
don't fall asleep because you're in that
不要因为身处其中而睡着。
pattern right and you're also staring
模式正确，你也在盯着看
the clock knowing I have to get up at 5
时钟告诉我，我得在5点起床。
and you're laying there worrying and
你躺在那里忧心忡忡，
thinking about how you're not sleeping
想着自己睡不着觉
and it is brutal and you're going to
而且这很残酷，你将会……
have a couple of hours of sleep and
睡几个小时，
you're going to wake up at 5: and you
你早上五点就要起床：然后你
are going to get up at 5: every single
每个人早上5点都要起床。
day period no sleeping in a weekends
白天不睡觉，周末也不睡觉
okay you're also going to not get into
好吧，你也不会进入
bed no matter how tired you are you're
无论你多么疲惫，你都应该上床睡觉。
not getting into bed until
直到……才上床睡觉
11:59 you do that for a week what will
11:59 如果你这样做一周会怎么样
happen very quickly is your body will
发生得非常快，你的身体会
start to realize a new pattern of yo the
开始意识到一种新的模式
second she lets us lay down you better
其次她让我们躺下，你最好
fall asleep and you better not mess
睡着了，你最好别惹事。
around during those 5 hours cuz we're
那五个小时里我们一直在附近，因为我们
not getting any naps or not getting
不午睡或不睡觉
anything else right you will start to
其他任何正确的事情你都会开始……
fall asleep quickly and you will jump
快速入睡，你会突然跳起来
right into deep sleep and you'll you'll
直接进入深度睡眠，你就会……
go through a a pretty compressed but a
经历一段相当紧凑但
proper sleep
充足的睡眠
architecture every week then you add
每周的建筑设计，然后你再添加
back 10 to 15 minutes so next week you
倒退10到15分钟，所以下周你
go to bed at 11:45 and you know what
晚上11点45分睡觉，你知道吗？
happens next week when you get into bed
下周你上床睡觉的时候就会发生这件事。
at 11:45 you lay around falling trying
11:45 你躺在地上，试图跌倒
to fall asleep no chance right cuz now
现在根本没机会睡着。
you've got a week with pretty gnarly
你接下来的一周会非常艰难。
sleep restriction you fall asleep
睡眠不足导致你入睡
immediately 10 or 15 minutes a week
立即每周 10 或 15 分钟
after that and so what you end up doing
之后，你最终会做什么？
is you backfill until you get back up to
你要回填直到恢复到……
your eight or eight and a half hours but
你的八小时或八个半小时，但是
the pattern you're learning the entire
你正在学习的整个模式
time is when I go to sleep I fall asleep
时间就是我睡觉的时候，我睡着了。
and I do not wake up until that next
直到第二天我才会醒来。
time so you stop the overnight wakings
时间到了，这样你就不会再夜里醒来了。
you stop the struggling to fall asleep
你停止了挣扎着入睡
it takes a couple of months clearly and
显然需要几个月的时间，而且
it is brutal but it is very very
虽然很残酷，但非常非常
effective how effective from your
你的有效性如何体现你的有效性
research we've never had a problem with
我们从未遇到过研究方面的问题
somebody and not working really putting
有人，而且工作不认真。
it that way now again we don't use it
现在我们又不用它了。
very often yeah you don't need to yeah
很多时候，是的，你不需要。
you can do a subtler version of those
你可以做一些更微妙的版本。
things um so I want to acknowledge that
嗯，我想承认这一点。
as an extreme sort of thing and I don't
这是一种极端情况，我不这么认为。
recommend doing it especially if you
建议这样做，尤其是在你
have legitimate health concerns like you
像你一样，也有正当的健康问题。
want to have an MD or walk through that
想去看医学博士还是想了解一下？
something like that on you you can do it
你可以做类似的事情
on a more condensed scale though if you
但从更简洁的角度来看，如果你
generally if you're laying there
一般来说，如果你躺在那里
struggling to fall asleep uh almost
难以入睡，呃，差不多了
every sleep scientist is going to tell
每个睡眠科学家都会这么说
you you get out of
你出去了
bed because you don't want to set that
因为你不想把床铺好。
pattern of like every night I toss and
几乎每天晚上我都会翻身，而且
turn for an hour and a half that's a
转身一个半小时，那是一个
problem right and so you want to break
问题确实存在，所以你想打破这种局面。
out of that pattern one way or the other
无论如何，都会打破这种模式
to not just set up that routine and the
不仅仅是建立这种惯例，而且
same thing would be this is why it's
同样的道理也适用于此，这就是为什么……
important to not do things first thing
不要把事情放在第一位，这一点很重要。
in the morning that are deleterious to
早上服用对身体有害的药物
sleep so rolling over waking up and
睡觉时翻身醒来
immediately turning the TV on or
立即打开电视或
immediately looking at social media
立即查看社交媒体
because your body will anticipate that
因为你的身体会预料到这一点。
response it will then start a Cascade
然后它会启动级联反应。
prior to that that kicks you up and
在此之前，这会让你振作起来，
starts waking you up earlier and earlier
开始让你越来越早起床
every morning because it knows that
每天早上，因为它知道
stimulation coming at 6 am. and so
刺激活动将于早上6点开始。所以
instead of you waking up at 600 am with
而不是你早上6点就起床
your alarm and then checking your phone
闹钟响了之后，你又查看了一下手机。
your body starts to wake you up at 5:45
你的身体会在5:45开始唤醒你。
5:30 5:15 because it just knows that
5:30 5:15 因为它知道
thing is coming at 6 and so making sure
事情发生在6点，所以要确保
that your morning is not jump started um
你的早晨并没有被迅速唤醒。
in that direction that it really does
朝着那个方向发展，它确实如此。
wake up appropriately is really
适当起床真的很重要
important to those that like wake up
对于那些喜欢醒来的人来说很重要
super early and they just can't get back
太早了，他们根本回不来了。
to sleep there's obviously a a
显然，睡觉需要……
well-known might be a myth I don't know
广为人知或许只是个神话，我不知道。
that says we should sleep for eight
也就是说我们应该睡八个小时
hours a
小时
night well anytime you throw out numbers
晚上好，任何时候你抛出数字
like that again you're talking on
你又在谈论这个了
average for most people most of the time
大多数时候对大多数人来说是平均水平
uh we certainly have some people that
呃，我们当然有一些人
are high performing at seven maybe seven
表现优异，或许在七点左右。
and a half um we certainly have plenty
嗯，我们当然有很多。
that need nine 15 need more um there's
需要九个，十五个，还需要更多，嗯，还有。
actually excellent research on um it's
实际上，关于这方面的研究非常出色。
called Sleep extension research when you
当你被称为睡眠延长研究时
look at so this I love this this is a
看看这个，我喜欢这个，这是一个
great example of going from like are you
一个很好的例子，说明如何从“你是……”过渡到“你是……”
talking about risk of long-term health
谈论长期健康风险
or are you talking about maximizing
或者你是说最大化
performance okay now the research is
目前性能良好，研究是
clear going from like s and a half hours
大约一个半小时后，一切就绪。
to 9 hours is probably not needed to
可能不需要工作9个小时
minimize your risk of brain health over
尽可能降低脑部健康风险
there okay like seven out probably fine
大概七个人左右应该没事吧
however if you're trying to maximize
但是，如果你想最大化
your performance it's a different answer
你的表现会给出不同的答案。
the Sleep extension research will show
睡眠扩展研究将显示
you that the most classic one share M's
你认为最经典的那一个分享了M的
work out of Stanford many years ago now
多年前在斯坦福大学工作
but she took the Stanford basketball
但她参加了斯坦福篮球队
team and she had them sleep an
她带领团队，并让他们睡觉。
additional 2 hours a night in season
旺季期间每晚额外延长2小时
right they asked them to sleep for 10
他们要求他们睡10分钟。
hours a night the end result was I think
每晚工作数小时，最终结果是我认为
like 1.8 hours of additional sleep per
例如，每人每天需要额外1.8小时睡眠。
night for five to eight weeks in season
在季节里，夜间要持续五到八周。
okay now there's no control group
好了，现在没有对照组了。
there's there's lots of potential
这里有很多潜力
criticisms I'll acknowledge all that but
我会接受所有批评，但是
it doesn't matter because what we're
这不重要，因为我们是
getting at here you you'll see the
到了这里你就会看到
bigger point and so she did this in high
更重要的是，所以她在高中时就这么做了。
level athletes in season right now these
目前正处于赛季中的这些水平的运动员
also were not chronically sleep deprived
他们也没有长期睡眠不足的情况。
so they didn't go through like three
所以他们没经历三个阶段。
hours of sleeping like that they were
他们就这样睡了好几个小时。
sleeping seven hours or whatever and
睡七个小时或者更多
said go from seven to or uh eight hours
据说从七小时增加到八小时
go from8 to 10 on average those numbers
平均而言，这些数字从 8 增加到 10。
different for every person but that's
因人而异，但这就是事实。
what she did and what she saw was a 9%
她所做和所见的，占9%。
Improvement in free throw
罚球命中率提高
percentage enormous right wow about a 9%
百分比非常高，哇，大约有9%
Improvement in three-point shooting
三分球命中率提高
percentage Improvement m in Reaction
反应改善百分比
Time reduced sleepiness um improved mood
时间缩短，困倦感减轻，情绪改善。
and a handful of other markers improved
还有一些其他指标有所改善。
in season in division one basketball
一级篮球赛季
players now probably would have gotten
现在的玩家可能已经获得了
better in season anyways right like that
反正当季效果更好，对吧？
tends to happen again no control group
这种情况往往会再次发生，而且没有对照组。
so I don't want to oversell it but I
所以我不想夸大其词，但是
think it's pretty powerful saying hey
我觉得说“嘿”很有力量。
going from okay sleep to maximizing your
从一般的睡眠到最大程度地提高你的睡眠质量
sleep pretty big improvements um in all
睡眠方面有了很大的改善，总的来说
these tests in some of the tests like
这些测试在某些测试中，例如
the the reaction time test they did
他们进行的反应时间测试
daily for the whole season so it wasn't
整个赛季每天都这样，所以并不是。
just like well the one time they did a
就像他们有一次做的那样
test they happen to get better that day
测试结果显示，他们那天碰巧好转了。
same thing the free throw and
罚球也是一样。
three-point shooting percentage stuff
三分球命中率相关的东西
was done like in a weekly practice and
就像每周例行训练一样，
so they measured it you know weekly over
所以他们每周都会进行测量。
the season in pretty marked improvements
本赛季表现有了显著提升。
that's been repeated in tennis swimming
这种情况在网球和游泳比赛中都曾发生过。
cycling it's been done in as little as
骑自行车的话，最短只需……
45 minutes of extra sleep per night for
每晚多睡45分钟
3 days and we're seeing improvements of
三天后，我们看到了改善。
reductions in cortisol by 20% as been
皮质醇水平降低了20%
shown in rugby players uh reductions in
橄榄球运动员的减少情况
body fat improvements in V2 Max all this
V2 Max 中体脂改善所有这些
stuff has been shown when you go from
当你从
this like even seven to 7 and a half
这甚至比七到七点半还要多。
hour range to eight eight plus um
小时范围到八八加微米
there's been there's actually evidence
确实有证据表明
of 30 additional minutes per night uh
每晚额外增加30分钟
reduces likelihood of getting a cold by
通过以下方式降低患感冒的可能性
four
四
times so good to great it's not the same
时代从美好到卓越，已经截然不同了。
thing now I run many companies in a lab
现在我在实验室里运营着多家公司。
I have two small children like I I I
我有两个像我一样的小孩
know some of you out there like oh my
我知道你们有些人会说“哦，我的天哪”。
God if I could only sleep for 10 hours
天哪，如果我能睡上10个小时该多好啊！
like trust me like my wife will murder
相信我，就像我老婆会杀人一样
me just hearing that but my point is not
我只是听到了这个消息，但我的重点不是
that my point is to say look what if
我的意思是，看看如果
what if that work at Stanford was
如果斯坦福大学的那项工作是
exaggerated okay so instead of improving
夸张了，好吧，所以与其说是改进，不如说是提高。
3point percentage by 9% it was actually
三分球命中率提高了9%，实际上是
5% or four like I don't know but who
5%还是4%？我不知道，但是谁？
cares right pretty powerful and look at
关心对吧，相当强大，看看
all the other studies like they're
所有其他研究都像这样
they're all generally in science when
他们通常都从事科学方面的工作。
you see multiple
你看到多个
studies from different Labs different
来自不同实验室的研究
scientists different groups different
不同群体的科学家
populations and they're all generally
人口，而且它们通常都很……
pointing towards the same thing the
指向同一事物
numbers aren't exact and the mechanisms
数字并不精确，而且机制也存在问题。
yeah yeah yeah but that is when you
是啊是啊是啊，但那就是当你
start to get real confidence and with
开始建立真正的自信，并且
sleep extension that's where I believe
睡眠延长，我相信这就是原因。
the collective research is it's like
集体研究表明，这就像……
there's a lot of studies from a lot of
有很多研究来自很多方面
different scientists and a lot of
不同的科学家和很多
different athletes measuring different
不同的运动员测量不同的
things and you see this 3 to 10%
你会发现这种情况占3%到10%。
Improvement in most measures when you go
当你去的时候，大多数指标都会有所改善。
from anywhere between 45 to an
介于 45 到 之间
additional two hours per night for as
每晚额外两小时
little as 3 Days To up to 5 to seven
最短3天，最长5至7天
weeks so uh from a normal person
几周，所以，呃，从一个普通人的角度来看
perspective if you can sleep even 30
如果你能睡上30分钟的话，情况就不同了。
more minutes it's probably going to
可能还要几分钟。
matter if you can if you need it if
如果你需要的话，这很重要。
you're person who needs a nap and does
你是个需要午睡的人，而且确实如此。
well with napping that can be your
午睡也可以是你的
additional 30 minutes or 45 minutes or
额外30分钟或45分钟或
90 minutes or whatever um so different
90分钟或者其他什么时间，嗯，真是太不一样了。
people will get this differently I
每个人对此的理解都会不同。
personally hate napping like as as a
我个人非常讨厌午睡，就像……
personal human but we'll use it a lot a
虽然是个人化的，但我们会经常使用它。
lot of actually in our um like our
实际上，我们有很多……嗯，比如我们的
Executives and CEOs we do a ton of of
我们为高管和首席执行官们做了很多工作
very concentrated like intentional
非常专注，像是故意的
napping that's super super effective so
午睡真的超级有效！
whatever it is for you um I personally
无论对你来说是什么，嗯，我个人
do better if I just go to bed earlier I
如果我早点睡觉，情况会更好。
can't sleep in like that that will never
那样睡不着觉，永远不可能了。
happen but if I can definitely go to
可能会发生，但如果我能去的话，我肯定会去
sleep earlier I can't nap those things
早点睡吧，我没法打盹儿。
so whatever works for you in your
所以，只要对你有效就行
situation and your physiology but it's
情况和你的生理状况，但就是这样。
generally a good idea um I can't make
一般来说这是个好主意，嗯……我做不到。
the argument that you'll live longer by
认为这样会延长寿命的论点
going from 8 hour hour to sleep to
从8小时睡眠到
8:30 not at all but I can make a strong
8:30 完全不是，但我可以做出一个强有力的
argument that it will make you perform
认为这会让你表现
better what about sleep debt you know
睡眠不足怎么办？你知道吗？
because there's a lot of misconceptions
因为存在很多误解
that if I sleep for four hours today I
如果我今天睡四个小时，
just make it up tomorrow by sleeping
明天睡觉补上就行了。
another four hours and I think I've
再过四个小时，我想我就……
lived under that illusion for a certain
在这种错觉中生活了一段时间
several years of my life yeah it's an
是的，那是我生命中的好几年。
excuse I tell myself I'll just make it
我告诉自己，我会搞定的。
up on the weekend the here's the
周末到了，这是……
misconceptions about sleep
关于睡眠的误解
debt um one of the guys that works for
债务，嗯，其中一个为……工作的人
us at Absolute rest Steven lley from
我们来自 Absolute rest Steven Lley
Harvard he he will always laugh about
哈佛，他总是会嘲笑
this and you'll say yeah man you can't
这样的话，你会说，是啊，你不能这么做。
time travel as in like you can't go
时间旅行，就像你不能穿越时空一样
backwards and make the debt up so if you
反过来还清债务，这样如果你
only suff for four hours you'll never
只够四个小时，你永远不会
get those additional four hours back but
把那额外的四个小时还回来，但是
that's not what we're saying with sleep
我们说的睡眠并不是这个意思。
Deb okay you can't do that but you can
黛布，好吧，你不能那样做，但你可以
absolutely go from consistent diminished
绝对从持续减少
sleep to getting back out of that sleep
从睡眠中醒来
debt so when you think about sleep debt
所以，当你想到睡眠债务时，就会想到睡眠债务。
that way you absolutely can do it you
那样你绝对可以做到
phrased it well though a second ago
刚才措辞不错。
which is to say it is a huge mistake to
也就是说，这是一个巨大的错误
think I'll have inconsistent sleep short
我觉得我短期内睡眠会很不规律。
sleep and then just sleep more and over
睡着，然后继续睡，如此反复。
the course of seven days as long as the
七天的疗程，只要
total amount of hours add up to the same
总时长加起来相同
I'm fine and that is is a terrible
我没事，这真是太糟糕了。
strategy and I don't think a single
策略，而且我认为没有一个
sleep scientist in the world would
世界上最好的睡眠科学家
disagree with me there trust me we
如果您不同意我的观点，请相信我。
interact with as many of these people as
尽可能多地与这些人互动
you can so one of the things um you
你可以做其中一件事，嗯，你
mentioned earlier you said your total
您之前提到过您的总额
sleep duration is good okay great that's
睡眠时长很好，没问题，太好了。
only one component of sleep you also
睡眠只是你的一部分
mentioned Sleep Quality that's another
提到睡眠质量，那也是一方面。
really important component I would argue
我认为，这确实是一个非常重要的组成部分。
the overwhelming majority of people have
绝大多数人都有
never had an accurate assessment of
从未有过准确的评估
Sleep Quality but that's another thing
睡眠质量，但那是另一回事。
right what people also don't realize the
没错，人们也没有意识到这一点。
Sleep consistency and in fact a lot of
睡眠规律性，实际上还有很多
the data will suggest that sleep
数据表明睡眠
consistency is more important than Total
一致性比总和更重要
Sleep Time meaning you need to be going
睡觉时间到了，这意味着你需要去睡觉了。
to bed and waking up at roughly the same
入睡时间和起床时间大致相同
time plus or minus 30 minutes is the
时间误差在正负 30 分钟以内。
goal I'm a human too I will stay up you
目标：我也是人，我会熬夜陪你
know later and you know occasionally do
后来才知道，而且你偶尔也会知道。
things like that so we'll give our
诸如此类的事情，所以我们会给出我们的
people typically 45 minutes a grace
人们通常会有45分钟的宽限期
period but as like a your default State
句号，但就像你的默认状态一样
you should be trying to go to bed and
你应该去睡觉了。
waking up plus or minus 20 to 30 minutes
醒来时间前后误差20到30分钟
most of your nights um if you can do
如果你能做到的话，你大部分晚上都可以。
that you will see many of the benefits
你会看到很多好处
of longer duration by simply getting
只需获得即可延长持续时间
more consistent the other major
其他主要方面则更为一致
component of sleep here is sleep
睡眠的组成部分是睡眠
timing so um the performing at the same
时间安排，所以，嗯，同时进行表演
time of day the same type of
一天中同一时间同类型的
tasks is as important as sleep duration
任务量与睡眠时长同等重要
and Sleep Quality meaning we we take
睡眠质量意味着我们采取
advantage of this with athletes all the
这对运动员来说是一个优势
time you can predict winning percentage
你可以预测胜率的时间
of NFL games NBA games NHL games and
NFL比赛、NBA比赛、NHL比赛和
Major League Baseball games the big four
美国职业棒球大联盟的比赛包括四大联盟。
in America over a 30-year span can be
在美国，30 年的时间跨度内可能是
predicted by simply looking at who
只需观察谁就能预测
performed not in their time zone but who
表演者并非在其时区，而是由
performed in the time that was their
在他们的时代所进行的表演
normal circadian
正常昼夜节律
time what I mean by that is let's say
时间，我的意思是，比如说
you had a West Coast team whether they
你们有一支西海岸球队，不管他们
travel to the East Coast or not doesn't
去不去东海岸并不重要
matter but if they played on the East
重要，但如果他们在东部比赛的话。
Coast at the same time of day that they
在一天中的同一时间，他们
normally play on the west coast it
通常在西海岸演出
doesn't matter that they got on a plane
他们上了飞机这件事并不重要。
for three hours they they performed at
他们表演了三个小时
the same time of day that they normally
在他们通常所在的同一时间。
did they have a competitive Advantage
他们是否拥有竞争优势
somewhere between two to 4% depending on
大约在2%到4%之间，具体取决于
the study maybe a little higher over the
这项研究的结果可能略高于预期。
team that is playing at home in their
主场作战的球队
same building if they're playing at a
如果他们在同一栋楼里比赛，那就是在同一栋楼里。
different time than they normally play
与他们通常比赛的时间不同
so I'll give you like one example we
所以我举个例子，我们
worked with the univ University of
与大学合作
Washington football team this year on
今年华盛顿橄榄球队
their sleep and so if they play a normal
他们的睡眠，以及如果他们正常玩耍的话
West Coast game at
西海岸比赛
1:00 um in normal West Coast Football
1:00 微米，西海岸橄榄球正常比赛时间
Time 1 p.m. and then we had to go to the
下午1点然后我们不得不去……
east coast which we didn't have to too
东海岸，我们其实不必去。
often but next year we're going to start
经常如此，但明年我们将开始
having to go there right and we got
必须去那里，对吧？我们到了
there and we played a game in Ohio but
我们在俄亥俄州打了一场比赛，但是
we played it at 4 o'clock Ohio time
我们在俄亥俄时间下午4点演奏了它。
which is still one o'clock our time then
那时我们这边还是下午一点呢。
we don't have any concerns with jet
我们对喷气式飞机没有任何担忧。
lager travel but in fact in that case
啤酒旅行，但实际上在这种情况下
the Ohio team who typically plays at you
俄亥俄州的球队通常会和你比赛
a different time is having to compete
不同的时代，竞争也随之而来。
way earlier or way later then they're
比他们早得多或晚得多
actually at a at a circadian
实际上，在昼夜节律
disadvantage because we're playing at
因为我们处于劣势，所以我们是在……
the same local circadian time so it's
当地昼夜节律时间相同，所以是
not the time change that gets people we
不是时差问题，而是时差问题。
do the same thing by the way with with
顺便也用同样的方式做这件事。
our executive professional clients when
我们的高级专业客户
especially like negotiations if you're
如果你喜欢谈判，那就尤其如此。
doing like a team meeting you have to
就像开团队会议一样，你必须……
think well that's great but if you're
想想看，那太好了，但是如果你是
going to like actually have to battle
真的要打仗了
somebody like negotiation or make really
有人喜欢谈判或者真的
hard decision I want you making that
我希望你做出这个艰难的决定。
decision on your local schedule and I
关于您当地日程安排的决定以及我
want your opponent off
想让你的对手离开
schedule don't don't tell anybody who
日程安排，不要告诉任何人
said that you'll have an
他说你会有一个
advantage so you get the East Coast
优势，让你获得东海岸
person to have to have a a a 400 PM or
一个人必须在下午 4 点或
5:00 p.m West Coast meeting that's 8 or
下午 5:00 西海岸会议，也就是 8 点或
N9 o'clock their time their their
N9点钟他们的时间他们的
cognitive performance is going to be
认知能力将会
lower than yours or the inverse so we
低于你的，或者反过来，所以我们
make sure we give our people advantages
确保我们给予员工优势
I was thinking about the gym because the
我当时在想去健身房的事，因为
time that I go to the gym fluctuates
我去健身房的时间不固定。
wildly sometimes I go in the morning and
有时候我早上会很随意地去，
I'm going to be honest because it's what
我要实话实说，因为事实就是如此。
I have to do sometimes I go at midnight
我有时不得不这样做，我得半夜去。
terrible idea I know you're gonna say
我知道你会说这是个糟糕的主意。
that Yeah we actually have we
是的，我们确实有
encountered this a number of times where
我多次遇到过这种情况
we see uh sleep issues we see energy
我们发现睡眠问题，也发现精力不足。
issues we see struggling to lose body
我们看到的问题在于难以减肥
fat issues things like that and they
肥胖问题之类的，还有他们
come in and they think they want this
他们进来后就以为自己想要这个
like secret recipe of supplements and
就像补充剂的秘方一样
you know blood markers and they want all
你知道血液标志物，他们想要所有这些东西。
this stuff and I'm like we do it I'm
这些东西，我就想，我们这么做吧，我是
like yo you got to stop training at
就像你得停止训练一样
night and we start looking at things
夜幕降临，我们开始观察事物。
like their respiratory rate their HRV
就像他们的呼吸频率和心率变异性一样
other markers of Sleep Quality and it
睡眠质量的其他指标及其
can be as simple as the fact that you
原因可能很简单，比如你
are doing too much high intensity stuff
他们做了太多高强度运动
in the evening that has a carryover that
晚上还有后续影响
carryover can be a couple of hours for
结转时间可能长达几个小时。
some people it could be six hours for
有些人可能需要六个小时。
other people and so if you are doing a a
其他人，所以如果你正在做一件事
training session at 10 p.m. you better
晚上10点进行训练。你最好
expect not to sleep very well that's
预计睡眠质量不会很好。
going to happen now some people are a
现在即将发生的事情，有些人是
little bit more resilient to that and
对这种情况稍微有抵抗力一些
others it's really really really
其他人则觉得这真的真的真的
damaging and so we have to pull people
造成损害，所以我们必须撤回人员
off of exercise a lot at that time or
那段时间经常停止锻炼或
minimum go hey yo for you if you're
至少要跟你打个招呼，如果你是的话
going to train at night it needs to be
晚上去训练需要这样做
restorative training short duration get
短期恢复性训练
a little sweat going don't get your
出点汗，别出什么岔子
heart rate up too high don't do anything
心率过高不要采取任何措施
too neurologically fatiguing and then
神经系统疲劳太严重，然后
get out of there we got to do our harder
快离开那里，我们得去做更难的事。
work in the morning um I'm just Mak it's
早上上班，嗯，我只是Mak，就是这样。
not always the case but it's more often
虽然并非总是如此，但这种情况更为常见。
than not that we have to peel people
而不是我们必须剥去人们的外衣
back that said again I work with
话虽如此，我还是和……一起工作
professional athletes we play major
我们与职业运动员进行主要比赛
league baseball games at 7 o'clock we're
晚上7点有联盟棒球比赛。
not done till 10 or 11 whether it's like
直到10点或11点才完成，不管怎样
hey they literally can't control it
嘿，他们根本控制不了。
that's their job or you know schedule
那是他们的工作，或者说是他们的日程安排。
wise whatever you you can work around it
明智的做法是，无论你怎么做，你都可以想办法克服它。
the world is
世界是
not perfect but in an ideal scenario you
并不完美，但在理想情况下……
really want to pay attention to that
真的很想注意这一点。
because that can can seriously affect
因为这可能会产生严重影响
what are the topics on sleep that most
关于睡眠，最热门的话题有哪些？
people just aren't talking about because
人们之所以不谈论这件事，是因为
you're right there's a theit proof stuff
你说得对，确实有防盗措施。
we all know about um but but from your
我们都知道嗯，但是从你那里……
research you must have discovered
你一定已经发现的研究成果
another set of issues that just don't
另一系列问题，却始终无法解决。
get the same level of Spotlight and
获得同等的关注度和
attention yeah um I mean I could I could
注意，嗯，我的意思是，我可以，我可以
go on about this stuff for a long time
就这些事情说个没完没了
we've mentioned the environmental piece
我们已经提到了环境方面的问题。
of it really important we actually have
这一点非常重要，我们实际上拥有
a a literature review in review right
文献综述正在进行中
now that that should be published fairly
现在应该公平地公布出来。
soon entirely on environmental factors
很快将完全取决于环境因素
Rel I've never thought about it before
我以前从来没想过这个问题。
when you start talking about sort of
当你开始谈论某种
pathogens in the environment I thought
我想到环境中的病原体。
Jesus Christ is that I didn't know that
耶稣基督啊，我以前不知道这一点。
was an issue oh oh yeah yeah CO2 I
二氧化碳是个问题哦哦耶耶
didn't think that was an issue when I
我当时并不认为这是个问题。
was asleep oh absolutely so think about
睡着了，哦，当然，想想看
it this way when you take a breath in
当你吸气时，就是这样
you breathe in oxygen when you take an
当你吸入氧气时，你会吸入氧气。
exhale and you breathe out you're
呼气，你把气息呼出。
breathing out CO2 so the difference is
呼出的气体中含有二氧化碳，所以区别在于：
O2 and CO2 is the carbon molecule now
O2 和 CO2 现在是碳分子
your tissue is breaking down car carbon
你的组织正在分解汽车碳
for all the metabolism in fact the way
事实上，所有新陈代谢都是如此。
that you produce all of your energy
你自己产生所有的能量
doesn't matter if you're using
无论你是否使用
carbohydrates or fat remember fat is
碳水化合物还是脂肪？记住，脂肪是
just a big long chain of carbon that's
就是一条很长的碳链。
what fat molecules are carbohydrates are
脂肪分子是什么？碳水化合物是什么？
a carbon that has a water on it it is a
碳原子上附着一个水分子，它就是
carbon that is been hydrated so the
被水合的碳
chemical equation for like glucose blood
类似葡萄糖血液的化学方程式
sugar is C6
糖是C6
h126 which means six carbons and six H2O
h126，这意味着六个碳原子和六个水分子
that's all carbohydrates are right
这就是全部的碳水化合物了，对吧？
they're big chains of carbon so whether
它们是巨大的碳链，所以无论
you're using carbohydrates or fat it
你用的是碳水化合物还是脂肪？
doesn't matter their the end product of
这并不重要，重要的是最终产品。
metabolism is going to be three things
新陈代谢包括三件事。
water ATP which is the central energy
水、ATP（三磷酸腺苷），这是中心能量来源。
currency and carbon dioxide great so it
货币和二氧化碳都很好，所以
doesn't matter what you're using for
无论你用它做什么都无关紧要。
fuel it doesn't matter what you're using
燃料是什么并不重要。
the fuel for exercise digestion building
运动消化所需的燃料
your immune system thinking it doesn't
你的免疫系统认为它不会。
matter remember your brain is a massive
记住，你的大脑是一个巨大的。
suck of of energy right uses the
正确使用能量吸取
majority of your ATP throughout the days
白天大部分的ATP
is to power your brain so great doesn't
就是要给你的大脑提供强大的动力，这难道不棒吗？
matter what it's coming from or what
无论它来自哪里，或者是什么
it's being used more metabolism for any
它被用于更多的新陈代谢
reason from any Source results in more
任何来源的原因都会导致更多
carbon dioxide buildup you take the
你摄入的二氧化碳积累
carbon dioxide out of your organs and
排出器官中的二氧化碳
tissue and you put it in your blood your
组织，然后你把它放进你的血液里
body is paying attention to carbon
身体正在关注碳
dioxide deeply right that's one of the
二氧化硫深度很深，没错，那是其中之一。
primary ways in which you regulate your
您调节自身的主要方式
pH your body will regulate PH almost
你的身体几乎会自行调节pH值
over almost anything else that it has uh
几乎胜过它所拥有的任何其他东西。
blood sugar pH um blood pressure things
血糖、pH值、血压等等
like that are like the tight things that
就像那些紧绷的东西一样
want to mess with ph is arguably the
想调整 pH 值可以说是
number one thing and the reason is if
第一件事，也是原因，是如果
you get too alkaline or too acidic
你的体液要么太碱性，要么太酸性。
enzymes don't work so everything shuts
酶失灵，所以一切都关闭了。
down so you want to keep your pH will
所以你想保持你的 pH 值降低。
stay very very very tight you could do
保持非常非常非常紧密，你可以做到
basically whatever you want you could
基本上你想要什么都可以。
eat and drink you could do anything you
吃喝玩乐，你可以做任何你想做的事
want and it's going to keep pH like
想要，而且它会保持 pH 值像这样
really really tight right it's hard hard
真的非常紧，很难。
hard to change so it's watching that CO2
很难改变，所以要监测二氧化碳浓度。
you take a breath in of O O2 you're
你吸入一口氧气（O₂），你就……
pretty much using that to run and
基本上就是用它来运行的
regulate cellular
调节细胞
metabolism you're managing O2 by
你通过代谢来管理氧气
altering respiration and so if you were
改变呼吸方式，所以如果你是
to hold your breath right now and you
现在屏住呼吸，你
were to 10 seconds 15 seconds 20 seconds
分别是 10 秒、15 秒和 20 秒
would go on right now I you could
现在就可以继续了，你可以
actually do this at home I would
实际上，我会在家做这件事。
encourage you to hit pause and do this
鼓励你按下暂停键并这样做
if you can not while
如果你不能在
driving if you don't breathe what's
如果你不呼吸，开车会怎么样？
going to happen is you're going to not
即将发生的事情是你不会
breathe in oxygen okay fine but really
吸入氧气，好吧，没问题，但真的
you're going to start building up CO2
你将会开始积累二氧化碳
because the way that you do is you build
因为你的做法是建立
it up in the blood you get it to the
把它注入血液，你就会明白。
pulmonary system and then you exhale and
肺部系统，然后你呼气
you get rid of it so you're breathing
你把它清除掉，这样你就能呼吸了。
your respir ation rate is entirely
你的呼吸频率完全
determined by how much O2 or how much
取决于氧气或氧气的含量
CO2 you want in your system that's what
你体内需要的二氧化碳就是这个。
regulates respiration such to say that
调节呼吸作用，也就是说，
air hunger you're feeling when you
当你感到呼吸困难时，你会感到口渴。
holding your breath it's not that you're
屏住呼吸并不是因为你
running out of oxygen you have anerobic
氧气耗尽时，你就患上了无氧症。
metabolism you can produce bolt loads of
新陈代谢可以产生大量的
energy without oxygen you have enough
没有氧气，你也能获得足够的能量。
oxygen in your system currently to go
你体内目前的氧气含量是多少？
extensive amounts of time you're not
大部分时间你都不在
running out of oxygen what you're
你快要缺氧了
feeling is a buildup of CO2 it's the CO2
感觉是二氧化碳积聚造成的，就是二氧化碳。
that drives your respiration so when you
这会驱动你的呼吸，所以当你
then breathe out you've exhaled and then
然后呼气，你就呼气了，然后
you're probably going to go and breathe
你大概会去深呼吸一下。
pretty hard for a few times because what
有好几次都挺难的，因为……
you're saying is there was too much CO2
你的意思是说二氧化碳含量过高吗？
build up I need to dump it so I can
积攒了太多东西，我需要把它们倾倒掉，这样我才能
lower that level okay now
把那个液位降低一点，好的
physiologically we call that hypo Capa
生理上我们称之为低容量
Capa is is carbon dioxide and hypo is
Capa 是二氧化碳，hypo 是
low if you breathe a
如果你呼吸，就会感到低落
bunch hyperventilate you're getting CO2
过度换气会导致二氧化碳积聚。
concentrations very very very low bring
浓度非常非常低，带来
it back if you hold your breath and hypo
如果你屏住呼吸并低氧，它会反弹回来。
ventilate you let CO2 concentrations go
通风可以降低二氧化碳浓度。
up CO2 concentrations have a
二氧化碳浓度升高会产生影响
bidirectional relationship between
双向关系
Psychology and
心理学和
Physiology okay so if CO2 Rises not only
生理学方面没问题，所以如果二氧化碳上升，不仅
do you feel a physical sensation in your
你是否感觉到身体上的某种感觉？
chest you feel a physical panic but
胸口传来一阵生理上的恐慌，但
you'll feel a psychological change right
你会立刻感受到心理上的变化。
it is telling you you need to move into
它告诉你，你需要搬进
what's called sympathetic drive this is
这就是所谓的交感神经驱动。
your fight flight or freeze right and
你的战斗、逃跑或僵住的反应是正确的。
this is great if you think about this
如果你仔细想想，这真是太好了。
from a normal electric perspective we'll
从正常的电气角度来看，我们将
get to a more interesting one here a
这里有个更有趣的例子。
second if I start moving and start
其次，如果我开始移动并开始
expending energy I start building up CO2
消耗能量时，我开始产生二氧化碳。
I want my brain to know hey this is
我希望我的大脑知道，嘿，这是
potentially a fight or flight situation
可能出现战斗或逃跑的情况
doesn't matter if it's that extreme
就算情况那么极端也没关系。
right it's just a gradient be more
对，这只是一个渐变，更复杂一些。
focused be more alert be more aroused be
专注、更加警觉、更加兴奋
more intent your vision literally
更专注地看待你的愿景
Narrows right be more focused um I'm on
向右收窄，更加专注，嗯，我正在……
task I'm like right now I guarantee you
我现在的任务就像我向你保证的那样
our respiratory rates are higher than
我们的呼吸频率高于
they need to be um I HRV is a little bit
他们需要……嗯，HRV有点……
lower right HRV is heart rate
右下角 HRV 代表心率
variability that's a measure of where
变异性是衡量某处
I'm at in the sympathetic
我处于同情心之中
parasympathetic drive right I'm more
副交感神经驱动力更强，我更……
focused our vision is very narrow right
我们的视野非常狭窄，这很正常。
now I got four feet to look at right and
现在我有四英尺的脚可以向右看，
I'm a tune I'm paying attention like all
我是一首曲子，我像所有人一样关注着它。
of our senses are really heightened
我们的感官变得异常敏锐。
right now when we're done we're probably
现在，当我们完成的时候，我们可能
going to go the exact opposite direction
正朝着完全相反的方向前进
right our vision is going to open back
没错，我们的视野即将重新开放。
up I'm not going to be paying things Etc
我不会再付钱了等等
I'm going to go into parasympathetic
我要进入副交感神经状态
parasympathetic is rest digest it is
副交感神经是休息和消化它。
chill it is Z it is depressed it's
冷静点，这是Z，这是抑郁，这是
lethargic it's all these things right so
精神萎靡，所有这些都是原因，对吧？
parasympathetic sympathetic is not good
副交感神经和交感神经的相互作用不好。
or bad you as a normal human want High
或者说，作为一个正常人，你很坏，想要高
resilience on both sides when you go to
当你去……时，双方都需要具备韧性。
bed tonight I want you to feel lethargic
今晚上床睡觉，我希望你感到昏昏欲睡。
I want you to feel no motivation I want
我希望你感觉不到任何动力。
you to feel Zen great I want digestion
让你感觉禅意十足，太好了，我想消化一下。
and things like that right now I I don't
诸如此类的事情，我现在不做。
want you to feel super Zen like I want
希望你也能像我一样感受到超级禅意。
you to be a little bit like May same way
你有点像梅，方式也一样。
right a little bit alert speaking a
稍微警觉一点，说话……
little faster than you'd like to be but
比你预想的稍快一点，但是
really focus driven and motivated that's
真正专注且积极主动的那位。
great I don't want you feeling that
太好了，我不想让你有这种感觉。
though before going to sleep I don't
不过，睡前我不会
want you feeling lethargic when it's
希望你感到昏昏欲睡
time to wake up I don't want you feel
该起床了，我不想让你有这种感觉
largic when we got to go to the gym so
当我们去健身房的时候，感觉很棒
it's about just making sure we're on
关键是要确保我们处于……状态
when we want to be on and not we want to
当我们想在线而不是离线时，我们想要
be on so your CO2 is going to tell you
保持开启状态，这样你的二氧化碳水平就能告诉你答案。
that so a physical stressor like the
因此，像……这样的生理压力源
exercise elevates CO2 tells the brain
运动会提高二氧化碳水平，这会告诉大脑。
sympathetic drive a psychological
同情心驱动是一种心理作用
stressor does the exact same thing so we
压力源也会产生完全相同的效果，所以我们
could be not doing anything we're
可能我们什么都没做
experiencing that right now we're not
我们现在并没有经历这种情况
moving at all for the most part but I
大部分时间我都动弹不得，但我
guarantee you our cortisol levels are
保证我们的皮质醇水平是
higher or glucose is being dumped into
葡萄糖含量升高或被倾倒至
the blood elevated uh I guarantee you
血气水平升高了，我保证。
our strength right now is higher our our
我们现在的实力更强了
speed our power our muscle endurance is
速度、力量、肌肉耐力是
higher right now than in the exact same
现在比之前更高了
situation if we were watching TV okay
如果当时我们在看电视，情况还好。
it's like we are primed and ready our
感觉我们已经准备就绪。
nervous system is actually literally
神经系统实际上是字面意义上的
primed you set out neurotransmitters
准备好的你开始释放神经递质
into the system already that are there
系统中已经存在的那些
ready to activate so it's faster okay so
准备激活，这样速度更快，好的。
that's awesome that's telling us to to
那太棒了，那是在告诉我们该怎么做
go the direction we want to be in now if
如果现在就朝着我们想要的方向前进
CO2 goes the opposite direction we have
二氧化碳的流动方向与我们相反。
the opposite feeling okay so we get
相反的感觉也行，所以我们得到了
super Zen super chin so what you want to
超级禅意超级下巴，所以你想要什么？
be doing is breathing at a rate to where
所做的就是以某种频率呼吸，即
your supply meets your demand if I'm my
如果我是我的，你的供应就能满足你的需求。
Supply is up a little bit and I have a
供应量略有增加，我有一个
little more demand then I'm going to
需求量再大一点我就满足了
breathe a little bit more normal
呼吸稍微正常一些。
respiration rate at night should be
夜间呼吸频率应为
something like 11 10 breaths per minute
大约每分钟呼吸11到10次
okay if you're looking at your overnight
好的，如果你正在查看你的隔夜账单。
sleep tracker and you're seeing you're
睡眠追踪器显示你正在……
breathing 16 17 18 breaths per minute
呼吸频率：每分钟 16、17、18 次
couple of things are probably happening
可能有两件事同时发生。
number one you may have some form of
第一，你可能患有某种形式的
sleep apnea you can't get enough
睡眠呼吸暂停症，你永远都无法满足
oxygen so you're ventilating more than
氧气充足，所以你的通气量比……更多
you need to be number two you could be
你需要成为第二名，你就可以
in sympathetic drive more than you need
出于同情心，你的驱动力超过了你的需求
to be okay now that could be happened
现在这种情况可能会发生，所以没关系。
for a number of different reasons but
由于多种不同的原因，但是
you're over breathing you shouldn't be
你呼吸过度了，你不应该这样。
breathing that much because your demand
呼吸如此频繁是因为你的需求
of energy is very very low and so you're
能量非常非常低，所以你
dumping
倾销
CO2 by doing that your CO2
这样做可以减少二氧化碳
concentrations get too low this puts you
浓度过低会导致你
in a little bit of a state we call
我们有点处于一种我们称之为的状态
respiratory
呼吸系统
alkalosis your kidneys will often times
碱中毒时，你的肾脏通常会……
not always often though respond by
虽然并非总是如此，但通常会做出回应。
trying to put you into metabolic
试图让你进入新陈代谢状态
acidosis and so there's a lot of
酸中毒，所以有很多
research showing that people that are
研究表明，那些
diagnosed with metabolic acidosis it's
被诊断为代谢性酸中毒
actually misdiagnosed in reality it's
实际上，这是误诊。
respiratory
呼吸系统
alkalosis that caus it's the over
导致碱中毒的原因是过度
breathing that caused the problem the
导致问题的呼吸
metabolic acidosis um you'll start
代谢性酸中毒，嗯，你会开始
changing how much bicarbonate you
改变碳酸氢盐的用量
recycle electroly light um we see
回收电解光，嗯，我们看到
hydration issues with this constantly so
持续的脱水问题
if you're an over breather like you're
如果你像你一样是个呼吸过度的人
going to have all kinds of hydration
将会进行各种补水
problems all that's going on over there
那边发生的一切问题
okay so getting back now that we have a
好的，现在我们回到正题……
little bit of foundation to what's
为以下内容奠定一点基础
really happening with CO2 in your room
房间里的二氧化碳真的在起作用吗？
if you are what we call CO2
如果你就是我们所说的二氧化碳
sensitive and you're intolerant to CO2
你对二氧化碳敏感且不耐受
so a little bit of CO2 starts building
于是，少量二氧化碳开始积聚。
up and your body already kicks you into
起床后，你的身体就会立刻启动。
a position where it thinks you're way
它认为你处于一种非常……的立场
too high it then will tell you to start
如果数值太高，它会提示你开始。
breathing you'll start over breathing
你会重新开始呼吸
that whole Cascade I just explained then
我刚才解释的整个级联过程
kicks in so what happens to your
药效开始发挥作用，那么你的身体会发生什么变化？
hrb gets worse what happens to your
HRB恶化后会发生什么？
ability to fall asleep gets worse oh I
入睡困难越来越严重，哦，我
wake up and then I can't get back to
醒来后我就回不去了。
sleep you look at your respiratory rate
睡觉时，你要观察自己的呼吸频率
you you check your CO2 tolerance you're
你检查一下你的二氧化碳耐受量，你是
going to know exactly why right now I'm
我现在就要确切地知道原因了。
about to finish the
即将完成
circle if it's not those
如果不是那些，就圈出来。
things and you simply are sitting there
事情就是这样，而你只是坐在那里。
let's imagine you and your partner are
假设你和你的伴侣
in your room um do you guys have any
你们房间里有吗？嗯……你们有吗？
other living things in your room this
你房间里的其他生物
sleep with you my dog your dog yeah what
跟你一起睡吧，我的狗，你的狗，是吗？什么？
size of dog uh not big not not big a
狗的体型，嗯，不大，不大。
foot and a half okay now um without
一英尺半，好的，现在嗯，没有
getting too personal here what does your
这里有点太私人了，你的
uh room look like when you guys are
呃，你们在的时候房间看起来怎么样？
asleep how big is the room roughly um
睡着了，房间大概有多大？
it's about the same size of the space
它的大小和空间差不多。
we're in now okay fantastic and is your
我们现在进去了，好的，太棒了，你的呢？
door shut is it closed always closed
门关着吗？它一直都关着吗？
always closed yeah perfect you you
总是关门，是啊，你真完美。
couldn't be seeing me up better here
这里再好不过看我了。
so you're at night laying there
所以你晚上躺在那里
breathing in and you're breathing out
吸气，然后呼气
and you're breathing out CO2 and your
你呼出的气体中含有二氧化碳，而你的
lovely little Bulldog is breathing out
可爱的小斗牛犬正在呼气
CO2 and your partner is breathing out
二氧化碳，你的伴侣正在呼气
CO2 so what's happening to the CO2
二氧化碳，那么二氧化碳发生了什么变化？
concentration in that room as that door
房间里的注意力就像那扇门一样集中在那里
is closed it's rising right it's going
已关闭，它正在上升，对吧，它正在前进
up generally not an issue not a huge
通常来说这不是什么大问题，也不是什么大问题。
deal but what of you is maybe a little
交易，但你身上可能有点……
bit CO2 sensitive the amount of CO2 in
二氧化碳含量对二氧化碳浓度非常敏感
your room is rising you're rebreathing
你的房间正在上升，你正在重新呼吸
that CO2 right back
二氧化碳又回来了
in CO2 is then getting too high that's
二氧化碳浓度过高就是这种情况。
going to cause your entire system like
会导致你的整个系统像……
we said earlier when when CO2 levels
我们之前说过，二氧化碳水平何时会升高。
increase this kicks off sympathetic
增加这种刺激会启动交感神经系统。
Drive puts you into fight or flight now
驱动力现在会让你进入战斗或逃跑状态
all a sudden HRV goes down a little bit
突然间，心率变异性略微下降。
resting heart rate goes up a little bit
静息心率略微上升
arousa goes up a little bit your body
身体的性兴奋感会略微上升。
temperature changes you're not getting
你没有感受到温度变化
into the same sleep stages and we're
进入相同的睡眠阶段，我们
having either a struggle falling asleep
难以入睡
staying asleep Etc in addition to that
除此之外，还有保持睡眠等等。
um there's a handful of studies now we
嗯，现在有一些研究……
need way more research here but there's
这里还需要更多研究，但目前有一些研究成果。
a handful of studies that have taken
少数研究已经采取了
people at what's called 900 parts per
所谓900个零件的人
million so that's the CO2 concentration
百万，这就是二氧化碳浓度。
that's the level right below 9900 parts
那是9900个零件下方的层级。
per million we have no issue and so
每百万人中我们没有问题，所以
normally like I'll check my house um if
通常情况下，我会检查一下我的房子，嗯，如果
if our doors are closed and stuff all
如果我们的大门紧闭，一切都乱套了。
day I myself two uh Shephard mix you
我自己两天呃谢泼德混音你
know rescues um wife two kids ours will
知道救援，嗯，妻子，两个孩子，我们的会
easily get up to 15,00 parts per million
很容易达到百万分之十五 (15,000) 的浓度。
now the research on this stuff has done
现在对这方面的研究已经完成了
experiments where they take people up to
在一些实验中，他们会带人们去
like 3,000 okay so can I make a strong
比如3000，好吧，那我能做一个强力的吗？
claim that if you're at 1100 parts per
声称如果你每人有 1100 个零件
million it's really going to screw up
一百万，这真的要搞砸了。
your sleep well I I I don't think
你睡得好吗？我觉得不是。
so but now we're playing a game of like
所以，但现在我们正在玩一个游戏，就像……
the studies have gone to the extreme and
这些研究已经走入了极端，
what they will see is a huge reduction
他们将会看到大幅减少
of Sleep Quality both subjective and
睡眠质量的主观和客观方面
objective so actually measured on like a
客观上，实际上是像……一样衡量的
a PSG system or similar as well as
PSG系统或类似系统以及
subjects saying like I did not sleep
有人说我没睡
well last night next day cognitive
昨晚第二天认知能力
function memory reaction time um
功能记忆反应时间
sleepiness um wakefulness um next day
困倦，嗯，清醒，嗯，第二天
executive function decision- making at
执行功能决策
work all this stuff is significantly and
做这些事情意义重大
when I say significant here I want to
我在这里说“意义重大”的意思是……
make sure I'm saying not only like
请确保我说的不仅仅是“喜欢”。
research statistically significant but
研究具有统计学意义，但
of a magnitude That Matters to your life
对你的生活至关重要
right so it's both clinically relevant
对，所以它既具有临床意义，又具有临床相关性。
and statistically significant so we're
而且具有统计学意义，所以我们是
seeing real reductions in Sleep Quality
睡眠质量明显下降
in fact there's a thing called something
事实上，有一种东西叫做……
to do with like a building sickness MH
与类似建筑物疾病 MH 有关
um where people like they they have
嗯，像他们这样的人有
headaches and they have uh they feel
他们头痛，而且他们感觉……
like you know brain fog and all that
就像你知道的，脑雾之类的。
stuff because they're in large like
东西，因为它们很大，比如
apartment buildings and the quality of
公寓楼及其质量
the air gets so low and by that I
空气变得非常低，以至于我
specifically referring to CO2 that they
具体而言，指的是他们排放的二氧化碳。
feel these issues and once they get Co2
感受到这些问题，一旦他们接触到二氧化碳
out of the room then this building
走出房间，然后是这座建筑
sickness thing goes away so if you're in
生病的事总会过去的，所以如果你在
that situation and that starts to rise
这种情况开始恶化。
and it does get up to 22,000 or 2500
而且它的确能达到 22,000 或 2500。
which is not that crazy you're
你说的也没那么疯狂。
absolutely going to see reductions in
肯定会看到减少
Sleep Quality um sleep onset again was
睡眠质量，嗯，入睡困难。
is a time it's called latency the time
延迟是指这段时间。
takes you to fall asleep waking events
带你进入入睡和醒来的事件
disturbances and then next day
骚乱，然后第二天
sleepiness wakefulness and cognitive
困倦、清醒和认知
function will be compromised certainly
功能肯定会受到影响。
up to 3,000 to 3500 parts per million um
浓度高达百万分之3000至3500微米
what happens at 2,000 I don't know like
2000米的时候会发生什么，我不知道。
again we need more research like where
我们还需要更多类似的研究。
is the exact line that starts to matter
正是这条线开始变得重要起来。
I do know you get up that high it starts
我知道当你爬到那么高的地方时，一切就开始了。
to matter and that number is not crazy
这件事很重要，而且这个数字并不疯狂。
especially for people who close their
尤其是对于那些关闭自己
door yeah I just thinking damn right
门，是啊，我当时就在想，没错
people who live in apartment buildings
住在公寓楼里的人们
uh or hotels where they can't control
或者像他们无法控制的酒店。
people that live in environments where
生活在以下环境中的人们
they can't open up their Windows because
他们打不开窗户，因为
it's too hot or too cold or rainy or the
太热、太冷、下雨或
air quality is really poor whatever the
无论如何，空气质量真的很差。
case is so if that happens a couple
情况就是这样，如果发生这种情况，几个
steps you can take take one you're not
你可以采取的步骤，如果你不这样做的话。
going to do cuz I don't do it either
我打算这么做，因为我也不这么做。
which is don't have your
也就是说，不要有你的
dog in the room uh I have two dogs and I
房间里有条狗，呃，我有两条狗，而且我
sleep right on the end of my bed like
我就睡在床尾，像这样
not on my bed but on the floor below it
不在我的床上，而是在下面的地板上。
so that that's out of the question but
所以这根本不可能，但是
making sure you have a lot of
确保你有很多
ventilation in your room if you can and
如果可以的话，请打开房间的通风口。
you want to use a fan in your room
你想在房间里用风扇
that's fine don't make it too loud if if
没关系，如果声音太大就别太吵。
you want to download there's all kinds
你想下载什么？各种各样的都有。
of apps you can download on your phone
你可以在手机上下载的应用程序
that allow you to measure the decimals
可以让你测量小数位数
of noise keep it under 35 35 decimal um
噪声控制在 35 微米以下
same thing by the way if you're using
顺便说一句，如果你正在使用的话，情况也是如此。
like a white noise machine white noises
就像白噪音机发出的白噪音
will actually compromise Sleep Quality
实际上会损害睡眠质量
they'll make it worse if they're too
如果他们太过分，情况只会更糟。
loud the other thing to do is if you can
大声说出来，另一件事是，如果你能……
get away with having your doors and
逃脱惩罚，拥有你的门和
windows open during times the day where
窗户在一天中的某些时段打开，
you can at least let that clear out a
至少可以让这种情况有所缓解。
little bit and then if you can shut them
稍微停一下，然后如果你能把它们关上的话。
you know even if you can open up up for
你知道，即使你能敞开心扉
half an hour or something like that um
大概半小时左右吧
all those steps will help manage CO2
所有这些措施都有助于控制二氧化碳排放。
that's just CO2 we haven't even gotten
那只是我们还没接触过的二氧化碳而已。
into the other stuff in your environment
融入你周围的其他事物
so is there any other big ticket sleep
所以还有其他高价睡眠项目吗？
items that are unobvious cuz CO2 for me
有些东西不太明显，因为二氧化碳对我来说很重要。
that's a revelation for me yeah sticking
对我来说，这真是个启示，没错，坚持下去。
with the environmental theme there are
以环境为主题的有
some things you can do for travel okay
旅行中你可以做些什么？
that are not super well understood one
那些不太容易理解的
of them is we've talked a lot about
其中之一是我们已经讨论过很多次的
patterning if you can pattern your sleep
如果你能养成规律的睡眠习惯的话。
environment at home with your sleep
在家中营造良好的睡眠环境
environment on the road you're going to
你要去的路上的环境
have much more
还有很多
success many people are aware of the
许多人都意识到了成功。
first night phenomenon which is the
新婚之夜现象，即
first night you get into a new place you
你到达新地方的第一晚
tend to struggle go sleep so the first
往往难以入睡，所以第一个
in a hotel or other place doesn't matter
在酒店或其他地方都无所谓
how comfortable it is cuz the body's on
因为身体贴合，所以感觉很舒服。
edge Bingo right so how do you take that
边缘宾果对吧，那么你该如何应对呢？
away well make the body think it's at
远离身体会让身体误以为它处于
home so how can you do that the sound
在家，你怎么能发出那种声音呢？
the smell the temperature all of this is
气味、温度，这一切都是
all these sensors are going in your
所有这些传感器都将安装在你的……
brain If you artificially design your
大脑 如果你人工设计你的
sleeping environment in your house any
您家里的睡眠环境
way that can be transported with you
可以随身携带的方式
then you can cut that problem down in
这样你就可以减少这个问题了。
large parts so if there's a particular
大部分部件，所以如果有特定部件的话
scent I don't mean like have a a plugin
气味，我指的不是像插件那样的气味
that there but some um like lavender is
那里有一些，比如薰衣草。
very common Lavender is highly
非常常见的薰衣草
associated with Sleep Quality um so a
与睡眠质量有关，嗯，所以
lot of people will do like a little bit
很多人都会喜欢一点点
of a lavender spray on the bottom of
在底部喷洒薰衣草喷雾
their bed or in the corner of their room
他们的床上或房间角落里
or just something very very subtle that
或者只是某种非常非常微妙的东西
you're not paying attention to um there
你没注意那个。
are companies that make little lavender
有哪些公司生产小薰衣草
sprays right and so then you have that
喷洒效果很好，所以就有了那个。
lavender scent at your house again
家里又弥漫着薰衣草的香气了
something that you would barely even be
你几乎不会是这样的
conscious of when you walk in then you
当你走进去的时候，你就会意识到这一点。
take that scent on the road with you
把这种香味带上你的旅程吧
when you get in your hotel room you can
当你进入酒店房间后，你可以
spray it around a little bit and now
稍微喷洒一下，现在
your body will go oh okay we're at home
你的身体会发出“哦，好的，我们到家了”的信号。
not going to fix it entirely but these
虽然不能完全解决问题，但这些
things can you can start stacking little
你可以开始堆叠小东西
behaviors like that trying to stay in
诸如此类的行为试图留在
the same Rhythm do the same thing the
同样的节奏做同样的事情
the 90 minutes before sleep that you did
睡前90分钟你做了什么
at home when you're on the road so don't
当你出差在外时，不要待在家里。
all of a sudden you know like switch out
突然之间，你知道，就像换了个地方一样
and shower at a different time or eat at
并且改天洗澡或吃饭
a different time like try to be as
不同的时代，比如尝试成为
consistent with your sleep routine as
与你的睡眠规律保持一致
possible will be the bigger ticket but
可能价格会更高，但
then little things like you know having
然后像你知道的，一些小事，比如拥有
the same setup if if you have a noise
如果出现噪音，则采用相同的设置。
machine machine take that thing with you
机器，机器，把那东西带走。
and try to bring that environment as
并努力营造那种环境
much as you can but the smell is a very
尽你所能，但气味非常……
big one because it's very high reward
很重要，因为回报非常高。
very low risk and you know pretty easy
风险极低，而且很容易。
to take a couple of ounces of a spray or
取几盎司喷雾剂或
something with you on the road is sleep
旅途中陪伴你的一件事就是睡觉
equal to recovery because I'm thinking K
相当于恢复，因为我在想K
now I'm really well slept sometimes I
我现在睡得很好，有时候……
wake up like last night in fact and I'd
事实上，我醒来时就像昨晚一样，然后……
had eight and a half hours sleep I'd
我睡了八个半小时。
flown in from London landed here in La
从伦敦飞来，降落在拉。
my recovery on my whoop band here was 10
我的 Whoop 手环恢复时间为 10。
12% it was really really low and I was
12%，真的非常非常低，我当时
shocked even though my HRV was quite
尽管我的心率变异性（HRV）相当低，但我仍然感到震惊。
high it was quite confusing I I spend a
高度，这相当令人困惑，我花了
lot of time thinking about my HRV I'm
我花了很多时间思考我的心率变异性（HRV）。
pretty obsessed with it and I spend a
我非常痴迷于此，我花了……
little bit less time thinking about my
少花点时间思考我的
my recovery but my HRV me and my friends
我的康复情况，以及我的心率变异性（HRV）和我的朋友们
Almost are like competitive with it we
几乎就像是在和它竞争一样
all have a little league table me and my
我和我的家人都有各自的小联赛积分榜
girlfriend it's one of the first things
女朋友，这是最先要做的事情之一。
we talk about in the morning every
我们每天早上都会谈论这件事。
morning do these things really really
早上真的要做这些事吗？
matter hrb is a very very strong metric
Matter hrb 是一个非常非常强大的指标。
it is effectively telling you the
它实际上是在告诉你
overall balance of your autonomic
自主神经系统的整体平衡
nervous system and that is very strong
神经系统非常强大。
there's a lot there's I don't know 50
有很多我不知道的 50
plus years of research on HIV it's not
加上多年来对艾滋病毒的研究，并非如此。
new it's not like it's very well
新的，但感觉不太好。
established it's highly associated with
已证实它与以下方面高度相关
actually um long long-term
实际上，嗯，长期的
cardiovascular risk Strokes hypertension
心血管风险 中风 高血压
blood glucose hyper cholesterolemia like
血糖高胆固醇血症类似
lots of things that are associated with
许多与此相关的事物
with HRV um mental health anxiety
伴有心率变异性（HRV）的心理健康焦虑
depression tons of stuff we also know uh
抑郁症，还有很多其他我们也知道的事情，呃
interventions that are generally
干预措施通常是
Associated to be positive for you
对你来说是积极的
exercise um stress regulation breath
运动、压力调节、呼吸
work meditation all generally improve
工作冥想通常都能有所改善。
HRV and things that are associated as
心率变异性 (HRV) 及相关因素
poor for your health like lack of
对你的健康不利，例如缺乏
exercise low quality nutrition alcohol
运动低质量营养酒精
use are also things that are going to
使用也是即将发生的事情
reduce in December about December the
12月减少约12月
20th or 30th around that time that 10day
大约在20号或30号左右，也就是那10天的时候
window my HIV was fantastic and then I
我的艾滋病窗口期非常棒，然后我
went keto for about four four or five
生酮饮食大概持续了四五年。
weeks for the entire time I was keto my
在我进行生酮饮食的整个过程中，持续了好几周。
HIV was in the bin and then I came out
艾滋病毒被扔进了垃圾桶，然后我出来了
of keto and my HIV was still in the bin
生酮饮食期间，我的艾滋病毒还在垃圾桶里。
and to be honest it's only in the last
说实话，只有在最后
three days and we're in February now
三天后，我们就进入二月了。
we're like mid mid-February when my HIV
大概是二月中旬，我的艾滋病毒感染情况开始恶化。
has started to recover and I was like
已经开始恢复了，我当时就想：
what the hell happened was it the keto
到底发生了什么？是生酮饮食吗？
that I did was it I don't know um again
我做的就是……我不知道，嗯，又来了
a lot to say on that uh depends on how
关于这一点有很多话要说，嗯，这取决于……
far you want me to go down this
你想让我走多远？
road I'm not surprised um I I would love
路，我并不惊讶，嗯，我很乐意
to see your blood work I could probably
我大概可以查看你的血液检查结果。
tell you exactly what's happening from
告诉你到底发生了什么
that that will explain a lot of what's
这将解释很多事情。
going on the reason I'm saying that is
我这么说的原因是……
we have seen uh many many times
我们已经见过很多很多次了
situations which people are fatigued HRV
人们感到疲劳的情况 HRV
goes down sleep like we see all these
像我们看到的所有这些一样，下床睡觉
issues right and you'll see kind of a
问题就在这里，你会看到某种……
interesting combination here and I've
这是一个有趣的组合，而且我已经……
used this example a lot because it's
我经常使用这个例子，因为它……
come up so many times where testosterone
睾酮水平多次出现。
starts to go a little bit low and you
开始有点降温，然后你
start looking at another thing called
开始关注另一件叫做……的事情
sex hormone binding globulin it's one of
性激素结合球蛋白是其中之一
the hormones it's a sex hormone binding
这种激素是一种性激素结合剂
glob globulin is like a collection of
球蛋白就像是球的集合体
proteins right so it's a protein that
对，蛋白质，所以它是一种蛋白质。
holds on to sex hormones like
保留性激素，例如
testosterone so when that gets really
所以当睾酮水平真正升高的时候
really high the amount of free
免费金额真的很高。
testosterone goes down that's what free
睾酮水平下降，这就是游离睾酮的现象。
testost how much is not being globbed up
睾丸骨有多少没有被吸收
and so you see this combination of like
所以你会看到这种组合，比如
sex hormone binding L globulin gets
性激素结合L球蛋白
really high testosterone gets super low
睾酮水平过高会变得非常低
and then you start poking around and you
然后你开始四处打听，然后你
look at insulin and insulin's low and
看看胰岛素，胰岛素水平低。
you're like oh okay great and we have we
你会想，哦，好的，太好了，我们有……
know that there's a known Association
要知道存在一个已知的协会
there's an inverse relationship between
两者之间存在反比关系
sex hormone binding globulin and
性激素结合球蛋白和
Insulin okay now could be a million
胰岛素现在可能要一百万
things you don't know anytime like this
你永远不知道的事情，比如这个
is one of the the reasons why I love
这也是我喜欢它的原因之一。
blood chemistry so much because it
血液化学成分之所以如此重要，是因为它
allows you to be in little bit of a ATT
让你稍微体验一下AT&amp;T
Ive now you're always working off the
我现在知道你总是在工作
human you're always working off
人类，你总是在努力工作
symptoms you don't treat or coach blood
症状你不治疗或指导血液
markers it's it's a bad way to go about
标记，这是一种糟糕的做法。
it right but you're looking for Clues
没错，但你正在寻找线索
okay so you're looking around you're
好的，所以你正在环顾四周。
poking around there and like trust me
在那儿转悠了一圈，相信我
like you can check the record I've given
你可以查看我提供的记录。
this example plenty times so I'm not I'm
这个例子很多次了，所以我不是……
not just saying this for you it's just
我这么说不只是为了你，只是
going to work you're teaming me up man
上班路上你得跟我组队，伙计
like you're just lighting me up here so
你简直让我眼前一亮
in this particular case you think okay
在这个具体案例中，你觉得可以。
why is insulin low again could be many
胰岛素水平再次偏低的原因可能有很多。
many many things you start asking
你开始问很多很多问题
additional questions but what we've seen
还有其他问题，但我们目前看到的
a lot is you start poking around looking
很多事情都是你开始四处打探、寻找答案的时候才会发现的。
what carbohydrate intake is like and if
碳水化合物摄入量如何，以及如果
carbohydrate intake is insufficient and
碳水化合物摄入不足
lower than what that person needs now
低于那个人现在需要的金额
that number is different for every
这个数字对于每个人来说都不同。
person situation all context but if it's
个人情况、所有背景都适用，但如果是……
lower than what you need in that
低于你所需的水平
particular instance then your insulin
特殊情况下，你的胰岛素
can start getting too low as a result of
由于以下原因，其数值可能会开始过低：
that sex hormone binding globulin goes
性激素结合球蛋白
up as a result of that testosterone
由于睾酮水平升高而导致
starts going down as a result of that
因此开始下降
you start feeling the feelings of low
你开始感到低落
testosterone so the solution in that
所以，睾酮是解决这个问题的关键。
particular case we give people
我们给人们提供的特殊案例
carbohydrates do you know what it feels
碳水化合物，你知道那是什么感觉吗？
like when they have some carb hydrates
比如当他们摄入一些碳水化合物的时候
back insulin starts going up
胰岛素水平开始上升
testosterone starts going up they start
睾酮开始上升，他们开始
feeling incredible in addition they
此外，他们感觉棒极了。
start sleeping better right so we know
现在就开始改善睡眠，这样我们才能知道
there's an association between
两者之间存在关联
carbohydrate intake and serotonin
碳水化合物摄入量和血清素
concentrations this is the molecule that
浓度，这是该分子
helps you fall asleep at night there's
能帮助你晚上入睡的
also metaanalyses that'll show a pretty
还有一些荟萃分析会显示相当
tight correlation between carbohydrate
碳水化合物之间存在紧密关联
intake and sleep onset and Sleep
摄入量和入睡及睡眠
Quality that is not at all to say you
质量并不是说你
can't be Ketone and sleep great that is
不可能是酮体导致睡眠质量差。
not at all to say you can't be K in
完全不是说你不能成为K
ketosis and have high testosterone
酮症和高睾酮水平
absolutely possible I'm not against it
完全有可能，我并不反对。
we just see that one often enough to
我们经常看到这种情况
where um this is a good example of it
这里，嗯，就是一个很好的例子。
just didn't work for you in that
只是这种方式对你来说行不通而已。
situation doesn't mean it doesn't work
这种情况并不意味着它不起作用。
for anybody else or any other situation
对于其他人或任何其他情况
plenty of times to go after it we
我们有很多次机会去追寻它
actually just put one of our clients in
实际上，我们刚刚把我们的一位客户安排进去了
our coaching program um on a ketogenic
我们的教练计划是关于生酮饮食的
diet for like a very specific brain
针对特定大脑的饮食
health reason actually at brain cancer
健康原因实际上是脑癌
um but nonetheless the other times is
嗯，但其他时候是
sort of like okay great this not working
有点像“好吧，太好了，这行不通”
for you right now why isn't how are you
你现在感觉如何？为什么不呢？
feeling not feeling there how is your
感觉不在状态，你怎么样？
your HRV how is your sleep how's your
你的心率变异性如何？你的睡眠状况如何？
respiratory rate how's your performance
呼吸频率如何？你的表现如何？
how's your training like I want to know
你的训练情况如何？我想知道
all these things how's your nutrition in
所有这些因素，你的营养状况如何？
these particular cases it's like all
这些特殊案例就像所有案例一样。
right sometimes as subtle as an
有时就像微妙一样
additional 50 grams of carbohydrate at
额外摄入50克碳水化合物
night Wham feel amazing sleep goes up
夜晚感觉棒极了，睡得真香。
testosterone goes way up body
睾酮水平在体内大幅上升
composition doesn't change at all right
成分完全没有改变，对吧？
you're not going to gain any additional
你不会获得任何额外好处。
fat as long as you reduce the calories
只要减少卡路里摄入，脂肪就可以摄入。
elsewhere right um and you feel great so
其他地方也一样，嗯，你感觉很棒。
we use carbohydrates at night a lot um
我们晚上经常摄入碳水化合物。
not not like right before bed but you
不是像睡前那样，而是你
know in your normal thing high quality
了解你平常所拥有的高品质
carbohydrates um as long as the total
碳水化合物，嗯，只要总量
amount of carbohydrates throughout the
整个过程中碳水化合物的含量
day are counting for all that so you're
日子都在计算这一切，所以你
just you're just switching you're saying
你只是在转换说法而已。
okay great we're going to pull a little
好的，太好了，我们要稍微拉一下
bit from morning or lunch put a little
从早晨或午餐时间稍微放一点
bit more that in the afternoon and
下午的时候比那时多一点，
changing the order here if needed and in
如果需要，可以在这里更改顺序。
that particular case um that's why I
那个特殊案例，嗯，这就是为什么我
would love to have seen your blood work
很想看看你的验血结果。
there I don't know that that was
我不知道那是什么。
happening but that brought me up because
这件事虽然发生了，但却让我想起了它，因为
you've seen that one so many times now
你已经看过很多遍了。
where we're like all right to step back
我们觉得可以退一步了。
and watch here without knowing some
在这里观看，却不知道一些事情
having this sort of
拥有这种能力
blood markers from me or having any
我的血液标志物或任何
tests done on me or anyone that's
对我或任何其他人进行的测试
listening now what are the like the
现在正在听的是什么？
first things you would look at if I'm
如果我……，你首先会看的是什么？
trying to whoop my friend's ass at HRV
我试图在HRV测试中打败我的朋友。
in our little HRV League table what are
在我们的小型 HRV 联赛表格中，有哪些
the like fundamentals of HRV are you
心率变异性 (HRV) 的基本原理是什么？
sure you want me to tell them you want
你确定你想让我告诉他们你想
me to just tell you afterwards yeah cuz
事后我再告诉你，是啊，因为
I can cut this out and no one needs to
我可以删掉这一段，也没人需要删掉。
hear it so I can just so I can know cuz
听着，这样我才能知道，因为
this is a big thing it's like a big
这是件大事，就像一件大事一样。
thing in my family now there's like a
现在我家里有件事，就像……
family leag table and there's like my
家庭联赛表格，还有我的
best friend's League table then me and
最好的朋友的联赛排名，然后是我和
my girlfriend so I'm trying to and I'm
我女朋友，所以我正在努力，我是
losing right now cuz this bloody keto
现在输了，都是这该死的生酮饮食害的。
thing that I did
我做的那件事
it really honestly my honest answer I
这是我实话实说的回答。
hate to do this but it does come back to
虽然不想这样做，但最终还是要回到原点。
what is your biggest anchor so we're
你最大的顾虑是什么？所以我们……
going to figure out because this going
得想办法解决，因为这事要发生了
be different for everybody if let's
如果让我们这样做，对每个人来说都会有所不同。
assume you've eliminated all the what we
假设你已经排除了所有我们
call 88 practices all that stuff is gone
拨打88号电话，所有那些东西都消失了。
okay now we start getting to kind of
好了，现在我们开始有点……
level two like level B level things all
二级水平，比如B级水平的一切
right um I would want to see what that
嗯，对，我想看看那是什么。
respiratory rate looks like I would want
呼吸频率看起来正是我想要的。
to see what's the Sleep data actually
看看实际的睡眠数据是什么。
look like that's your starting place no
看来这就是你的起点，不。
question um you want to think about it
问题，嗯，你想考虑一下吗？
this way okay maybe I'll back up little
这样行吧，也许我该稍微后退一点。
bit easier when go to solve this problem
解决这个问题就容易多了。
I'm using what's called first principles
我运用的是所谓的第一性原理。
okay so I'm going to very very
好的，所以我打算非常非常
fundamental things saying what's causing
根本原因在于……
stress and then what's causing stress
压力，以及导致压力的原因。
relief two sides that equation and I
缓解方程式的两边，而我
want to see what's going on where's the
想看看发生了什么事，在哪儿？
problem too much in or not handling
问题处理不当或处理不当
enough of what we currently have need
我们目前拥有的足够了
thoughts is one of two areas so coming
思想是两个领域之一，因此即将到来
in was there is there any changes we can
有什么可以改变的地方吗？
make in your total stress that is a
把你所有的压力都算进去。
non-specific stressor right so things
非特异性应激源，所以事情就是这样。
that are not helping you achieve an
那些无助于你实现目标的因素
adaptation that not
适应性并非
business can we solve those things right
企业能否妥善解决这些问题？
relationship wise like great um
关系方面就像很棒
something in the environment like is
环境中的某些东西，比如……
there some other non-specific are there
还有一些其他的不具体的
any hidden stressors if I can remove
如果可以的话，我想消除所有隐藏的压力源。
these hidden stressors all of a sudden
这些隐藏的压力源突然爆发了。
the stress bucket just got lowered now
压力骤减。
Len you're automatically having your HRV
Len，你的心率变异性（HRV）会自动检测。
and so I'm going hunting right I I'll
所以我现在就要去打猎了。
take you through the full battery kit
带您了解完整的电池套件
and Kaboodle and I will find like what
还有 Kaboodle，我会找到类似的东西
are the non-specific stressors that are
非特异性应激源是指
in there and we're dialing those things
我们正在里面调整那些参数。
up okay let's assume you either can't do
好吧，假设你做不到这一点。
all that stuff or or you done all that
所有那些事，或者你都做过了。
now how do we modify how we handle the
现在我们该如何修改处理方式？
stress the stress resilience is the
压力，压力适应力是
piece okay great what are we doing for
好的，太棒了，我们接下来要做什么？
Stress Management um how much time are
压力管理，嗯，需要多少时间？
you spending
你花费
decompressing I mean physically and
减压我指的是生理上的和心理上的。
physiologically okay um one of the
生理上没问题，嗯，其中一个
things I love is we are in a state right
我喜欢的一点是，我们现在所处的状态很好。
now uh For Better or For Worse I'll just
现在，呃，不管好坏，我都会这么做。
assume better where we have way more
假设我们在拥有更多资源的情况下能做得更好
arousal in our daily lives than we've
我们日常生活中的性唤起比我们以往任何时候都要多。
probably had in human history in the
人类历史上可能出现过这种情况。
past okay great so how do we how do we
好的，太棒了，那么我们该怎么做？
address that we need
我们需要的地址
intentional times when we're removing
故意移除某些内容
input a mistake that some folks will
输入一个错误，有些人会……
make is okay I'm working and then
没关系，我在工作，然后
sometimes I listen to music or a podcast
有时我会听音乐或播客。
and that's great that's part of your day
那太好了，那是你一天的一部分。
and then what do you do after work okay
那你下班后做什么呢？
I go to the gym okay awesome love you
我去健身房，好棒，爱你
there what do you listen to oh I listen
你在那儿听什么？哦，我听
to more podcasts okay great so arousal
更多播客，好的，太棒了，所以兴奋
Rous arousal all right then what are you
性兴奋，好吧，那你是什么？
doing when you're done like oh okay
当你做完之后，就像“哦，好的”那样。
great um watch tv okay great like all
太好了，嗯，看电视，好的，太好了，就像所有的一切
what kind of TV
什么类型的电视
all right and you see the you see that
好的，你看，你看那
the calculus I'm going through what are
我正在学习的微积分是什么？
we doing the time of our day what do you
我们正在度过一天中最美好的时光，你呢？
do if you get done with work early for
如果你提前下班了，可以这样做。
an hour what are you do in the weekends
一个小时后，你周末都在做什么？
right I'm not judging but I'm I'm trying
没错，我不是在评判，但我确实在尝试。
to run the calculus of going like where
运行计算，看看该往哪里走
is our time where we don't have input
这是我们无法参与的时期。
coming in and so sometimes I'm not I
进来的时候，所以有时候我不是我
listen to music and stuff when I train
训练的时候我会听音乐什么的
occasionally not against it I I've said
我偶尔并不反对，我说过。
this stuff before and people have been
以前也有过这种事，人们也一直如此。
like oh man Andy's like you shouldn't
就像，哦，老兄，安迪说你不应该……
never listen to podcast like no no no no
绝对不听播客，真的不不不不
they please listen to
请他们听我说
podcast definitely and like And
播客绝对是，而且很喜欢。
subscribe you know absolutely R can we
订阅你知道绝对可以 R 我们
five star R please please come on now we
五星R级，拜托拜托，快点！
got kids to feed dogs to take care
让孩子们喂狗，照顾它们
of just when is the time when we don't
究竟何时才是我们不该如此的时候？
have sensory input coming in so one of
有感官输入进来，所以其中一个
the things we'll do often is saying okay
我们经常会说“好的”。
great can we do one to three 10minute
太好了，我们可以做一到三个10分钟的吗？
walks with no input nothing in your
走路时没有任何输入，你的什么都没有
ears if you want to make it a 45 minute
如果你想把它变成45分钟的话，就得注意耳朵了。
walk great if you want to do one I don't
如果你想走的话，走得很好，但我个人不建议这么做。
really care what it is but we need some
我们并不在意它是什么，但我们需要一些
time where you can I like three a day
有空的时候，我喜欢一天吃三次。
because I want to start your day like
因为我想这样开始你的一天。
that mhm de compress get focused you're
嗯，解压缩，集中注意力，你
going to notice I'm sure your brain
你会注意到的，我确信你的大脑会注意到。
works similar to mine we're like if you
和我的工作类似，我们就像……如果你
go 20
去20
seconds he like all of a sudden and
几秒钟后，他突然就像……
you're getting back and you're gonna
你要回去了，而且你会
fire off 50 emails and texts and like
发送 50 封电子邮件和短信，然后点赞
you're you're on right which is great
你是对的，这太好了。
but you need that time I like doing it
但你需要那段时间，我喜欢这样做。
lunch same thing you've been on on on on
午餐还是老样子，你一​​直在说这个
on on on give yourself 10 minutes if you
给自己10分钟时间，如果你
want to do actual breath work if you
如果你想进行真正的呼吸练习，
want to do actual just closed eyes if
如果只想闭上眼睛的话
you want to do meditation if you I
如果你想冥想，我
prefer to just like walk outside
更喜欢在户外散步。
personally what whatever it is but you
就我个人而言，无论是什么，但你
need some time where we just stop the
我们需要一些时间，让我们停下来。
world it's like torture for me it's
这个世界对我来说就像酷刑一样。
horrible right it's so awful for me you
太可怕了，对我来说真是太糟糕了。
know how you know how much I have to
你知道你如何知道我有多少东西
like force myself to do those that part
比如强迫自己去做那部分
my girlfriend's a breath practitioner so
我女朋友是呼吸疗法师，所以
she finds it so easy of course she
她当然觉得这很容易。
she'll wake up in the morning and she'll
她早上醒来后，她会
do like an hour and a half yoga breath
做大约一个半小时的瑜伽呼吸练习
work in front of me never yeah and she
她从来不在我面前工作，是的，她
doesn't she doesn't she hasn't even gone
她难道没去吗？她甚至还没去过呢。
and got her phone off charging she'll
她把手机从充电座上取下来了。
then walk into the kitchen and drink her
然后走进厨房，喝了她的酒
water make her little tea with the herbs
水，给她泡杯加了草药的小茶。
thing in it and she'll drift back and
她把东西放进去，然后就会慢慢地回来。
she'll go and she sits on the balcony
她会去，然后坐在阳台上。
and just sits in the sun me whatever the
然后就坐在阳光下，不管我怎么样
opposite of that is is me yeah I know I
相反的就是我，是的，我知道。
wake up like the second My Eyes Are Open
醒来就像第二首《我的眼睛睁开了》那样
I'm like I'm like 100% I'm raging to
我百分之百确定我非常愤怒
like get after something or I actually
比如追求某样东西，或者我实际上
tend to wake up with a huge creative
醒来时往往灵感迸发。
explosion so I don't have just like have
爆炸，所以我没有，就像有
anxiety of like stuff I have to do but I
焦虑，比如我必须做的事情，但我
have excitement of like oh I got an idea
兴奋地想：哦，我有个主意！
like this is really cool like I want to
这真的太酷了，我想要
like I want to get raging right and but
就像我想彻底爆发一样，但是
I don't I'm like I play with my kids and
我不，我就像在和孩子们玩耍一样。
stuff like that right so can you give me
诸如此类的事情，对吧？所以你能给我吗？
five minutes right can what can you give
五分钟就能做到，你能付出什么？
me in the morning of just down can we do
早上刚睡醒的我，我们能做什么？
the same thing at some point during the
在某个阶段也发生了同样的事情
day and trust me that midday one is like
白天，相信我，中午那一天就像
awful for me right cuz the whole time I
对我来说太糟糕了，因为我一直……
sit there just going all I'm doing is
就坐在那儿，我只是……
wasting time right now
现在浪费时间
but it it is a it is a worthwhile
但这确实值得
investment because even that amount of
因为即使是那笔投资
time like to reenter um I don't close my
时间就像重新进入嗯，我不会关闭我的
eyes I don't do breath like I don't I
眼睛，我不会像我一样呼吸。
don't even try it's just like okay great
别费劲了，就跟“好吧，太好了”一样。
I'm gonna literally walk outside like
我打算直接走到外面去，就像这样
I'm gonna take one lap around my house
我打算绕着我家跑一圈。
like I'm doing something to like bring
就像我在做某件事来带来
it back down and then I love it for guys
把它放回去，然后我喜欢它对男人来说
like you and I at night because there
就像你我夜晚一样，因为那里
has to be some sort of physiological
一定是某种生理现象
signal that we're done M I have to have
发出完成的信号 M 我必须有
a thing if not I'm like boom kids dinner
如果不是这样，我就跟Boom Kids的晚餐一样无聊。
playing with them get them to bed and
陪他们玩一会儿，然后哄他们睡觉。
then I'm
那我
like everything I can do to not walk
就像我能做的一切来避免走路一样
back in my office like everything I can
回到办公室，感觉一切都好。
do the wife just has to be like nah so
妻子只要说“不”就行了。
if I can finish that with like fine
如果我能顺利完成这件事就好了。
we're going to do dinner and then we're
我们打算吃晚饭，然后我们……
going to go play outside we're going to
我们要去外面玩。
take the dogs for a walk we're going to
我们要带狗出去散步。
go on a nature walk or something I have
去自然漫步之类的，我……
to have something that tells me you're
有什么东西能告诉我你是
done um the last thing I'll say on this
好了，这是我最后要说的了。
is there's actually really interesting
实际上，这真的很有趣。
research that will find a
研究将发现
disassociation between HRV and
HRV 和
respiratory rate and Sleep
呼吸频率和睡眠
Quality and the reason I'm saying that
质量以及我这么说的原因
is they are all entwined but they are
它们彼此交织，但它们是
all so different there's actually a
它们如此不同，实际上……
study that came out last year and found
去年发布的一项研究发现
for every breath rate per minute so one
每分钟呼吸频率为 1
breath per minute rate increase this was
每分钟呼吸频率增加是
in college freshman there was a 25%
大学一年级新生中有25%
increase in likehood of experiencing
经历的可能性增加
moderate to high
中等至高
stress but it wasn't found in HRV and it
压力，但并未在心率变异性（HRV）中发现。
wasn't found in any sleep objective or
在任何睡眠目标中均未发现或
subjective markers what that's telling
主观标记说明了什么
you is again those are associated
你又一次与那些相关
but they are independent variables to
但它们是独立变量。
pay attention to and so just because
注意，所以仅仅因为
you're like oh I sleep enough and just
你会说，哦，我睡得够多了，然后就……
because and the last one to get to is is
因为最后一个要提到的是
we actually use scientifically validated
我们实际上使用的是经过科学验证的
questionnaires to look at mental health
调查心理健康的问卷
and in every people every person we work
以及我们工作的每一个人
with it's not our expertise that we have
但这并非我们所擅长的领域。
somebody in our team that that does that
我们团队里有人专门做这个。
but really we're looking for red flags
但实际上，我们是在寻找危险信号。
if we need to refer out right but we do
如果需要转诊，我们当然会这样做。
that because there's just no way you can
因为你根本不可能
optimize a human experience with just
仅通过优化人类体验
total disregard for mental health right
完全漠视心理健康权利
but what happens often is we see people
但经常发生的情况是，我们看到人们
who are fine or just not like major
那些很好或者只是不像主要角色那样的人
issues in mental health but they can
心理健康问题，但他们可以
still have an extremely stressed
仍然压力极大。
physiology and so understanding stress
生理学以及对压力的理解
when I say stress I do the same thing I
我说压力的时候，我做的也是同样的事情
associate that with like oh I'm not
把那和“哦，我不是”联系起来
stressed I'm not stressed but then when
压力大？我并不觉得压力大，但是后来……
we look at your HRV and we look at all
我们会查看您的心率变异性，我们会查看所有
these other markers we're looking at a
我们正在观察的其他这些指标
bunch of blood markers and other
一系列血液标志物和其他
molecular markers we're seeing like well
我们看到的分子标记物，例如……
you have a very stressed physiology now
你现在的生理状态非常紧张。
for whatever reason you're handling it
无论你出于什么原因处理这件事
fine
美好的
psychologically or it's not making an
心理上，或者说它没有产生任何影响
impact
影响
whether it is or not or I don't know
我不知道是不是真的。
that's not my area but we can see it
那不是我的专业领域，但我们可以看到。
physiologically and so coming into your
生理上，因此进入你的
equation it goes okay we have levers to
方程式运行正​​常，我们有杠杆……
pull here um you asked a few minutes ago
拉这里，嗯，你几分钟前问过。
is sleep and Recovery the same thing
睡眠和恢复是一回事吗？
they are not they're Associated but this
它们不是，它们是关联方，但是这个
is a good example you could be sleeping
一个很好的例子就是你可能正在睡觉
fine but if you're not physiologically
没问题，但如果你生理上不正常的话
recovering enough that can be a separate
恢复到足以成为一个独立的状态
issue there's a ven diagram here there's
这里有一张维恩图，问题是……
an overlap but they are not necessarily
它们之间有重叠，但并非一定如此。
just the same thing and a lot of people
情况完全一样，而且很多人都这样。
you you'll see the same pattern with CO2
你会发现二氧化碳也呈现出同样的模式。
tolerance respiratory rate sleep and HRV
耐受性呼吸频率睡眠和心率变异性
they'll be highly Associated but in some
它们之间会有很强的关联性，但在某些情况下。
people you might have to disang one from
你可能不得不与某人断绝关系
the other one or another one and really
另一个，或者另一个，真的
pull something apart so that's what we
把某样东西拆开，这就是我们所做的。
would do for you is to go in to with
对你来说，最好的办法就是进去和
this HRV game is to say okay great
这个 HRV 游戏的意思是，好的，很棒
where's the place we have to go and
我们要去的地方是哪里？
usually you'll see something poking out
通常你会看到有什么东西露出来。
there that says okay here's our
上面写着好的，这是我们的
opportunity um to go after something and
有机会去追求某样东西，
improve and to work on and this is where
需要改进和努力的地方
we're going to get the most bang for the
我们将获得最大的收益
buck for you does red light play a role
对你来说，红灯起什么作用？
because for Christmas she got me two
因为圣诞节她送了我两个
massive red light um I don't even know
巨大的红灯……嗯……我也不知道。
what they are they're just like panels
它们是什么？它们就像面板一样。
yeah there's a lot of data on H on red
是的，关于红色 H 有很多数据。
light therapy this is actually a good
光疗法确实不错
example of something that um that I
举个例子，嗯，我
missed the boat on like I've changed my
错过了机会，就像我已经改变了我
tune on this one big time I I didn't
我当时特别关注这件事，但我没有。
think that there was anything here and I
我觉得这里应该有什么东西，而且我
I was wrong about that one there there's
我在那件事上判断错了。
a lot of research um what is red light
很多研究……嗯，什么是红光
therapy doing I'm in my head I was like
做心理治疗的时候，我一直在想我当时的想法。
maybe it's mimicking the Sun or
或许它是在模仿太阳，或者
something I don't know okay so there's a
有些事我不知道，好吧，所以……
couple of wavel there's one around like
几只海浪，附近有一只，就像这样
640 is nanometers and another about 850
640是纳米，另一个大约是850
nanometers plus or minus here and what
这里指的是纳米的正负值，以及什么？
what we're looking at here is red light
我们现在看到的是红灯
therapy in those wavelengths have an
这些波长的治疗具有
ability to cross and get into tissue so
能够穿过并进入组织
they can get past your skin lever and
它们可以穿过你的皮肤屏障，
they activate a whole series of Cascades
它们会启动一系列连锁反应。
um of things that are that are
嗯，关于那些……
beneficial for skin Health um we've seen
对皮肤健康有益，我们已经看到
injury um we actually seen changes in
伤情方面，我们实际上看到了一些变化
endocrine system hormone balances for
内分泌系统激素平衡
them um there's that again it's pretty
嗯，还有那个，挺漂亮的。
impressive what it's actually doing
它实际所做的事情令人印象深刻。
because it can get in and stimulate um
因为它能进入体内并刺激……
it absolutely can mimic there's actually
它绝对可以模仿，实际上确实存在。
data on uh it potentially improves
数据显示，它可能会有所改进
Vision when actually like in the eye um
视觉，比如眼睛里的视觉，嗯。
work with your your eye doctors on that
与您的眼科医生合作解决这个问题
one please your opthalmologist and stuff
请你联系你的眼科医生等等
but you can actually see that you'll see
但实际上你可以看到你会看到
this a lot for overall Global recovery
这对全球整体复苏至关重要
again for muscle soreness and muscle
再次出现肌肉酸痛和肌肉疼痛
damage um it can actually benefit those
损害，嗯，实际上可能对那些人有利。
as well I have them there there's a
我那里也有，那里有一个
bunch coming out but they actually get
很多人出来，但他们实际上得到了
hypers specific and like focus it on a
非常具体，就像专注于一个方面
certain area of your body that that is
你身体的某个部位，那就是
damaged and tissue um we've used them a
受损的组织，嗯，我们已经用过它们了。
l a lot with athletes coming back from
很多运动员都从国外回来了
surgery specifically so one of our
手术，特别是我们的手术。
quarterbacks this year had a pretty um
今年的四分卫表现相当……
gnarly lower body injury at the very
非常严重的下半身损伤
beginning of the season and we were able
赛季开始时，我们能够
to get him back in pretty good shape
让他恢复到相当不错的状态
pretty fast and and we used many
速度很快，而且我们用了很多
different things but red light was
虽然是不同的事情，但红灯是
certainly one of them I haven't found
当然，我还没找到其中一个。
many people yet where I'm like you
很多人都像你一样。
definitely have to go get red light it's
肯定得去看看红灯的事儿。
one of those things where I'm like oh
就是那种我会想“哦”的事情之一。
you got it oh cool like I would do it or
你明白了，哦，酷，就像我会做的那样？
like hey you have a $60 million contract
比如，嘿，你签了一份价值 6000 万美元的合同。
this year on the line well we're doing
今年我们处境艰难，做得不错。
everything like like bring it all on um
一切都像……来吧，嗯
that that's kind of where I I stand with
这就是我的立场。
it so it's it's another area that I am
所以，这是我的另一个领域。
paying attention to more and more to see
越来越关注这一点
what more things come out but really the
还有什么事情会爆出来呢？但实际上……
ability for those um those wavelengths
对这些波长的能力
to penetrate skin to actually get into
穿透皮肤才能真正进入
tissue is what's causing active change
组织是引起活跃变化的原因。
uh inside your actual
呃，在你实际的内心深处
physiology I'm someone that works out
生理学方面，我是一个经常锻炼的人。
every day I I got to be honest not all
每天我都必须诚实，并非总是如此
the workouts are great workouts some of
这些锻炼方式很棒，其中一些
them are pretty terrible workouts
这些锻炼方式相当糟糕。
because this by the way is the next
因为顺便说一下，这是下一个
place I was going with your HRV question
我原本想就你的 HRV 问题做个解释。
okay another uh thing where we could
好的，还有一件事我们可以……
potentially see some improvements at
可能会看到一些改进
your HRV is breaking down how you're
你的心率变异性 (HRV) 正在分析你的身体状况
training what types of training you're
培训，你接受哪些类型的培训？
doing and what time of day you're doing
你在做什么，以及你在一天中的什么时间做。
them typically lower intensity longer
它们通常强度较低，持续时间较长。
duration stuff oftentimes increases HRV
持续时间过长通常会增加心率变异性 (HRV)。
over time higher intensity stuff can put
随着时间的推移，更高强度的训练可能会造成……
people in the hole and what I mean by
身处困境的人，以及我的意思
that is people that have very high
那是那些拥有非常高……的人
demanding jobs and then they couple that
高强度的工作，然后他们把这些工作结合起来。
with really high-intensity high
强度非常高
sympathetic Drive training well now
同情心驱动训练现在很好
we're wondering you're like you're high
我们觉得你好像嗑药了。
sympathetic drive all day and then the
一整天都充满同情心，然后是
only break from you had from that you
只是和你从那件事中解脱出来而已
went higher sympathetic drive and now we
交感神经驱动增强，现在我们
wonder why your total drive is pretty
想知道为什么你的总驱动力相当
high sympathetic well you know when I
高度同情心，你知道当我
think I think about training you always
我想我总会想到训练你。
talk about these trade-offs that you're
谈谈你所面临的这些权衡取舍。
making one of the questions I have is
我的问题之一是：
can I
我可以吗？
achieve it all at once and being more
同时实现所有这些目标，并且更加
specific I want to gain muscle mass and
具体来说，我想要增加肌肉量，
I want to stay superan at the same time
我想同时保持超强状态
and there's a school of thought that
有一种观点认为，
says you've got to like load up and then
他说你得先装满东西，然后
you've got to cut but I don't want to do
你必须裁员，但我不想这么做。
that I just want to gain muscle mass but
我只是想增加肌肉量，但是
stay lean MH is that possible yes oh
保持苗条身材 MH 可能吗？是的，哦
good great yeah couple things to think
好的，有几点需要考虑。
about here it depends on your Baseline
这方面取决于你的基线水平。
Fitness and your how lean you are to
健身以及你的体脂率
start okay now you're pretty lean as it
现在开始还不错，你现在身材很苗条。
is already and I assume you're
已经是了，我猜你是
reasonably fit and clearly you work out
身材匀称，显然你经常锻炼。
and stuff like okay
还有一些类似“好的”之类的话。
great it's going to be a little harder
太好了，这会更难一些。
for you right if you're really really
对你来说，如果你真的真的
unfit and you're really overweight it's
你体能不好，而且严重超重。
much easier to gain muscle and lose fat
增肌减脂要容易得多。
at the same time right so it's going to
同时，对吧，所以它将要
be challenging for you especially you
对你来说尤其具有挑战性
got a number three years of training uh
接受了三年的训练
that's still kind of like early in your
那仍然有点像你职业生涯的早期阶段。
training age right that's a pretty young
训练年龄对，那还很年轻。
training age we got some newbie games
训练阶段，我们有一些新手游戏
that we'll still be able to take
我们仍然能够采取
advantage of especially you don't have
尤其是你没有的优势
like a specific plan and intention with
就像制定一个具体的计划和意图一样
your training you to kind of just you
你的训练让你有点像你
you know working out all right great we
你知道，一切进展顺利，我们很棒
would be able to have pretty good
应该能够拥有相当不错的
success with that physiologically it's
从生理角度来说，这样做是成功的。
possible it's never going to be 100%
可能永远无法达到100%。
though there's no way I can put
虽然我没办法把它放进去
especially without exogenous
尤其是没有外源性因素
testosterone there's just no way I can
睾酮水平，我根本无法承受。
put 15 pounds of muscle on you and zero
增加15磅肌肉，零
fat like that's just not going to happen
那样的肥胖根本不可能发生
could we put on seven or eight pounds of
我们能增重七八磅吗？
muscle and one pound of fat oh yeah we
肌肉和一磅脂肪，哦耶，我们
could do that like that would not be a
那样做就不是……
crazy thing you would see that pretty
你会看到一些很疯狂的事情，很漂亮
consistently in the research and
在研究和中始终如一地
certainly thousands of coaches and
当然，成千上万的教练和
practice like oh yeah like I've seen
练习就像，哦耶，就像我见过的那样
that countless times and so it's it's
无数次了，所以就是这样。
kind of like what are the reasonable
有点像什么是合理的
expectations there um so what I would do
对此我有一些期望，嗯，所以我会怎么做呢？
is for you is recommend saying you don't
对你来说，建议是说你不……
have to go like 40 pounds and like you
得减掉40磅，就像你一样
know but how much you really want to be
但你知道你到底有多想成为
at what's that number right we would
那个数字是多少来着？
figure that out maybe run analysis on
弄清楚这一点，或许可以进行分析。
you see where you're actually at all
你完全看清了自己身处何方。
right great and then we set reasonable
很好，然后我们设定合理的目标。
expectations so you want to end up being
期望，所以你希望最终成为
you know you want to put on five kilos
你知道你想增重五公斤
total okay tremendous you willing to
总体来说，好的，非常棒，你愿意吗？
accept you know 5 kilos 4 and a half
接受你知道5公斤4.5
kilos of muscle and maybe one of fat oh
几公斤肌肉，可能还有一公斤脂肪哦
okay we get reasonable expectations and
好的，我们有合理的期望。
then what you would want to do there is
那么你在那里想做的就是
train consistently you would want to be
坚持训练，你就会想要……
in a close to caloric slight Surplus as
接近热量略微盈余
possible we have to add calories to gain
可能需要增加卡路里摄入才能增重
Mass right but how we're going to do
大众对，但我们该怎么做呢？
that is 10% Surplus something like that
那大概是10%的盈余吧。
so if your normal maintenance with all
所以，如果你的日常维护包括所有方面。
your exercise is 3,000 calories I don't
你的运动消耗了3000卡路里，我没有。
need you to go to 6,000 calories that's
你需要达到每天6000卡路里，那就是
a recipe to put on some muscle but a lot
一份增肌食谱，但很多
of fat too now we don't know the exact
现在脂肪的含量也不清楚了，具体是多少。
number here there's a lot of studies
这里有很多研究
going on actually friends of mine Eric
实际上，我的朋友埃里克正在那里。
Helms in New Zealand has done a handful
新西兰的赫尔姆斯已经做了一些
of studies like this recently trying to
最近有不少类似的研究试图……
figure out what is that number 5% 10%
找出5%和10%这几个数字分别是多少。
20% where is the number in terms of
20% 这个数字是指
caloric excess that you want to be on to
你想要避免的热量过剩
put the most amount of lean muscle mass
尽可能多地增加瘦肌肉量
and the least amount of fat on because
而且脂肪含量最少，因为
it's not going to be zero right 10 or so
不会是零，大概十点左右吧。
percent which for you would be 10% of
对你来说，这个百分比就是10%。
3,000 would be 300 extra calories maybe
3000卡路里大概会多出300卡路里吧。
15% maybe going to 500 extra calories
15%的人可能会额外摄入500卡路里。
we're not going to 5,000 calories we're
我们不会摄入5000卡路里，我们是
not making these crazy jumps in your
不要在你的生活中做出这些疯狂的举动
situation there we'd make sure protein
在那里，我们会确保蛋白质的供应。
is really really high uh at least 2 gam
真的很高，至少2个游戏
per kilogram right something like that
每公斤，大概是这样。
maybe even higher making sure we have
或许还要更高，以确保我们拥有
enough extra on there but we're hedging
那里还有不少余地，但我们正在对冲风险。
on if we're going to miss the mark i'
如果我们要错失目标，我
rather you miss by 15% too high than 2%
宁愿错高15%，也不愿错高2%。
too low there's just no advantage of
太低的话就没有优势了。
being down there and then we'll regulate
到了那里，我们再进行调节。
chloric intake in terms of your calories
氯的摄入量与你的卡路里摄入量之间的关系
and fat we would play with those ratios
至于脂肪，我们会调整这些比例。
if you wanted a little more fat little
如果你想要稍微胖一点的小胖子
less carbs we could do that if you want
少吃碳水化合物，如果你想的话，我们可以做到。
to do the empite we could play with that
为了达到空虚的效果，我们可以玩弄它。
stuff but those would be the standards
但这些才是标准。
we'd said does it matter what time I eat
我们曾说过，我什么时候吃饭重要吗？
in terms of exercise because I've always
就锻炼而言，因为我一直
heard that you should eat sort of
听说你应该吃某种东西
immediately after you do a workout
锻炼结束后立即
doesn't matter in terms of protein
就蛋白质而言，这并不重要。
timing if you're just looking at muscle
如果你只关注肌肉的话，时机很重要。
growth none of the other human factors
增长不受其他人类因素影响
which there are many then timing of
然后有很多时机
protein is pretty irrelevant you're fine
蛋白质含量其实无关紧要，你没事的。
timing of carbohydrates does start to
碳水化合物的摄入时间确实开始……
matter though specifically for recovery
虽然这对于康复来说至关重要，但具体而言却并非如此。
now that typically happens in athletes
这种情况通常发生在运动员身上。
that train multiple times a day that
那列火车一天多次往返
said with both of them you have options
他们说，你和他们俩都有选择。
again look at the research on
再次查看相关研究
intermittent fasting you don't see
间歇性禁食，你看不到
especially if you look at the the
尤其是如果你仔细观察……
classic kind of like 168 which is you
经典的那种，比如168，那就是你。
you know you have a condensed eating
你知道你饮食很节制
window of just six hours a day and the
每天只有六个小时的窗口期
other 18 you're fasting um that is not
其他18个人你在禁食，嗯，那不是。
any more advantageous for fat loss than
比其他任何方式都更有利于减脂
non-fasting there doesn't seem to be any
非禁食者似乎没有任何
difference at all when you account for
当你考虑到这一点时，差异就完全不存在了。
calories and protein so if you want to
卡路里和蛋白质，所以如果你想
eat six meals a day great you want to
一天吃六顿饭很棒，如果你想的话
eat one meal a day won't matter for fat
一天只吃一顿饭对脂肪摄入量没有影响。
loss so that still though tells us
损失，所以这仍然告诉我们
timing of protein it's just not super
蛋白质摄入时间真的不太理想。
important for someone like you for
对像你这样的人来说很重要
muscle mass gains the only practical
增加肌肉质量是唯一可行的方法
challenge is this if we need you at that
问题在于，如果我们需要你到场的话。
two grams of protein per kilo or maybe
每公斤体重两克蛋白质，或者也许
higher can you get enough food in during
在高海拔地区，你能获得足够的食物吗？
your timing of eating
你的进食时间
sometimes yeah um you know in our study
有时候，嗯，你知道，在我们的研究中
we had plenty of participants that had
我们有很多参与者，他们
no issue eating all their food and
吃完所有食物没有任何问题
calories in a caloric Surplus in a six-
卡路里 热量盈余 六
hour window they had no problem others
一小时窗口期内，他们没有遇到任何问题；其他人也没有遇到问题。
really struggled and so now we're not
真的非常艰难，所以现在我们不是了
talking science or physiology we're
谈论科学或生理学时，我们
talking practical application you in
谈谈实际应用，你
your own personal life ah my stomach is
你自己的个人生活啊，我的胃是
so full or timing of work or whatever
所以工作安排或其他什么的。
but if that's not the case then I'd be
但如果情况并非如此，那么我就会……
like great we're going to have no
太好了，我们不会再有……
problem so I wouldn't be super concerned
这不是什么大问题，所以我不会特别担心。
with the timing of either of your or any
与您或任何其他人的时间有关
of your macronutrients
你的宏量营养素
um outside of personal preference real
嗯，撇开个人喜好不谈，真的
world situations things like that if I'm
世界局势之类的事情，如果我是
just a normal guy which I very much am
我只是个普通人，而我确实如此。
and I'm maybe a busy business person or
我可能是一位忙碌的商人，或者
I just have a you know job as a manager
我只是个经理，你知道的。
or something and I'm thinking about the
或者别的什么，我正在思考……
types of training that are going to help
有助于的培训类型
me perform at my best cognitively in my
在我的认知能力方面，我能发挥出最佳水平
work but then just be healthy over time
努力工作，然后随着时间的推移保持健康。
in my life what is the like blend of
在我的生活中，什么是类似的融合？
training types and styles and durations
培训类型、方式和时长
that are optimal for me to just be a
对我来说，最好的状态就是成为一个
great average Joe mhm you need a handful
伟大的普通人乔，嗯，你需要一把。
of
的
physiological skills to age super well
生理技能使人能够超常衰老
okay so if you want to live and live as
好吧，如果你想活下去，并且像……一样生活
well as possible for a long time and it
尽可能长时间地保持良好状态，而且
comes down to a couple of things you
归根结底，取决于以下两点：
need to move well what's that mean
需要顺利搬家，这是什么意思？
different definitions but you need to
定义不同，但你需要
move in a way that is not getting hurt
以不会受伤的方式移动
causing pain great that comes down to
造成巨大痛苦，归根结底是
movement skill there's some flexibility
动作技巧方面，有一定的灵活性。
in there there's some mobility and
里面有一些活动空间，
there's also just like do you know how
还有，你知道吗？
to stand up do you know how to walk
站起来，你知道怎么走路吗？
right so we need to move well so
对，所以我们需要顺利行动。
something where you're addressing I
你在谈论我
don't need you to be the most talented
不需要你是最有才华的
Sprinter in the world but we just can't
他是世界上最好的短跑运动员，但我们就是做不到。
have glaring holes can have huge
有明显的孔洞，可能巨大
problems in Mobility flexibility posture
活动能力、灵活性和姿势方面的问题
range of the motion because we have to
因为我们必须要有运动范围
stay out of pain so number one biggest
避免疼痛，这是最重要的一点。
key to successful aging when it comes to
成功老龄化的关键在于……
exercise is not missing
运动并没有缺失
training we can't miss training for big
训练我们不能错过大型训练。
chunks in time months and years because
以月和年为单位的时间段，因为
we're hurt we have to stay active Okay
我们受伤了，但我们必须保持活跃，好的。
see what I'm saying yeah so Mobility
你明白我的意思吗？是的，所以流动性
means that we can be consistent if it
这意味着如果我们这样做，我们就可以保持一致。
does yeah right so um there's no like
是啊，对吧？所以，嗯，没有那种
strong tie there of like hey the more
那里的联系很紧密，就像……嘿，越多越好
range of motion your hamstring the less
腘绳肌的活动范围越小
injuries you'll have I'm just talking if
你会受的伤，我只是说说而已。
you have some really bad issue where all
你遇到了非常严重的问题，所有
of a sudden you're 40 years old and
突然间，你就40岁了，
you're in so much back pain you can't
你背痛得厉害，根本没法……
walk okay you're that's going to be a
走吧，你这将会是一个
problem so don't get hurt step number
问题在于不要受伤，步骤编号
one number two is now speed and power
第一点和第二点是速度和力量。
and I'm saying that because if you look
我这么说是因为，如果你仔细观察……
at one of the most significant issues
在最重要的问题之一上
that we face during aging it's our Falls
我们在衰老过程中面临的最大挑战就是跌倒。
risk you can't fall if you look at the
如果你看着……就不会有跌倒的风险
data I don't know what it is off the top
我不知道这到底是什么数据。
of my head but if you look at the risk
我脑子里一片混乱，但如果你看看风险……
of dying after a hip break in those that
在那些髋部骨折后死亡的人中
are over 60 years old it's something
都超过60岁了，这可不是什么好事。
alarming like a 50% chance of death over
令人震惊的是，死亡概率高达50%。
the next 15 years like it's absurd and
接下来的15年简直荒谬至极。
you could whatever the number is it
你可以把那个数字当成任何东西。
doesn't matter when you look up the real
当你查找真实情况时，这并不重要。
ones you're going to be like wow it's
你会惊叹：哇，这真是……
just as bad as as I exemplified there so
就像我在那里举的例子一样糟糕。
you you can't afford to do that why do
你负担不起那样做，为什么？
you fall when you're over 60 well
你60多岁的时候摔倒是常有的事。
sometimes a dog just walks out in front
有时候，一只狗会径直走到前面。
of you and okay great but the things
你很好，但是这些事情
that you can control you can't lose your
你能控制的，你就不会失去你的
balance don't like you need to train
平衡感不好，你需要训练。
balance okay great secondly if you lose
平衡性很好，其次，如果你输了
your balance you need to have the foot
你需要保持平衡，你的脚要稳固。
speed and the Hand speed to move your
移动速度和手部移动速度
appendices out in front of you to stop
伸出你面前的附件来阻止
that fall from happening right this is a
摔倒发生的原因就在于此。
foot speed this is a hand speed mostly
脚速，这主要取决于手速。
since your legs are the way that you
因为你的腿是这样的
interface with the world most of the
与世界大部分地区的接口
time
时间
we always start with our lower body
我们总是从下半身开始。
right we can't can't have bad knees
对，我们不能有不好的膝盖。
can't have bad ankles and we can't lose
脚踝不能受伤，我们不能输。
foot speed and power let's assume that
假设步速和力量
freak accident happened you had um a
发生了一起离奇的事故，你……
slip and you had the ability to get your
失误，你就有机会得到你的
foot out in front of you and you're
一只脚伸出来，你就……
falling right so you're tripping you're
向右跌倒，所以你绊倒了。
falling forward and then you flung your
向前摔倒，然后你扔出了你的
right foot out in front of you and you
右脚伸出到你前面，然后你
planted it to stop yourself from falling
把它种下是为了防止自己摔倒
so you didn't smash your hip you then
所以你当时没摔断髋骨。
need to have the Ecentric
需要有偏心
strength to stop yourself from
有力量阻止自己
collapsing on that foot so you had the
你当时脚着地了，所以你……
foot speed to get it out there but did
用脚速度把球传出去，但确实如此
you have enough strength to actually
你有足够的实力去实现这一点
stop yourself from
阻止自己
falling physical strength uh is one of
体能下降是其中之一
these strongest predictors of
这些最强的预测因子
mortality of any metric in the entire
整个生命周期中任何指标的死亡率
world the only one that is sort of close
世界上唯一一个勉强算得上接近的。
to it is your V2 Max those things will
那就是你的V2 Max，那些东西会
out predict how long you're going to
预测你将要持续多久
live more than almost any metric if you
如果你活得比几乎任何其他指标都更重要，那就更应该如此。
look at them stacked up directly against
看看它们直接堆叠在一起的样子
clinical uh traditional clinical risk
临床传统临床风险
factors uh blood pressure um
血压等因素
cardiovascular disease markers coronary
心血管疾病标志物冠状动脉
artery disease smoking diabetes things
动脉疾病、吸烟、糖尿病
like that those are all bad but leg
那样的话，那些都不好，但是腿
strength and V2 Max typically will
力量和V2 Max通常会
predict survival rate more so than those
比其他方法更能预测生存率
other markers there's actually a couple
其他标记实际上还有几个
of studies um that come to mind one of
我能想到的研究之一是……
them out of Jonathan Myers lab the
它们来自乔纳森·迈尔斯实验室
famous One 750,000 people in the studies
著名的 One 参与了 75 万人的研究
like big studies and over the course of
例如大型研究，以及在整个过程中
it I think
我觉得
174,000 people died you know these are
你知道，有17.4万人死亡。
retrospective studies and stuff like
回顾性研究之类的
that right but what you're looking at is
没错，但你现在看到的是
like who stayed alive and who didn't not
比如谁活了下来，谁没活下来。
like a surrogate marker not some sort of
就像一个替代标记，而不是某种……
like direct marker right and you will
就像直接标记一样，你会
definitely see what's called a hazard
绝对能看到所谓的危险。
ratio which is to say okay 1.0 is
比率，也就是说，好的，1.0是
neutral below one is reduced risk of
中性低于 1 表示风险降低
dying above one is increased risk and
死亡风险高于1岁，且死亡风险增加。
you'll look at things um you you'll see
你会看到一些东西，你会看到
smoking and diabetes put you at a HR of
吸烟和糖尿病会使你的心率达到……
like 1.3 1.4 so 30% in increase Hazard
比如 1.3 到 1.4，所以风险增加了 30%。
ratio 40% increase like that's not good
比例增长40%可不好。
and then you start to see the things
然后你开始看到那些东西。
like V to Max and you start seeing like
就像 V 到 Max，然后你开始看到
4X increases 5x increases like they just
4倍增长，5倍增长，就像他们只是
outpace smoking and Diabetes by massive
吸烟和糖尿病的发病率远超吸烟和糖尿病。
amounts it's not like uh smoking is 30%
数量可不是像吸烟那样，占30%。
and BO2 Max is 40% it's like smoking is
BO2 Max 为 40%，就像吸烟一样。
30% and V2 Max is 300% what is V2 Max
30% 和 V2 Max 是 300%，那么 V2 Max 是多少？
for anybody that doesn't know your
对于任何不了解你的人
maximum ability to bring in and utilize
最大限度地发挥引进和利用能力
oxygen um cardiovascular fitness if you
氧气，嗯，心血管健康，如果你
want to think about it like that when
想这样想的时候
you compare leg strength in those same
你比较的是那些相同的腿部力量。
studies
研究
depending on the studies it's comparable
根据不同的研究，结果具有可比性。
if not higher of a predictor than the
即使它不是比……更高的预测指标
VO2 max can I just think about that when
VO2 max 我可以想想这个吗
I get older because a lot of people you
我变老是因为很多人……
know I'm 30 years old great question you
我知道我今年30岁了，你问的这个问题很好。
can you're welcome to but here's what
当然可以，但这里有一些注意事项。
happens we know that VO2 max will drop
我们知道，这种情况发生时，最大摄氧量会下降。
something like 1% per year after the age
大约每年增长1%，年龄之后。
of around 40 to
大约40到
45ish right now you can you can amarate
现在大概45岁左右，你可以，你可以amarate
or attenuate a lot of that Sor it will
或者减弱很多，否则它将
drop automatically yeah with aging okay
随着年龄增长，会自动下降，好的。
for sure regardless of what I I mean
当然，不管我是什么意思。
obviously my work will go against it yes
显然，我的作品会与之相悖，是的。
but if if left alone it kind of drops
但如果放任不管，它就会慢慢下降。
itself not even if left alone um we
即使放任不管，它本身也不会……嗯，我们
actually did a study years ago in
实际上，几年前我做过一项研究
Stockholm Sweden where we took we ran
我们在瑞典斯德哥尔摩跑步
VO2 max tests on cross country skiers
越野滑雪运动员的最大摄氧量测试
and these people were world champions in
这些人都是世界冠军
the 1940s and 50s and they were still
20世纪40年代和50年代，他们仍然
competing in
参加比赛
2010 so they're on year 50 55 60 of
2010年，所以他们正处于第50、55、60年。
continuous training and competing is
持续的训练和比赛
really really cool to get these people
能遇到这些人真是太棒了
in there a little like again you're your
里面有点像你又回到了你的
studs in the 1950s and you're they
20世纪50年代的种马，而你就是他们
haven't stopped
一直没有停止
competing and we compared them to age
我们比较了他们的年龄，并对他们进行了比较。
matched um individuals in in back here
这里匹配了几个个体。
in in the States now all these people
现在在美国的这些人
were over 80 some of them were up to 92
他们中有的超过80岁，有的甚至高达92岁。
years old and we ran their V2 Max test
多年来，我们进行了他们的 V2 Max 测试
and there a bunch of fun stuff we' did
我们还做了很多有趣的事情
there but when you look at the V2 Max um
但是当你查看V2 Max时，嗯……
our group average was something like 35
我们组的平均分大概是35分左右。
38 milliliters per kilogram per minute
每公斤每分钟38毫升
those people we didn't have their data
我们没有那些人的数据
from the 1940s but if you're going to
虽然可以追溯到20世纪40年代，但如果你打算……
win a world championship in cross
赢得越野赛世界冠军
country skiing you're probably going to
你可能会去乡村滑雪
be in the 80s or 90s your V to Max so
你的V到Max速度应该在80或90秒之间，所以
they were way up there in the 80s or 90s
他们在八九十年代可是相当红极一时。
presumably when they were in their 20s
大概是在他们二十多岁的时候
and 30s we're down to the
30多岁了，我们已经到了……
mid-30s you know 50 years later but
你知道，30多岁的时候，50年后……
people their age that don't
那些和他们同龄却不这样的人
train typically on average V2 Max is
训练通常平均V2 Max为
about
关于
20 so it is way higher with training the
所以经过训练后，这个数值会高得多，达到 20。
slope in terms of the decrease can
就下降幅度而言，斜率可以
really be blunted but it will still go
虽然会变得迟钝，但它仍然会继续下去。
down you'll never see an
往下走，你永远不会看到一个
80-year-old who can outrun a 30-year old
一位80岁的老人跑得比一位30岁的年轻人快
if they're equivalently like trained and
如果他们接受过同等训练，
talented right so it goes down the same
很有天赋，所以事情也一样发展下去了。
thing will happen with muscle strength
肌肉力量会改变事情的走向
and muscle size how is this linked to
肌肉大小与此有何关联？
mortality though what is it about my V2
死亡，但究竟是什么让我的V2如此特别？
Max that ends up you know putting me in
最终，你知道，Max 把我放了进去
a grave yeah so here's what happens when
坟墓，是的，所以这就是当……时发生的事情
men cross below 18 milliliters per
男性每分钟血糖低于 18 毫升
kilogram per minute for women it's about
女性每分钟输注公斤数约为
15 to 16 it's what we call the line of
15到16，这就是我们所说的分界线。
Independence and what that means is
独立及其意义是
basic tasks of everyday living represent
日常生活基本任务
so much oxygen utilization that you
如此大量的氧气利用，以至于你
can't do anything as an example if your
例如，如果你的……就什么也做不了。
V2 Max is 15 things like getting dressed
V2 Max 包含 15 项功能，例如穿衣打扮。
in the morning are about 12 okay uh
早上大概12点，好的，嗯。
getting up from the toilet 12 or 13
从厕所起床 12 或 13
walking 14 15 you imagine doing a
步行 14 15 你想象着做一件事
workout where you're at literally at
在你所在的地方锻炼
your maximum heart rate just walking up
你步行时的最大心率
your stairs you shut down right and so
你把楼梯关上了，对吧？
what happens is it's multifaceted number
这是一个多方面的问题。
one cardiovascular your heart is just no
心血管疾病，你的心脏根本就不是……
longer fit right the amount of blood
不再适合合适的血量
pressure and the amount of stress your
压力和你的压力大小
heart is under all day just surviving um
心脏整天都在挣扎求生。
is is enormous so what do you think
它非常庞大，你觉得怎么样？
happens to your HRV what do you think
你觉得你的心率变异性（HRV）会发生什么变化？
happens to your sleep what do you think
你觉得你的睡眠怎么样？
happens to your glob it's a very
发生在你的球体上，这是一个非常
stressed physiology it gets worse than
生理压力会加剧这种情况
that though you tend to stop doing
虽然你往往会停止这样做。
things so you you socially light you
所以你在社交方面很轻松
stop being around people you stop having
停止和那些你不再拥有的人来往。
purpose and drive because you can't do
目标和动力，因为你做不到
anything mental health can decline
任何可能导致心理健康衰退的因素
because you you don't feel like you're
因为你觉得自己不像是
worth anything so selfworth goes really
值得拥有的东西，所以自尊心真的很重要。
low because you can't do anything by
低是因为你不能通过以下方式做任何事：
yourself you can't even make your own
你自己连一个都做不了。
breakfast you can't and so you start to
你吃不上早餐，于是你开始……
just re and so this thing just catapults
就这样，这东西就弹射出去了。
so it is a it is a again multifaceted
所以它又是一个多方面的事物。
problem you can talk about just the
你可以谈谈这个问题
ability to you can't bring any utiliz
你无法利用这种能力
oxgen you can't feel your brain you
缺氧时你感觉不到你的大脑
start to deteriorate but then you can go
开始恶化，但之后你可以走了
all the way to the other the Spectrum
一直到光谱的另一端
that I just said of like social
我刚才说的就是社交方面的事情。
isolation because you can't walk you
因为你无法行走而感到孤立
can't be in the world you can't get out
不能身处你无法逃离的世界
in the sunlight like you you can't
在阳光下，你就像你一样，你不能
physical activity starts to plummet once
一旦身体活动开始急剧下降
leg strength leg strength specifically
腿部力量，特别是腿部力量。
will tell you how long you'll be
会告诉你你需要多长时间
physically active once your legs get
一旦你的腿开始活动，身体就会变得强壮。
weak you stop being Physically Active
身体虚弱，停止体育锻炼。
because everything gets really really
因为一切都变得非常非常
down hard so you're like I'm not even
跌倒得很惨，所以你才会觉得我甚至都算不上。
going to go for a walk why because I'm
我打算去散步，为什么？因为我……
going to be exhausted because my legs
我会累得筋疲力尽，因为我的腿
are going to be shaking because my legs
我的腿会发抖，因为它们会颤抖。
are so weak so you tend to stop you tend
太虚弱了，所以你往往会停下来，你往往会
to sit you tend to not want to move and
坐着的时候，你往往不想动。
then all those other problems exist and
那么其他所有问题就都存在了。
now what we what we call this is atrophy
现在我们称之为萎缩
leads to atrophy so atrophy is a loss of
导致萎缩，因此萎缩是指失去
muscle but now because we're weaker we
肌肉，但现在因为我们更虚弱了，我们
want to do less things which makes it
想少做一些事情，这使得它
worse and worse and we just spiral down
情况越来越糟，我们就像陷入了漩涡一样。
so not ever getting into that cycle is
所以，永远不要陷入那种恶性循环。
critically important so why can't you
至关重要，所以你为什么不能？
wait until you're old first of all
首先，等你老了再说吧。
trainability is still really high we've
训练能力仍然非常高，我们已经
done training studies on people 80 years
对80岁人群进行过培训研究
old you can grow muscle and strength at
年老了，你仍然可以增长肌肉和力量。
80 no question in fact almost as well as
80 毫无疑问，事实上几乎一样好
you can when you're in your 20s
当你20多岁的时候就可以了。
but if you're starting at a V2 Max of
但如果你是从 V2 Max 开始的
35 when you're 40 years
35岁的时候你40岁
old how long until you cross below 20
多久才能跌破20
well 1% per year you can run the math
每年1%，你可以自己算算。
there pretty quickly you're going to
很快你就会到那里
cross that line of independence by 60 65
60 65 跨越那条独立线
and now I guess you can start working
现在我想你可以开始工作了。
out but right really really challenging
出去，但右边真的非常非常具有挑战性
alternatively you drive it as high as
或者你可以把它开到最高处
possible now so when you see that
现在有可能了，所以当你看到的时候
decline over time your buffer is much
随着时间的推移，你的缓冲能力会下降很多。
higher last point I'll make I'm sure you
我最后一点要说得更重要，我相信你
got a 100 questions there if you run
如果你跑的话，那里有100个问题
that Gamble and you get to 50 and you
那场赌博，你赌到50，然后你
have any little thing go wrong you got
如果出了什么小差错，你就……
to have a hip replacement you got to
要进行髋关节置换手术，你必须……
have something going on and now you're
你现在有事要办，而且……
bedridden for six
卧床六年
weeks boom you just fall off the cliff
几周后，你突然就掉下悬崖了。
um you get really busy at work you got
嗯，你工作的时候真的很忙，你……
to take care of your mom who now need
照顾你现在需要的妈妈
all these things that happen in real
所有这些在现实中发生的事情
life and you can't work out as much
生活节奏快，你没法像以前那样锻炼了。
great so the the way that we say this
很好，所以我们这样说
like one of the uh the golfers I work
就像我合作过的那些高尔夫球手中的一位一样
with Donn ROM we were talking about this
我和唐恩·罗姆（Donn ROM）谈到了这个。
a couple weeks ago as well I bring it up
几周前我也提过这件事。
and he was like yo look one of the
他就像是说，哟，看，其中一个
strategies is we always control the
策略是我们始终掌控局面
things we can control so there are parts
我们可以控制的事情，所以存在一些部分。
of the golf game that you can't control
高尔夫比赛中你​​无法控制的部分
the weather and what your opponents are
天气以及你的对手是谁
doing and so he always makes sure he
所以他总是确保这样做。
gets really good at the things he can
他非常擅长他能做的事情。
physically control I would say the exact
身体控制方面，我会说是完全的。
same thing right here if you have the
如果你有以下情况，情况也是如此：
time right now and there's never a good
现在是时候了，而且从来没有好的
time but you can control it you you can
时间，但你可以掌控它，你可以
work out you have the ability then you
先证明你有能力做到，然后你
want to put that as high as possible
想尽可能把它放在最高位置
because when things then come out of
因为当事情最终真相大白的时候
your control and you get hurt or work
你无法控制自己，结果却受伤或工作。
or all the gyms in the world shut down
或者全世界的健身房都关门大吉
like you know all these things that can
就像你知道的所有这些事情一样
happen then then you've got some buffer
如果这种情况发生，你就有一些缓冲空间了。
but if you got no buffer you're running
但如果没有缓冲区，你就是在运行
a pretty high risk and you're running a
风险相当高，你正在冒险
risk of losing your health which means
面临失去健康的风险，这意味着
you're not going to be able to do
你做不到这一点。
anything reminds me of a conversation I
任何事都会让我想起一段对话。
had at Christmas with a dear relative of
圣诞节时和一位亲爱的亲戚一起度过
mine who to scen set of Christmas we've
我们已经为圣诞节布置了场景
got three little kids below the age of
有三个未满 18 岁的小孩
six running around which my brother's
六个在我哥哥周围跑来跑去
kids um we've got all the generations
孩子们，嗯，我们有各个年龄段的孩子。
there and then we've got the oldest
那里，然后我们还有最老的那个。
generation and a member of that
一代人，也是其中的一员。
generation isn't able to move for many
一代人很多时候都无法搬家。
of the reasons you've described anymore
你描述的原因已经不再适用。
there's not an injury there but just
那里没有受伤，只是
going up the stairs even will make them
即使上楼梯也会让他们……
out of breath and we sat down as a as a
我们气喘吁吁地坐了下来，就像……
family at Christmas trying to figure out
圣诞节期间，一家人试图弄清楚
whether this was reversible or not and
无论这是否可逆，以及
oh yeah and we all concluded you know
哦，对了，我们都得出结论，你知道的。
again being Optimist and trying and
再次保持乐观，努力尝试
loving this person very much that in
非常爱这个人，以至于
fact it was a part of a downward spiral
事实上，这是恶性循环的一部分。
and this individual had kind of accepted
而这个人似乎已经接受了
that it was their fate they said like
他们说，那是他们的命运。
they had blamed on something that was
他们把责任推卸给了某件事。
unchangeable and I was there on YouTube
不可改变，我当时就在YouTube上。
trying to find videos to prove that you
试图找到视频来证明你
know if you start I'll get you an
如果你开始，我会给你一个
exercise bike and if you start moving it
健身自行车，如果你开始移动它
can it can
可以吗？
change there's extensive evidence to
有大量证据表明，改变是可能的。
show you're right okay good tons um
证明你是对的，好的，很好，嗯
again you can look at our any of our
您可以再次查看我们的任何产品
work or any other groups of scientists
工作或其他任何科学家团体
that have done training studies in
那些进行过培训研究的人
untrained 70 year olds uh men women 80
未经训练的70岁老人，呃，男人，女人，80岁
year olds plus there's the reason I'm
再加上其他年龄段的人，这就是我的原因。
saying 80s because of a study that came
之所以说是 80 年代，是因为一项研究得出了这个结论。
out last I think it was last year the
我记得上次出局好像是去年。
year before on that strength training in
一年前，我进行了那次力量训练
80 plus year olds that are not currently
80岁以上的老人，目前不在
active huge improvements in strength
力量方面有了显著提升
muscle growth like you're I can't
像你这样肌肉增长，我做不到。
remember the exact one but you're I
记得确切的那个，但你是我
think it was like over 15% increase in
我认为增幅超过15%
muscle Sid like numbers that that matter
肌肉西德喜欢那些重要的数字
so yeah you absolutely you could pick
所以，是的，你当然可以选择。
your study you would have dozens to pick
在你的研究中，你会有几十个选项可供选择。
from that would show work now can you
从那以后就能看出现在的工作情况了，你能吗？
get that person did do it that's the
查明那个人确实做了这件事，就是这样。
hard part that's the ultimate hard part
最难的部分，也是最难的部分
A lot of it starting starts with it even
很多事情都是从这里开始的。
believing it it's possible which most
相信它是可能的，这大多数人
people don't believe it's possible they
人们不相信这是可能的
think once you get to 60 it's kind of an
我觉得一旦到了60岁，就有点像……
inevitability and there's nothing I can
这是不可避免的，我无能为力。
do to change it yeah absolutely
确实要改，绝对可以。
fundamentally not true in fact if you
从根本上来说，如果你……则并非如此。
look at the papers that have been done
看看已经完成的论文。
on the rate of
按……的速率
decrease I don't remember the exact
减少的幅度我记不清了。
numbers right now um but it's stunning
目前的数字……嗯，但是真是令人震惊。
what percentage of physiological
生理百分比
decrements are stopped
减免停止
entirely um like specifically with V2
完全是，嗯，特别是V2版本。
Max your V2 Max will remain high highly
V2 Max 将保持极高水平
stable the the kind of number we always
稳定的那种数字总是
play with is 50 at 50 which is at 50
玩法是 50，也就是 50。
years old I want your V to Max to be at
年龄多大了，我希望你的 V 到 Max 达到……
least
至少
50 if you train consistently you'll see
50 如果你坚持训练，你会看到
tons of people who I remember I said
我记得我跟很多人说过话。
earlier it tends to start dropping
它往往会提前开始下降
around 45 to 50 you'll see people who do
大约45到50岁左右，你会看到一些人这样做。
not drop into their 60s from their 20s
不要从二十多岁一下子跌到六十多岁
if they consistently train and that that
如果他们坚持训练，并且
is a very real phenomenon so you have a
这是一个非常真实的现象，所以你有一个
huge control over it the earlier start
对它拥有巨大的控制权，更早开始
the better but if you've already missed
越好越好，但如果你已经错过了
that window it's no problem whatsoever
那扇窗户完全没问题。
your ability to change like really never
你改变的能力简直前所未有
stops in response to exercise plasticity
停止响应运动可塑性
in tissue is extraordinarily high and it
组织中的含量异常高，而且
responds very well the training and and
对培训的反应非常好
there's just no reason to think you
没有任何理由认为你
can't make huge progress at any age what
无论哪个年龄段都无法取得巨大进步，这是什么？
kind of training for v2 Max I understand
我理解这种针对 v2 Max 的训练方式。
leg strength I figure I can kind of
腿部力量方面，我觉得我应该可以应付。
figure out what I need to do there but
弄清楚我该在那里做什么，但是
to improve my V2 Max what do I need to
为了改进我的V2 Max，我需要做什么？
be doing yeah think of a couple of
正在做，嗯，想想几个
things you need to challenge your heart
你需要挑战自己内心的事情
to pump consistently over time what that
随着时间的推移持续泵送什么
means is if you want to think about that
意思是，如果你想考虑一下的话。
as lower intensity more continuous work
强度较低、更持续的工作
that's great the mode running swimming
跑步游泳模式真棒！
cycling pushing a sled doing a circuit
骑自行车推雪橇绕圈
joining a group activity class those
加入团体活动课程
things don't matter that much in terms
从某种意义上说，事情并没有那么重要。
of they all work great so something that
如果它们都能很好地工作，那么……
continue makes your heart rate elevated
继续下去会使你的心率升高
for let's just call it 20 minutes
就暂且称之为20分钟吧。
minimum somewhere between 20 and 60
最低值介于 20 到 60 之间
minutes so if all you can do is 20 let's
几分钟，所以如果你只能做20分钟，那就20分钟吧。
start at 20 no problem um what zone
从20开始没问题，嗯，哪个区域
should you be in I don't care what heart
你是否在……我不在乎你的心
rate I don't care elevated great I'll
评分我不在乎提升很棒我会
take that as a win win that's all I need
就当是双赢吧，这就足够了。
then we need to do something that
那么我们需要做一些事情
requires your heart rate to get closer
需要你的心率更接近
to Max what heart rate what's I don't it
最大心率是多少？我不知道。
doesn't matter go up high I would Bank
没关系，往高处走，我会去银行
on those two things something that is a
关于这两件事，有一件事是
lower intensity longer duration and then
降低强度，延长持续时间，然后
something that is a higher intensity
强度更高的某种东西
shorter duration if you want to do
如果你想缩短持续时间，可以这样做
something like 30 seconds as hard as you
大概持续30秒，就像你一样努力。
can and 30 seconds of rest for four to
罐装饮料，休息30秒，持续4到
six rounds great no problem there right
六轮，没问题，对吧？
if you want to do something that's a
如果你想做某件事，那是一个
little bit different if you want to not
如果你不想的话，可以稍微有点不同。
even worry about that and again go to a
甚至不必为此担心，然后再次前往
group activity class go to a spin class
团体活动课，去上动感单车课
go to a kettle bell circuit class great
去上壶铃循环训练课，很棒
you want to go to cardio kickboxing all
你想去上有氧搏击操课
that's gonna fine great that alone will
那肯定没问题，光这一点就很好。
check the boxes off for a lot of people
很多人会勾选这些选项。
so when you think about this uh people
所以当你思考这个问题的时候，呃，人们
get like as an exercise scientist people
就像运动科学家一样
get way too caught up in like the
太沉迷于……
specific protocol how many reps exactly
具体方案是重复多少次？
when you ask a question like how do I
当你问类似“我该如何……”这样的问题时
improve my VO2
提高我的VO2
max specificity always matters towards
最大特异性始终至关重要
the end but at the highest level it's
最后，但在最高层面上是
like yo just get your heart rate
就像你测一下心率那样
up there's a there's a principle in
上面有一个原则
science we call said Sid specific
我们称之为科学的西德具体
adaptation to imposed demand that is to
适应强加的需求，即
say if your physiology is challenged it
比如说，如果你的生理机能受到挑战……
will adapt that's all it has to be if
它会适应，仅此而已。
you want your heart to improve just
你只想让你的心脏状况好转
challenge it that's as complicated as we
挑战它，这和我们一样复杂。
have to be you do that consistently
你必须始终如一地这样做。
ideally you overload a little bit over
理想情况下，你应该稍微超负荷一点。
time it will adapt your V toax will
时间会适应你的V toax
improve and does that also count for
改进是否也算在内？
muscles because I've been really Keen to
肌肉，因为我真的很想
ask you I go to the gym every day and I
问你我每天都去健身房，我
think I'm not growing my muscles very
我觉得我的肌肉增长不太明显。
well because I'm basically doing the
因为我基本上是在做
same thing yeah I'm like I know that I
一样，对，我就像我知道我
should be doing something differently
应该采取不同的做法。
here we can do better than that what are
我们在这里可以做得更好，是什么？
the fundamental things I need to be
我需要具备的基本素质
thinking about I'm going to go to the
想着我要去……
gym tomorrow morning now but what do I
明天早上要去健身房，但我该怎么办？
what do I need to be thinking about what
我需要考虑什么？
you've kind of described is playing a
你刚才描述的有点像是在玩游戏
game of
游戏
variation against
针对变化
specificity okay like everything Pro and
具体来说，好的，就像所有专业版和……一样。
cons here it's not much better if you
缺点是，如果你……情况也不会好多少。
were to go hypers specific you did the
如果要进行更具体的操作，你已经做到了。
exact same workout every single time you
每次都做完全相同的训练内容。
would drive a lot of adaptation because
这将推动大量的适应性改变，因为
you're seeing exactly what you're going
你现在看到的正是你要去的地方。
after at the same time though you've
虽然与此同时你已经
increased our chance of overuse
增加了我们过度使用的可能性
injury problems because we're we're
伤病问题，因为我们……
putting all of our load and stress in
把我们所有的负担和压力都放在
the same movement patterns the same
相同的运动模式
joints Etc if you go the other direction
如果你反方向走，就会出现关节等问题。
which is like I literally just make up
就好像我只是凭空捏造的一样
my workouts every single time right
我每次锻炼都对
chance of overuse of a specific movement
过度使用特定动作的可能性
pattern goes down
模式下降
but progress also goes down because
但进度也会放缓，因为
there's not enough stimulus in the same
刺激不足
pattern so we need consistency we need
模式，所以我们需要一致性，我们需要
to drive a Groove and get better at
驾驶 Groove 并不断进步
something but we don't want to be there
有些事，但我们不想待在那里。
so how do we play the game a little bit
那么我们该如何玩这个游戏呢？
well we want to have what's called
我们想要拥有所谓的
variation we want to have for you some
我们希望为您提供一些变化
sort of progressive overload how do we
某种程度的渐进式超负荷，我们该如何应对？
achieve that we can go up and load or
实现这一点后，我们就可以上去装载或
wait okay we can go up in reps per set
好的，我们可以增加每组的次数。
we can go up in sets we can go up in
我们可以成组地向上走，我们可以向上走
number of exercises we can go up on
我们可以增加练习的数量
what's called frequency so how many days
频率是什么？也就是多少天？
per week we could do a combination we
每周我们可以进行以下组合：
could reduce your rest intervals how
可以减少你的休息间隔，方法
much time you resting between reps any
每次重复动作之间休息的时间有多长？
combinations right but we have to have
组合方式正确，但我们必须有
some strategy we can't do it all and
有些策略我们不可能面面俱到，
what we want to think about is 10% which
我们想考虑的是10%，这
is no more than a 10% increase week to
每周增幅不超过10%。
week okay that'll be enough to where we
一周时间足够了，我们
can progressively overload you but also
可能会逐渐使你超负荷，而且
not really uh make our injury RIS too
其实并没有，呃，让我们的伤病也变得很严重。
high so we would want a a fairly
很高，所以我们想要一个相当高的
consistent plan for maybe 6 to 8 weeks
持续6到8周的计划
or so that we can watch and monitor and
或者以便我们能够观察和监控和
going get great what I would recommend
我会推荐一些很棒的建议
you doing is having say 50 workouts all
你所做的就是进行比如说50次锻炼
planned out and you're going to get to
计划好了，你将会到达
the end of 50 whenever you get to the
当你达到50岁时，就是50的末尾。
end of 50 we're not doing like you
50岁末，我们不会像你那样做
workout legs Monday you do upper body
周一练腿，你还要练上半身
Wednesday no no here's your workout and
星期三，不不，这是你的锻炼计划。
this is the order you're going to do
这是你要做的顺序
them in and here's the 50 you're going
把它们放进去，这是你要去的50个。
to complete and we're going to write a
为了完成，我们将编写一个
new program when you're done with 50 but
当你完成50个项目后，就会启动新项目，但是
if you can get EX workout one done today
如果你今天能完成EX训练计划一的话……
and tomorrow you can get workout number
明天你就可以拿到训练计划编号了。
two done great and then it's 3 days
两天都做得很好，然后还有三天。
before you get to number three fine
在你到达第三点之前，很好
number four so instead of thinking about
第四点，所以与其思考……
this on like a 7day micro cycle is what
这就像一个7天的微周期。
we called it no no no we just have this
我们称之为不不不，我们只有这个
much work to get done ideally we want to
有很多工作要做，理想情况下我们希望
get this 50 done in the next 100 days
在接下来的100天内完成这50件事
okay great whatever you're going to go
好的，太好了，你打算去哪儿都行
three four days in a row because you're
连续三四天，因为你
like hey actually I got a trip going on
嘿，其实我正在计划一次旅行。
I'm not going be able to train those two
我没办法训练那两个人。
days so I'm going to train four days in
所以我打算训练四天。
a row well that's not ideal but it's
一排，嗯，这虽然不太理想，但也算不错了。
better than skipping 3 days okay great
总比跳过三天好，太好了。
then you're going to come back and go
然后你就会回来，然后离开
hey I'm actually home for 10 days I got
嘿，我其实在家待10天。
to stretch I'm going to go three days a
为了伸展一下，我打算休息三天。
day off oh okay great but that's what we
休息日哦，好的，太好了，但这就是我们
would do as a system somewhere like that
可以作为类似这样的系统使用。
where we you know what the end goal is
你知道最终目标是什么吗？
but that allows us to then construct
但这使我们能够构建
those 50 days with intentional overload
那50天故意超负荷工作
as you know whoop are a sponsor of this
如你所知，Whoop是本次活动的赞助商。
podcast and I'm an investor in the
播客，我也是该播客的投资人。
company and last month I had the chance
公司，上个月我有机会
to sit down with Kristen Holmes she's
她要和克里斯汀·霍姆斯坐下来谈谈。
the VP of performance at whoop and I
Whoop 的性能副总裁和我
learned so much from our conversation
从我们的谈话中我学到了很多。
about circadian rhythms and things like
关于昼夜节律之类的
sleep studies show that for every 45
睡眠研究表明，每45人中就有一人出现睡眠问题
minutes of sleep debt that you acrew
你欠下的睡眠债
that your decision-making ability will
你的决策能力将
drop by up to 10% and when you're
最多可下降 10%，当你……
chronically underslept you'll only be a
长期睡眠不足只会让你变成一个……
fraction of the person the fraction of
这个人的一部分
the boss partner friend manager that you
你的老板、合伙人、朋友和经理
can be that's why I'm obsessed with
或许这就是我如此痴迷的原因
whoop which not just tracks but coaches
哇哦，这不仅适用于赛道，也适用于教练
you on how to get better at sleep so you
告诉你如何改善睡眠，这样你
can bring your best to everything that
能将你最好的一面展现出来
you choose to do if you're not convinced
如果你不确定，你可以选择这样做。
you can try whoop for 30 days completely
您可以完全免费试用 Whoop 30 天。
risk-free with zero commitment just by
零风险，零承诺，只需
going to join. whoop.com
准备加入。 whoop.com
CEO that's join. whoop.com
CEO加入。 whoop.com
CEO and let me know how you get on if
CEO，请告诉我你的进展如何。
you don't like it there's no commitment
如果你不喜欢，那就没有义务。
join. woop.com
加入。 woop.com
CEO I had a big debate this Christmas
CEO，我今年圣诞节和你进行了一场激烈的辩论。
with my girlfriend about creatine so
我和女朋友聊了肌酸的事
we're in Cape Town in South Africa and I
我们现在在南非开普敦，我
went and bought creatine and I put it on
我去买了肌酸，然后涂在了身上。
the table and I was like I'm going to
桌子，然后我就想，我要……
start taking creatine right that's so me
马上开始服用肌酸，这太适合我了。
not really knowing what it is what it's
不太清楚它到底是什么。
for that's right and she picked it up
没错，她把它捡了起来。
and then looked at the label and gave it
然后看了看标签，把它给了它。
back to me and she said crea's not for
她回来告诉我，Crea 不适合
work women oh and she she felt and I
职业女性哦，她感觉到了，而我
think a lot of people feel this this is
我认为很多人都有这种感觉。
why I wanted to ask you it is she thinks
我之所以想问你，是因为她觉得……
that she thought creatine was for
她认为肌酸是用来
bodybuilders and I Googled it and
我谷歌了一下，发现健美运动员
Googled it and showed her the Google
我用谷歌搜索了一下，然后给她看了谷歌搜索结果。
thing and she was oh amazing and she
她真是太棒了，她
started taking creatine but I imagine
开始服用肌酸，但我估计
there's a lot of people out there that
外面有很多这样的人
think creatine is for people that want
我认为肌酸是给那些想要补充肌酸的人用的。
to just get stacked great question um
只是想囤积物资，好问题，嗯。
sometimes you you get deep in your own
有时你会陷入自己的世界里。
world and you forget you know what the
世界，你却忘记了你知道的
people are really think out of that the
人们真的在认真思考这个问题。
world so there's a website and company
所以世界上有一家网站和一家公司
called
称为
examine.com I have no affiliation with
examine.com 我与该公司没有任何关联
them but is it is an unbiased place you
但他们，但这真的是个公正的地方吗？
can go to and you can ask that question
你可以去问这个问题
for any supplement you can ask about
关于任何补充剂，您都可以咨询。
or you can ask about Arginine or
或者你可以问问关于克汀病的事，或者精氨酸病的事。
tongat Ali or whatever you want you can
通加特·阿里或者任何你想用的词都可以
also ask it by the adaptation so what
也可以通过改编来问，那又怎样？
are the best supplements for fat loss
哪些是最好的减肥补剂
for brain function for cardiovascular
大脑功能与心血管
health and it'll give you answers based
它会根据健康状况给你答案。
on there so it's a really phenomenal
上面那个东西真是太棒了
site so when you ask does it
网站，所以当你问它是否
work well work for what and work how
好好工作，为什么工作，以及如何工作。
much
很多
that's the two questions right work for
这就是适合你的两个问题
what so in the case of creatine it
那么，肌酸的情况又是如何呢？
improves say muscle strength probably
例如，增强肌肉力量
why she had that muscle size okay what's
她为什么会有那么大的肌肉？好吧，这是怎么回事？
the weight of the evidence lots of
证据的分量很多
studies hundreds and hundreds of studies
数百项研究
men women young old children all kinds
男人、女人、年轻人、老年人、儿童，各种各样的
of stuff right of astronauts space
宇航员太空的物品
flight um bed rest tons and tons of
飞行、卧床休息、大量的
research okay check that box What's the
研究完成，勾选该框。这是什么？
magnitude of effect you're probably
你可能感受到的影响程度
looking at somewhere between a three to
看起来介于三到
12% okay
12% 可以
that's a pretty good magnitude of effect
那是一个相当大的影响程度。
um for something that has an insanely
嗯，对于一个拥有极其……
good risk profile meaning like you can't
良好的风险承受能力意味着你不能
cause imbalances with it it's not a
它不会导致失衡。
hormone um it's not a mineral so it's
激素，嗯，它不是矿物质，所以它是……
not causing oxidative stress anywhere
不会在任何地方造成氧化应激。
it's like really really robust in there
里面感觉非常非常坚固。
and so when you look at it you go okay
所以当你看到它时，你会说：好吧
great pretty easy Choice here
这里是个很棒的、相当容易的选择。
um I'm not it's not like the hormone
嗯，我不是，它不像激素那样。
stuff like I said where like you're
就像我刚才说的，就像你……
turning on something it's a fuel source
启动某个东西，它就是一种燃料来源。
so in fact remember earlier when I said
所以，其实还记得我之前说过的话吗？
metabolism you're either using
你正在使用的新陈代谢
carbohydrates or fat as a fuel actually
实际上，碳水化合物或脂肪可以作为燃料。
creatine is the third one it's a faster
肌酸是第三种，它起效更快。
one so the sto geometry is one to one so
一，所以sto几何是一对一的
you can break down one molecule of
你可以分解一个分子
phosphor gives you one molecule
磷酸肌酸给你一个分子
of ATP it's the fastest one but it gives
ATP 中它是速度最快的，但它会……
you the lowest energetic output so it's
你的能量输出最低，所以是
a fuel and because of this there is
燃料，因此有
extensive research on Performance Based
对基于绩效的广泛研究
things this is where it started in fact
事情就是这样开始的，事实上。
I remember as a kid when the entire
我记得小时候，整个
Valco and steroid thing hit baseball in
Valco 和类固醇事件影响了棒球运动
the early
早期
2000s creatine was like on that list and
2000 年代的肌酸就在那份名单上，
that's where this entire Association
这就是整个协会的所在地。
came because Mark Maguire and Barry
来是因为马克·马奎尔和巴里
Bonds were using all of of course
债券当然使用了所有资源。
allegedly whatever performance enhancing
据称，任何增强体能的
drugs they were not using and they were
他们没有使用毒品，而且他们是
also using things like creatine and so
还会使用肌酸之类的东西等等。
that just kind of got lumped in as like
那件事就这么被归类为……
oh it's a steroid it's like a because it
哦，它是一种类固醇，就像……因为它
came from that world and most of the
来自那个世界，而且大部分
evidence and most of the research was on
证据和大部分研究都集中在……
that fortunately the last 20 years
幸运的是，过去20年
honestly people have sort of left that
说实话，人们基本上已经不再关注这一点了。
with because we know the answer
和克汀一起，因为我们知道答案
there more interesting stuff is coming
还有更多有趣的东西即将到来
in things like bone health now my friend
比如骨骼健康方面，我的朋友。
Darren kando just finished a really
Darren Kando刚刚完成了一项非常
great study two-year study on post mopal
一项为期两年的关于莫帕尔后遗症的伟大研究
women at 20 grams a day typical dosage
女性每日典型剂量为 20 克
for is five grams so your typical
克汀病的典型剂量是五克，所以你通常
bodybuilder at the gym is using five
健身房里的健美运动员正在使用五种不同的器材。
grams a day he put this in post
他每天摄入克数，并在帖子中写道。
menopausal women 4X the dose and did it
更年期妇女服用4倍剂量，结果成功了。
for two years no adverse effects no
两年内未出现不良反应
kidney issues no problems
肾脏问题没问题
uh improved some of the bone markers I
呃，改善了一些骨标志物
think in the actual like the femur area
想想实际的股骨区域
I remember exactly it didn't improve
我清楚地记得，情况并没有好转。
others it's not a miracle it's not a
对其他人来说，这不是奇迹，这不是……
Panacea but it was like hey didn't do
灵丹妙药，但感觉就像他们根本没做一样。
anything bad potential to help bone M
任何可能对骨骼造成不良影响的因素
density and a in a a population that
人口密度和
really needs it from just a simple fuel
真的需要它，仅仅依靠简单的燃料。
it's kind of rather than thinking about
与其说是思考，不如说是……
it like a mineral or a vitamin or
它就像矿物质或维生素一样。
hormone think it more of like protein
激素，我觉得它更像蛋白质
powder like it's just it's a it's a
粉末状，就像……它就是……它就是……
nutrient that you get that that fuels it
你从中获得的、能为其提供能量的营养物质
in addition there's been at least two
此外，至少还有两起
trials that I can think of at the top of
我能想到的最重要的几个例子是：
my head that have shown that it may
我的头脑已经表明，它可能
enhance things like
增强诸如
mood uh there's a ton of research on
情绪方面，有很多研究。
traumatic brain injury long-term
创伤性脑损伤的长期影响
physical brain health um because it is
生理脑健康，嗯，因为它是
such a fast fuel source it's actually a
这种快速的燃料来源实际上是一种
preferred fuel source in your
您首选的燃料来源
brain the your asro sites which are kind
大脑，你的asro网站，这些网站很友好
of like the the central nervous system
就像中枢神经系统一样
cells thrive on Creatine so they
细胞在肌酸的作用下茁壮成长，所以它们
absolutely love it so it is it is U um
我非常喜欢它，就是这样，嗯。
neurological as well so it'll help the
对神经系统也有帮助，所以也会有帮助。
neurological system nervous system um as
神经系统 神经系统 嗯，作为
brain and tons and tons of stuff going
大脑和各种各样的事情都在运转
is an antioxidant anti has some like
是一种抗氧化剂，具有一些类似作用
mild antioxidant properties and a bunch
温和的抗氧化特性和一系列
of other stuff so um while I understand
其他事情，所以嗯，虽然我明白
a lot of people still here and think
很多人仍然留在这里，并且认为
about as like the muscle thing that's
就像肌肉那样
because that's where it's came from and
因为它就是从那里来的。
the dominant research but really I would
主流研究，但实际上我会
encourage people to look at um more of
鼓励人们更多地关注
the last 20 years what people that are
过去20年里，那些人是
doing creating research the topics
进行创作研究主题
they're actually studying and it's not
他们确实在学习，而且情况并非如此。
muscle growth in young healthy
年轻健康人群的肌肉生长
guys there's two most replayed moments
伙计们，这里有两个重播次数最多的瞬间
these most replayed moments are
这些被反复播放的片段是
basically from the podcast and
基本上来自播客和
interviews you've already done the thing
你已经做过面试了
that people replayed the most and I I I
人们重播次数最多的那个，还有我
was looking at what those moments were
当时我在思考那些时刻究竟是什么。
because I find it quite interesting and
因为我觉得这很有趣，而且
I thought I'd just let you know what
我想告诉你……
they are the first one was um people
他们是第一批人。
overrating burning fat in Anor robic
过分强调在有氧运动中燃烧脂肪
exercise as a method of fat loss and
运动作为一种减脂方法
this is really what I want to talk about
这正是我想谈的。
is I've definitely grown up my whole
我确实长大了。
life thinking that the way that you burn
生活思考的方式就是你燃烧的方式
fat is by running h i mean this is what
肥胖是通过跑步实现的，我的意思是，这就是……
most people think right they think you
大多数人认为你是对的，他们认为你
want to burn fat around here the belly
想减掉肚子周围的脂肪
fat the best way to do is go for a run
减肥最好的方法就是跑步。
and a lot of people have very little
很多人几乎没有什么。
luck with that and end up beating
运气不错，最终赢了。
themselves up so to close off on this
他们自己振作起来，以便关闭这个
conversation I'd like to hear your take
我想听听你的看法。
on
在
that you need to think about fat
你需要考虑脂肪
loss in a broader approach than most
损失的衡量标准比大多数情况都更广泛
people give it to which is to say when
人们把它送给，也就是说，当
you say fat loss let's get specific what
你说减脂，那我们具体说说什么？
we're meaning is we're losing fat and
意思是说，我们正在减脂。
ideally we're preserving
理想情况下，我们正在保存
muscle that's what that's what we
肌肉，那就是，那就是我们
typically want okay we're also talking
通常情况下，我们希望我们也在谈论这件事。
about losing fat so that it stays off as
关于如何减掉脂肪并保持体重不反弹
long as possible those are baked into to
只要尽可能地将它们融入到……
that phrase but oftentimes forgotten so
这句话，但常常被人遗忘。
the advice I'm going to give you is with
我要给你的建议是……
those two assumptions in mind you're
牢记这两个假设，你
trying to keep as much lean Master as
尽量保持精益大师的风格
you can and you're trying to make this a
你可以做到，而且你正在努力做到这一点。
successful journey and not something you
成功的旅程，而不是你
have to repeat again Time and Time
不得不一遍又一遍地重复
totally right yo-yo dieting in fact one
完全正确，溜溜球式节食确实如此。
of the
的
more I probably the highest
我可能最高
most cited paper I've ever published was
我发表过的论文中被引用次数最多的是
on yo-yo dieting like a review article
关于节食反弹的评论文章
on that so you you can go read that
这样你就可以去读那篇文章了。
people love that paper I was just a
人们喜欢那份报纸，我只是其中之一
co-author um Jackson wrote that paper so
合著者杰克逊写了那篇论文。
credit goes to Jackson for that um but
那件事要归功于杰克逊，嗯，但是
making sure you're paying attention to
确保你注意到
say those parameters in mind how do I
考虑到这些参数，我该如何做？
lose weight you can look across meta
减肥你可以看看 Meta
analyses and review articles and you
分析和评论文章以及你
will see the number one predictor of
我们将看到排名第一的预测指标
long-term successful weight loss and by
长期成功减肥和通过
again weight less I mean fat loss is
再次强调，减重是指减脂。
always
总是
adherence it's adherence to your workout
坚持性是指坚持你的锻炼计划
program and it's adherence to your
该计划及其对您的遵守情况
nutrition program so step number one
营养计划第一步
before we worry about any change in diet
在我们考虑任何饮食改变之前，先别急着动手。
we s we start arguing about which method
我们开始争论应该采用哪种方法
of exercise is best before we start
开始前最好先进行一些锻炼。
really going way down the line to things
真的要深入到事情的深处。
like genetic testing like you're really
就像基因检测一样，你真的
wasting your time here and a lot of that
在这里浪费时间，还有很多其他事情。
stuff especially if you're not paying
尤其是如果你不付钱的话。
attention to what's going to make you
关注那些会让你……的事情
adhere
粘着
the longest amount of time in fact if
事实上，最长的时间是……
you just stopped right there that's
你刚才就停在那儿了，就是这样。
enough for most people can you put
对大多数人来说足够了，你可以放
yourself in a position where you're able
让自己处于能够……的位置
to feel abundant with your nutrition
感受营养充足
approach and notice I'm I'm trying not
走近并注意到我，我尽量不
to say diet here right should be a
这里说的饮食应该是指
nutritional approach you have a balance
你的营养方法要平衡
between living life and flexibility but
兼顾生活和灵活性
then also figuring out what triggers you
然后还要弄清楚是什么触发了你。
and maybe you don't have a trigger maybe
或许你根本没有触发因素。
you can be more flexible maybe you need
你可以更灵活一些，或许你需要
more stringent like all the things that
像所有那些事情一样更加严格
go into it you got to figure out a
进去之后，你得想办法解决一个问题。
system so you're not people will not be
系统，所以你不是人们，不会是
on a diet very long collectively right
长期节食，集体而言是正确的
on average diets don't work quote
平均而言，节食减肥并不起作用。
unquote for those exact reasons right
正是出于这些原因，对吧？
you got to get to a caloric deficit
你必须达到热量缺口。
somehow okay but you got to do that in a
勉强可以，但你必须在某种情况下这样做。
way where you still are happy and
找到让你依然快乐的方式
sustainable totally right and you still
完全可持续，没错，你仍然
feel energy and you're you're there and
感受到能量，你就在那里。
that it's working for you right and
它对你来说确实有效，对吧？
that's different for every physiology
这对于每种生理机能来说都不同。
okay great and you got to me exercise
好的，太好了，你得跟我一起锻炼。
system the same thing right if you hate
如果你讨厌，那系统也是一样的，对吧？
running there's no reason you don't have
跑步，你没有理由不……
to run a step to lose a ton of weight if
跑步可以减掉很多体重
you love running
你热爱跑步
you should run if you hate lifting
如果你讨厌举重，那就去跑步吧。
weight fine I can work with any
体重没问题，我可以接受任何体重。
parameter you give me if all we're
如果你给我的参数，我们都是
concerned about is preserving lean
关注的是保持精益
muscle mass and losing fat over the long
长期来看，肌肉量和脂肪都会减少。
term that's really what we have to to
这就是我们真正需要做的。
consider the most okay now within that
现在考虑一下这其中最合适的做法。
does that mean every training and
那是否意味着每次训练和
nutrition program is the same no no no
营养计划还是一样，不行不行不行
not at all there are fundamental
完全没有，基本
differences here's the problem to think
问题在于，这里存在一些差异，需要仔细思考。
about if I said hey you're going to do
如果我说“嘿，你要做什么”，
the same training program the rest of
其余人员参加同样的培训计划
your life you'd probably be like
你的人生大概会是这样
well
出色地
but if I told you that with
但如果我告诉你……
nutrition people are like well yeah of
营养学家们会说，嗯，是的。
course like there's you know magic diets
当然，就像你知道的，有一些神奇的减肥方法一样。
that do like no keto great meditranian
就像没有酮症的伟大地中海人一样
great high carb great great great you
高碳水化合物，太棒了，太棒了，太棒了，太棒了，你
can do them all they can all work for
他们可以做所有这些事，他们都可以为他们工作
you some people taking on gluten help
你们有些人正在服用麸质药物
some people great great great sure all
有些人非常非常非常肯定
of it is possible right we come from
有可能，我们来自
very different backgrounds if you look
如果你仔细观察，会发现它们有着非常不同的背景。
at any of the research for example like
例如，在任何研究中，
a really interesting point on genetic
关于基因学，这是一个非常有趣的观点。
testing
测试
if you're not taking account genetic
如果你不考虑基因因素的话
background on that genetic testing for
关于该基因检测的背景
things like nutrition Precision
比如营养精准度
Nutrition is entirely worthless because
营养完全没有价值，因为
we see classic markers that are
我们看到一些经典的标记物，例如：
associated with say more effective um
与更有效的嗯相关
carbohydrate utilization or fat
碳水化合物利用或脂肪
utilization or or body composition and
利用率或身体成分和
they might predict a decent percentage
他们或许能预测出相当可观的百分比
of variance in European conasi you apply
您所应用的欧洲 conasi 的差异
those exact same things to West African
对西非人来说，同样的事情也同样存在。
or east African and those variants go to
或者东非，以及那些变体
zero
零
people forget that part when they start
人们在开始的时候往往会忘记这一点。
talking genetic testing they have not
他们谈到基因检测时，还没有进行过。
been validated across all ethnic
已在所有种族中得到验证。
backgrounds and the ones that have have
背景以及那些有背景的人
shown they range from like 40% variance
数据显示，它们的差异范围大约在 40% 左右。
to
到
zero so like really like you're way way
零，所以真的，你离目标太远了
way ahead of the cart here paying
远远领先于这里的购物车付款
attention to things that just do not
关注那些根本不会发生的事情
matter we got to get you on a system
我们必须让你接入系统。
that works okay great for some people
这对于某些人来说效果很好。
that might be more nutritionally based
这可能更侧重于营养方面。
all right you can lose and preserve
好吧，你可以输也可以保留
muscle mass really well by just going
通过这种方式可以很好地增加肌肉质量。
decently high on protein and then
蛋白质含量相当高，然后
regulating your calories the example I
控制卡路里摄入量的例子
gave you earlier you want to go more
之前已经告诉过你，你想走得更远。
carbs less fat great you want to the
碳水化合物少脂肪，如果你想要……
opposite like we can play those levers
相反，就像我们可以操作那些杠杆一样。
no problem all right what's your problem
没问题，好的，你有什么问题？
though oh I struggle with um car
虽然我不太会开车
Cravings okay great oh I struggle with
渴望，好吧，太好了，哦，我为此苦恼
hunger pangs okay great I struggle with
饥饿感，好吧，太好了，我很难忍受
okay well then we're going to make those
好的，那我们接下来就要做这些。
decisions based on more this more La
基于更多此类更多 La 的决定
based on like where is your pain Point
基于你的痛点在哪里
what's your problem I struggle with the
你有什么问题？我在这方面很挣扎。
okay great I have to now we're
好的，太好了，我现在必须……
personalizing now we're individual izing
个性化，我们现在要个性化了
it based on things that are going to
它基于即将发生的事情
matter orders of magnitude more than
比这大几个数量级
other things that I've just talked about
我刚才提到的其他事情
right that stuff will trumpet exercise
没错，那些东西会大肆宣扬锻炼
the same thing maybe you you hate
或许你也讨厌同样的事情
exercise okay great maybe we can get you
锻炼好，太好了，也许我们可以让你
to walk a few times a day and we'll get
每天走几次路，我们就能……
most of our fat loss dur nutrition maybe
我们大部分的脂肪减少可能都与营养有关。
the opposite you love training but po
相反，你喜欢训练，但是……
man you just struggle to eat whatever or
伙计，你就是吃不下任何东西。
not eat something all right great maybe
不吃点东西，好吧，也许很棒
we'll play the game more with you know
我们会和你一起玩更多这个游戏的。
willpower will push the pace on our
意志力将推动我们前进的步伐。
exercise high intensity fine low
高强度运动精细低
intensity fine weight great cardiio
强度适中，重量轻，有氧运动效果好
great surfing great like don't zone six
冲浪很棒，就像不要去六区一样。
to I don't care all of it can be done
我不在乎，所有事情都能做到。
okay some of the foundational things
好的，一些基础知识
that tend to be
往往是
consistent for those two things on most
在大多数情况下，这两件事都保持一致。
people is you need to make sure protein
人们需要确保摄入足够的蛋白质
is
是
adequate hard to maintain muscle mass
维持足够的肌肉量很困难
with lower protein especially if we're
蛋白质含量较低时，尤其是当我们……
going hypochloric so keep protein High
进入低氯状态，所以要保持高蛋白饮食。
you want to do something revolving
你想做一些旋转的事情
strength training at least once week for
每周至少进行一次力量训练
the same exact reasons something that
原因完全相同，比如……
makes you burn a lot of
会让你燃烧很多
calories long duration high intensity
长时间高强度消耗卡路里
either way that's all you really have to
总之，这就是你真正需要知道的一切。
do if you can do that stuff
如果你能做到那些事，那就去做吧。
consistently over time you're going to
随着时间的推移，你会持续地
get there you're going to be just fine
到了那里你就没事的。
um where we see problems are people that
嗯，我们看到问题的地方在于那些人……
put themselves in a positions of
让自己处于以下境地
scarcity what you mean by scarcity for
稀缺性，你所说的稀缺性是什么意思？
anyone that doesn't know that depriving
任何不知道剥夺的人
themselves of the pr you feel like you
他们自己感觉像是公关人员
never get to do the thing you want to do
永远没机会做自己想做的事
psych this is a psychological thing
这是心理学方面的问题。
right totally which causes the effect
完全正确，这导致了这种效果
which causes the the problem of
这就导致了以下问题：
consistency inherence over time right so
随着时间的推移，一致性和内在性就是这样
making sure you do that I personally
确保你做到这一点，我个人非常重视。
have some go-to standards I like to do
我有一些常用的标准做法。
I'll happily share that with you um I
我很乐意与你分享。嗯……
tend to like to have a decent balance
倾向于保持良好的平衡
between kind of our Anor robic strength
介于我们Anor robic力量之间的某种程度
training high heart rate stuff and our U
训练高心率相关内容以及我们的U
more steady state longer duration stuff
更稳定的、持续时间更长的东西
so if someone's going to be able to work
所以如果有人能够工作的话
out three times per week I'm probably
我每周外出三次，大概
doing one thing where we're going long
我们正在做一件事，那就是做多。
duration call it a hike call it a SW
时长：你可以称之为徒步旅行，也可以称之为西南偏南
swim call it a run whatever we can do
游泳也好，跑步也好，总之我们能做的都行。
and then the other two days I'm probably
然后剩下的两天我大概会……
doing combination of lifting and then
先进行举重等组合动作，然后
probably finishing with some high heart
可能以某种高昂的情绪结束
rate thing right so we'll do like a
对事情进行评价，这样我们就可以像这样了
little bit of strength and hypertrophy
力量和肌肉增长一点点
muscle growth work and then we'll do a
肌肉增长训练，然后我们会进行……
circuit or an air assault bike or some
赛道、空中突击摩托车或其他什么
Sprints or like what can we get you into
冲刺赛或者我们能让你参加什么？
it's like really really hard if I can
如果我能做到的话，那真的非常非常难。
get you in an environment where you're
让你置身于一个这样的环境中：
working out with some other human I love
和另一个我爱的人一起锻炼
that is there any reason why you do the
你这样做有什么原因吗？
strength first and then absolutely
首先是实力，然后才是绝对的
that's a great question if you do
如果你确实有这方面的经验，那确实是个好问题。
strength training before endurance work
耐力训练前先进行力量训练
your strength training will not
你的力量训练不会
compromise your endurance in fact
事实上，这会损害你的耐力。
sometimes it exacerbates it if you do
有时这样做反而会加剧这种情况。
your endurance first you're going to be
首先，你的耐力将会……
more fatigued and you're going to lose
越疲惫，你就越会输。
strength and so you'll have worse
力量越强，你的情况就越糟糕。
performance in your strength training
力量训练表现
what's the most important thing we
我们最重要的事情是什么
haven't spoken about you know if there
我们还没谈过，你知道，如果有的话。
was one more thing you could add of all
这是你可以添加的另一件事。
the things you know that would allow
你知道哪些事情可以允许
Jennifer who's a 34y old single mother
詹妮弗是一位34岁的单身母亲
or Dave who's a black cab driver in
或者戴夫，他是一名黑出租车司机。
London the average person I think it is
我认为，伦敦的普通人是
exciting what's coming in the world of
令人兴奋的是，这个世界即将发生什么？
human
人类
health and I think it's helpful for
我认为这对健康有益
people to know that stuff because a lot
人们需要了解这些，因为很多
of the challenges we're facing going to
我们面临的挑战之一是
get worse we have things that
情况会变得更糟，我们还有一些事情……
are going to be possible pretty soon at
很快就能实现。
kind of the stuff I'm talking about this
我说的就是这类东西。
idea of precision exercise Precision
精准练习的概念 精准
Nutrition
营养
it's not really available to many people
它对很多人来说并不真正可用。
too expensive Etc we're going to cross
太贵了等等，我们要穿越
those barriers pretty
那些障碍物很漂亮
soon we are working on a project right
我们很快就要开始一个项目了。
now called the human digital twin so
现在被称为人类数字孪生
this is a combination of you know a
这是你知道的……的组合
couple of my companies so the Sleep
我的几家公司，所以睡眠
company absolute rest um our blood work
公司绝对休息嗯我们的血液检查
company Vitality blueprint Springbok um
公司活力蓝图Springbok um
there's another company called axio
还有一家叫Axio的公司
force that actually has four sensors in
实际上，该力传感器有四个传感器。
your shoe and we can see early changes
你的鞋子，我们可以看到早期变化
potentially in gate so how you're
可能在登机口，所以你怎么样？
walking which could potentially and
步行可能会有潜在风险
research is needed here but potentially
这里需要进行研究，但可能
be early signs of Parkinson's
可能是帕金森病的早期征兆
development neurological disorders so
神经系统疾病发展
we'll see this in Gate before we'll see
我们会在《登月门》中看到这一点，然后再看到
this in symptoms companies that are
这在症状中体现在公司
involved in this entire thing we can
参与到整个过程中，我们可以
take all those data we're actually doing
把我们实际收集的所有数据都收集起来。
this right now uh put them together and
现在把它们放在一起。
make what's called a digital twin this
制作所谓的数字孪生体
allows us to make your physiology and so
使我们能够了解您的生理状况等等。
from our perspective of you know
从我们的角度来看，你知道
Vitality we've got all your blood work
活力，我们这里有你所有的血液检查结果
and molecular biomark
和分子生物标志物
from absolute rest we've got your sleep
我们保证您从绝对休息中安然入睡
we've got your movement patterns we can
我们已经掌握了你的运动模式，我们可以
actually work with another company to
实际上与另一家公司合作
watch you physically move and do other
观察你的身体活动和其他行为
stuff we can take your physiology and
我们可以测量你的生理机能和
upload it then from there we can run
上传之后我们就可以运行了
endless simulations of combinations of
无尽的组合模拟
nutrition and training and
营养和训练以及
supplementation medicine movement
补充医学运动
daytime patterns sunlight water all
日间模式 阳光 水 所有
those things and figure out really
那些事情，然后真正弄清楚。
quickly how you're going to respond the
你打算如何尽快回应？
best for whatever outcome we want it's
无论我们想要什么结果，这都是最好的选择。
not ready at all right now but we're
现在还没完全准备好，但是我们正在
actually again running it right now
实际上，我现在又在运行它了
we'll have our first cohort done
我们的第一批学员即将毕业。
probably in the next week or
可能在下周或
so we really really soon I don't know
所以，我们真的很快就不知道了。
how well the model is going to be the
该模型的效果如何？
first time through it I don't know if
第一次看的时候，我不知道是否
our group's going to be the best at it
我们团队将会在这方面做到最好。
it doesn't matter but this is clearly
这无关紧要，但这显然是
going to be something the world is
将成为世界的一部分
capable of uh as we get better at Being
随着我们越来越擅长成为……，我们就能做到。
Human
人类
sensors and we can bring those data in
我们可以使用传感器并将这些数据导入系统。
we're going to be able to deploy things
我们将能够部署一些东西。
like this and say hey yo this is most
像这样，然后说嘿哟，这是最
likely to work for you the digital twin
数字孪生技术很可能对您有用
is already being used for like the heart
它已经被用于类似心脏的用途。
it's in place we have the digital twin
我们已经拥有了数字孪生体。
of the the kidneys is is as well the
肾脏也是
lungs are coming soon the heart is
肺很快就要发育了，心脏也快要发育了。
coming pretty soon there's lots of
很快就会有很多
groups I'm I'm not involved in any of
我没有参与任何团体。
those projects but that's that's coming
那些项目，但那是即将到来的。
on board so the ability to not have to
船上具备这种能力，因此不必……
guess anymore and most importantly try I
不再猜测，最重要的是尝试。
tried this for six weeks it didn't work
试了六周，没用。
I tried this for n that's going to go
我尝试了这种方法，n 将会……
away really
真的
fast great you still have to go do all
速度很快，你仍然需要完成所有事情
the work the technology won't work out
这项技术行不通。
for
为了
you well
你好
we have some stuff that'll do that
我们有一些东西可以做到这一点。
too um what's the cost though like when
嗯……不过费用是多少呢？比如什么时候？
you were saying all of that I go you
你说的那些我都懂。
know what I mean we spent the
我知道我的意思，我们花了
entire length of human history with one
整个人类历史都与一个
maybe arguably two singular
或许可以说是两个单数
goals one of them at the core was stress
目标之一的核心是压力
reduction that was what we were after
减少开支正是我们所追求的。
right you create communities so you're
没错，你创建社区，所以你
safer you create homes so you're
你创造的家园越安全，你就越……
environmental and you create agriculture
环境，你创造农业
so we food and we all want to reduce the
所以，我们吃食物，而且我们都想减少……
stress thing right didn't called that
压力问题，对吧？没那么严重。
but that's what it was and then we got
但事实就是如此，然后我们就得到了
to the year 2000 or so we realized oh
大约在2000年左右，我们意识到……
maybe that was the wrong target I
操，也许我找错目标了。
saw on your bookshelf at home there's a
我在家里的书架上看到了一个
book called The Comfort crisis oh yeah
一本书叫《舒适危机》，哦耶
and that just flash in front of me as
那一刻就这么在我眼前闪过。
you were saying that yeah shout out
你刚才说的是，对，大声喊出来
Michael it's a great book
迈克尔，这是一本很棒的书。
um when we have astronauts come back
嗯，等宇航员回来的时候。
from the International Space Station um
来自国际空间站
getting people to live on
让人们靠……生活
Mars it's a bit of a rocket problem
火星有点像火箭发射的问题。
but it's a bigger physiology
但这涉及到更广泛的生理学问题。
problem and the this HDT project ran is
问题在于，这个HDT项目运行起来是
part of the people we're working with is
我们合作的人员中有一部分是
Cody burkart runs human works at
Cody Burkart 运营着 Human Works。
Nasa figuring out that line of going hey
美国宇航局正在研究如何说“嘿”
you don't want to release
你不想发布
stress if you do like what happens when
如果你喜欢发生的事情，那就感到压力吧
we send people up to space because
我们之所以将人送入太空，是因为
there's no gravity your physiology tanks
没有重力，你的生理机能会崩溃。
really quickly right uh they come back
很快他们就回来了
often times astronauts come back and
宇航员经常会返回地球。
they like they can't physically walk for
他们好像无法行走。
a few days because in that case that
几天时间，因为那样的话……
aspect now other aspects of stress are
现在，压力的其他方面是
way up but we've lost some of the core
一路高歌猛进，但我们失去了一些核心力量。
tenants that it means to be a human and
租户们认为，做人意味着……
we are not ready for that we are not
我们还没有做好准备，我们还没有
ready at all to be able to be told oh
完全准备好被告知哦
yeah run this scan and here's the exact
是的，运行这个扫描，这是确切结果。
culmination of life you need to run not
人生的巅峰，你需要奔跑，而不是奔跑。
even counting the ethics behind all that
即使考虑到这一切背后的伦理道德。
like the ethics of genetic testing alone
例如，基因检测的伦理问题
are really really interesting to say the
说起来真的很有意思
least
至少
the ethics of doing something like
做某事的伦理问题
that we have not thought through this
我们还没有仔细考虑过这个问题。
stuff right collectively
集体正确的东西
we there is more in our world than our
我们的世界远不止我们所拥有的。
human experience than just straight
人类体验不仅仅是直白的
answers right this is one of the
答案正确，这是其中之一
beauties of this ride we get to
这段旅程的美妙之处在于……
take I don't know if we have good
我不知道我们是否有好的
answers I think we've clearly
我认为我们已经明确地回答了这个问题。
shown we're not very good at asking
这表明我们不太擅长提问。
those questions before
这些问题之前
never because the incentives in the
绝不可能，因为激励机制
short term is so tempting we're seeing
短期利益如此诱人，我们看到
this with AI at the moment it's just so
目前人工智能就是这样。
tempting yeah and then we we figure we
确实很诱人，然后我们觉得我们
get the results back in 20 years and by
20年后才能获得结果，并且
then it's just too late well I mean look
那就太晚了，我的意思是，你看
at the current health position that
就目前的健康状况而言，
we're in right we went after that entire
我们进去了，我们追着那整个
idea of minimizing as many stressors as
尽量减少压力源的想法
we possibly
我们可能
could and uh oh we it worked yeah oops
可以，哦哦，我们成功了，哎呀。
now we have to go back and do this weird
现在我们得回去做这件奇怪的事。
thing when we re re-engineer stress back
当我们重新设计应力回来时，事情就是这样。
into our lives you have to be
你必须融入我们的生活
very
非常
careful and
谨慎而
judicious when you pull things out of a
从……中取出东西时要谨慎
natural state I'm being very choosy with
自然状态，我非常挑剔
my words there if you're not directing
如果你不是导演，我的话就到此为止吧。
stress you're letting something else
你压力过大，是因为其他事情。
direct that that stress is still coming
直接表明这种压力仍然存在
one way or the other which means
无论如何，这意味着
adaptation is coming so you can be
适应即将到来，所以你可以
intentional and point that ship in One
故意并指出那艘船在一
Direction or you can cover your eyes and
方向指示，或者你可以遮住眼睛。
think it's not happening at all and
我觉得这事根本不会发生。
realize you're getting pointed somewhere
意识到你被引导到了某个地方
else it's better to at
否则最好……
least have the acknowledgement this is
至少要承认这一点。
why the word Consciousness is in the
为什么“意识”一词会出现在……
title of of my book it's this is part
我的书的书名是《这是第一部分》。
of the process right you can be aware of
了解流程的正确性至关重要
it or you can not from there you can
它，或者你不能从那里开始你可以
choose whatever you want that's entirely
你完全可以自由选择任何你想要的东西。
up to you and all that I just want
都由你决定，而我只想……
people to realize you're making a choice
让人们意识到你正在做出选择
one way or the other so when you involve
无论如何，当你参与其中时
technology into the picture AI is is
将技术融入人工智能领域是
another really really challenging thing
另一件非常非常具有挑战性的事情
in a lot of
在许多
ways but I'll reiterate we've seen this
方式有很多，但我还是要重申，我们已经看到这种情况了。
already play out and we know the answer
事情已经发生了，我们知道答案。
is this gets worse in terms of we're not
就我们而言，情况是否会变得更糟？
going to make very good choices right
将会做出非常好的选择，对吧？
away how does that manifest itself in
那么，这种现象是如何体现出来的呢？
the end I don't know nobody knows but to
结局我不知道，没人知道，但是……
date we're not particularly good at
我们不太擅长约会
making that decision so there's lots of
做出这个决定，所以有很多
consequences there um I think that we
后果嘛，嗯，我认为我们
have there
有吗？
um the last one of the last thing I'll
嗯，最后一点，我要说的最后一件事是……
say on this is if if you break down okay
这么说吧，如果你崩溃了，好吧
the way that we structure it is there's
我们构建它的方式是这样的：
four pieces okay in order for you to
四件套可以，以便你
have more success at your performance
在你的表演中取得更大的成功
and health you number one have to have
健康是你最必须拥有的。
assessment once you have all this data
一旦你掌握了所有这些数据，就可以进行评估了。
you have to go to step number two which
你必须进入第二步，即
is then you have to qualify good bad
那么你就需要对好坏进行限定了。
great worst ever best in world history
世界历史上最糟糕、最精彩的篇章
okay we're struggling on that we don't
好吧，我们在这方面遇到了困难，我们没有
know what healthy looks like I know what
我知道健康是什么样子，我知道什么
clinically deficient rickets looks like
临床上表现为营养不良性佝偻病的症状
I know what obesity and type two
我知道什么是肥胖和二型糖尿病。
diabetes and we know disease we don't
糖尿病，以及我们所知的疾病，我们却一无所知
know what good versus great means there
要明白优秀和卓越之间的区别。
are no databases I can pull from there
我无法从中提取任何数据库信息。
is no metric I can look at and say what
没有任何指标可以让我查看并判断其意义。
what is a great com what's a great
什么是伟大的公司？什么是伟大的公司？
vertical jump number what does somebody
垂直跳跃次数是多少？
need to be able to jump in their 40s to
需要能够在40多岁时跳伞
be healthy like we don't know these
要像我们不知道这些一样保持健康
things and I don't know it by ethnicity
我不知道这是按种族划分的。
and I and I mentioned that before that's
我之前也提到过这一点。
a critical component because is clearly
这是一个关键组成部分，因为它显然
different right there's some markers in
不一样，这里有一些标记。
basic blood chemistry that are not
基本的血液化学成分并非
different in southeast Asians or that
东南亚人的情况有所不同，或者说……
are different in southeast Asians versus
东南亚人与……有所不同
Northern Europeans like we don't have
北欧人不像我们这样……
that fully fleshed out and we if we do
这一点已经完全明确，如果我们这样做的话
it's four disease markers we don't have
我们没有这四种疾病标志物。
the so I don't even know what I'm
所以我甚至不知道我是什么
judging okay now assessment great where
判断正确，现在评估很棒，在哪里
are we going to get these databases of
我们能否获得这些数据库？
super healthy people as the world
世界上的超级健康人群
continues to get less healthy I'm losing
我的健康状况持续恶化，我正在失去……
my population to pull from really really
我的人口真的真的可以抽调
quickly okay then the next piece is okay
好的，快速完成，下一块也行。
great
伟大的
you've told me that this marker should
你告诉我这个标记应该
be here pick your marker whatever you
在这里挑选你的标记，随便你
want how do I get it
想知道我该如何获得它
there and that's really where we're
我们就在那里，那才是我们真正所在的地方。
struggling so the second problem is what
正为此苦恼，所以第二个问题是：
I call Polaris like we have no Northstar
我把北极星称为“北极星”，就好像我们没有北极星一样。
we don't know where this thing should go
我们不知道这东西应该放在哪里。
the third one is okay how do I get there
第三个问题是：好的，我该怎么去那里？
what is the intervention what is the
干预措施是什么？
thing that's where I actually think
这就是我真正认为的地方。
people in my field are going to not only
我这个领域的人不仅会……
in maintain but increase their value
保持并提升其价值
such as like personal coaches physical
例如私人教练、体能教练等
therapists athletic trainers people that
治疗师、运动教练、那些人
are going to nurses because you might
去看护士是因为你可能会
have an AI that can come in and and run
拥有一个可以进入并运行的人工智能
something and say great your numbers are
做点什么，然后说你的数字很棒
here and our metrics say you should be
这里，我们的指标显示你应该……
here and then you should go do
然后你应该去那里做
X I want somebody there with me I want a
我希望有人陪在我身边，我想要一个
human taking me through X that's going
人类带我经历X，那正在发生
to feel better because we don't know
因为我们不知道，所以感觉好些
there's almost no data on okay great
关于“好的，很棒”的数据几乎没有。
what is the optimal training for that
针对这种情况，最佳训练方法是什么？
marker what is the optimal nutrition or
什么是最佳营养？
that is really really Limited
这真的非常有限
so we have to rely on Expert we have to
所以我们必须依靠专家，我们必须
rely on people that go I know the
依靠那些我认识的人
evidence based but then also in my
有证据支持，但同时我也认为……
experience I'm think about this this way
我是这样看待这件事的经验
if you were an NFL quarterback and you
如果你是一名 NFL 四分卫，而你
tore your
撕破你的
ACL and we ran all that stuff on you you
ACL，我们对你进行了所有那些检查。
would still come back and go oh great
还是会回来，然后说：哦，太好了！
there's a coach over there who's
那边有个教练，他
actually run people through ACL
实际上，要让人们经历ACL（前交叉韧带损伤）。
recoveries on 15 starting NFL
15名首发NFL球员的恢复情况
quarterbacks like what's it going to
四分卫们会想：接下来会发生什么？
cost you're hiring that person right cuz
你雇佣那个人是有成本的，对吧？
like you've done it before fantastic
就像你以前做过的那样，太棒了！
like the budget doesn't matter at that
就好像预算在那方面无关紧要一样。
point because the person's actually done
重点在于这个人确实做了
it and they will be there fantastic I
它，他们会在那里，太棒了！
really feel like our field is going to
感觉我们这个领域将会……
increase um in the value because of that
因为这个原因，价值增加了​​。
they're going to want to say okay
他们会想说“好的”。
awesome the numbers came out on this the
太棒了，这些数据出来了！
AI told me this this year you've done it
今年人工智能告诉我，你已经做到了。
before yeah done a
之前已经做过了
lot great I trust you the most I want
太好了，我最信任你，我想要
you by my side I want that companionship
你需要在我身边，我想要这种陪伴。
as we lose more and more connection to
随着我们与外界的联系越来越少
other
其他
people it's my biased opinion and my
各位，这只是我个人的偏见和看法。
feel that like this is is a great place
感觉这里是个好地方。
where people want someone there um
人们希望有人在那里……
online coaching is great that's fine and
在线辅导很好，这没问题。
all that but you're seeing actually
所有这些，但你实际上看到的是……
already a premium coming on like yo I
已经像哟一样，高级会员马上就要来了
want to hire an inperson trainer can you
想聘请一位线下培训师，可以吗？
get me that person where like the boom
把那个人给我弄到那儿，就像爆炸一样
was the opposite for a while and now
之前一段时间情况正好相反，而现在
it's already swinging back where people
它已经开始转向人们
would rather have somebody there in
宁愿有人在那里。
person for all those reasons
出于所有这些原因而选择这个人
so uh that is I think an incredibly
所以，呃，我认为这真是太棒了
interesting
有趣的
challenge but that's that's the way to
挑战，但这才是正确的方法
think about it that top one's going to
想想看，最上面的那个会是
get better lots of
好转很多
problems but what are we comparing again
问题在于，我们究竟在比较什么？
and then what do we do about it that's
那么我们该怎么办呢？
going be the real
将成为真正的
trick we have a closing tradition where
我们有个结束仪式的传统，那就是
the last guest leaves a question for the
最后一位客人留下了一个问题。
next guest not knowing who they're going
下一位客人不知道自己要去哪里。
to leave it for ah who on your team or
留给你团队里的谁？
in your life can you not function
在你的生活中，你无法正常运转吗？
without who rarely ever gets the credit
如果没有那些几乎从未获得赞誉的人，我们将不胜感激。
they truly deserve oh
他们真的值得哦
man I can't see any scenario how that
老兄，我实在想不出任何可能的情况。
answer doesn't go straight to my wife
答案不会直接告诉我妻子。
Natasha I don't want to be you know
娜塔莎，我不想……你知道的
cliche on in that one but it's not
虽然有点老套，但并非如此
cliche in my case it is um like she is
对我来说，这很老套，嗯，就像她一样。
fundamental to so many things about my
对我而言，很多事情都至关重要。
life um the success I've had in the last
生活，嗯，我过去取得的成功
any number of years is um in large part
任何年数在很大程度上都是如此
like because of her and I mean
就因为她，我的意思是
tactically but I also
从战术上讲，但我也
mean like
意思是像
unfortunately uh I'm not particularly
很遗憾，呃，我不太擅长这个。
fond
喜爱
of talking to people when it comes to
与人交谈时
like something crummy happens or
比如发生了一些糟糕的事情，或者
whatever I'm just like okay like I'm
随便吧，我就觉得好吧，就像……
honestly pretty good
说实话，相当不错
about separating those things out so and
关于如何将这些东西分开，以及
I don't like lock to tuck to people
我不喜欢把锁锁起来给别人用。
about this stuff but when I do um that's
关于这些东西，但当我做的时候，嗯……
pretty much going to be her for the most
大部分时间应该都会是她。
part and she's also very good
她也是其中一员，而且她也非常好。
about sometimes because it's you know
有时候是因为你知道的
when things that affect me affect her
当影响我的事情也影响到她时
it's the same thing so sometimes it's
两者是一样的，所以有时候是
like oh she needs me to talk to like I
就像，哦，她需要我跟她说话，就像我
don't want to talk to I don't care but
不想跟我说话，我不在乎，但是
it's like okay I have to get in but
感觉就像，好吧，我必须进去，但是
she's good about being like this is what
她很擅长这样，就是这样。
you need and this what you don't so yeah
你需要这个，而你不需要这个，所以，是的。
I me I just there's no scenario in which
我，我只是觉得没有任何一种情况是
she's not the answer to that
她不是这个问题的答案。
question thank you so much you know this
问题，非常感谢，你知道这一点
is probably the longest conversation
这可能是最长的一次谈话
I've ever had but for good reason
我曾经有过，但这是有充分理由的。
because I could have carried on talking
因为我本来可以继续说下去。
to you for a very very long time I find
我发现，很长很长一段时间以来，我一直都对你抱有希望。
it absolutely fascinating and
它真是太迷人了，
you're I've never really met anybody
你，我其实从来没真正见过任何人
like you in the sense that you're
就像你一样，你是
so so innately p
所以天生如此
passionate Mission driven and so
充满热情，以使命为驱动，因此
rigorous in the way that you present
你呈现方式的严谨性
information and you provide really
您提供的信息确实很有帮助。
really important Nuance to everything
一切事物都至关重要的细微差别
you're saying as you're delivering it
你边说边讲
and I
我
think it's really really remarkable it's
我觉得这真的很了不起。
really really really remarkable and I
真的真的真的太棒了，而且我
don't say that lightly but I've spoken
别轻易这么说，但我确实说过。
about this subject matter before you
在您了解这个主题之前，请先阅读相关资料。
know I've had people on this this
我知道我之前也遇到过类似的情况。
podcast to speak about these but I've
我会在播客里谈论这些，但我已经……
never ever learned so much oh man you
我从未学到过这么多东西，我的天哪！
know and I really really mean that um
我知道，我是认真的，嗯
but I've also never felt so empowered
但我从未感到如此充满力量。
which I think is an important point to
我认为这一点很重要。
add because sometimes you can learn
添加，因为有时你可以学习
something but it can feel disempowering
虽然有点奇怪，但可能会让人感到无力。
but to make me feel like I've I'm
但要让我感觉我拥有我
intellectually better off in terms of
在智力方面更胜一筹
like my intellectual wealth around these
就像我围绕这些方面的智力财富一样
subject matters but also feel really
主题方面，而且感觉也真的
really empowered is a real superpower
真正拥有超能力是一种真正的超能力。
you know and I just wish we could bottle
你知道，我真希望我们能把瓶子装进瓶子里。
you up in a jar use AI to keep you alive
你被装进罐子里，用人工智能来维持你的生命
forever because I think you're a real
永远，因为我觉得你是一个真正的
Force for good in the world so thank you
为世界带来积极影响，谢谢。
so much for giving me your time today
今天你抽出时间给我，真是白费力气。
it's a real honor oh
真是我的荣幸哦
man I I don't know how to accept
老兄，我不知道该如何接受
compliments like that so thank you so
非常感谢这样的赞美。
much is all I can say it's an honor
我只能说，这真是莫大的荣幸。
thank you so much dry
非常感谢 Dry
[Music]
[音乐]
gpin let's talk about Zoe who you may
gpin，我们来聊聊佐伊吧，你可能……
know because they a sponsor of this
我知道，因为他们是这个活动的赞助商。
podcast and I'm an investor in the
播客，我也是该播客的投资人。
company you guys know health is my
公司，你们都知道，健康是我的。
number one priority Zoe's growth story
首要任务：佐伊的成长故事
has been absolutely incredible so far
到目前为止，一切都简直太棒了。
they're doing science at a scale that
他们正在进行大规模的科学研究，
I've never seen before because of their
我以前从未见过，因为他们
members and recent breakthroughs in
成员及近期突破
research they can now continue to offer
他们现在可以继续提供的研究
the most scientifically Advanced gut
最科学的肠道
health test on the market previously the
此前市场上已有健康测试
test allowed them to analyze 30 bacteria
这项测试使他们能够分析30种细菌。
types in your gut but now thanks to new
你肠道中的各种类型，但现在多亏了新的
science they've identified 100 bacteria
科学研究已经鉴定出100种细菌
types this is a huge step forward and
这是一种巨大的进步，而且
there's nothing else that's available
没有其他选择。
even close to it on the market at all so
市场上根本没有类似的。
to find out more and to get started on
了解更多信息并开始使用
your Zoe Journey visit zoe.com
开启您的 Zoe 之旅，请访问 zoe.com
stepen you can use my exclusive code
Stepen，你可以使用我的专属代码
ce10 for 10% off don't tell anybody
使用优惠码ce10可享10%折扣，别告诉别人哦
about that okay just for you
关于这件事，好吧，就为了你。
guys
伙计们
[Music]
[音乐]
oh
哦